<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rcsdh">
<title><claim type="interpretation">CMV: Humans are going to die out because of an economic collapse</claim></title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rcsdh/cmv_humans_are_going_to_die_out_because_of_an/</source>
<OP author="Oflameo">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">Bill Gade presents the argument better than I do so I will just quote him.</claim>

&gt; There have been 4 jobs or activities which Man has engaged in throughout the centuries: Hunter/Gathering, Agriculture, Manufacturing, and Services. What's next? What category can you imagine in which billions of people will be working in the future? 
&gt; It turns out that there is a final category. It is known as Unemployment. As Agriculture, Manufacturing, and Services become more efficient in the coming months, workers will have nowhere to go but to the unemployment line. At some point, Man's artificial economic system will necessarily collapse. When that happens, the corporations which produce and deliver food will no longer have an incentive to do so. The cities will suffer great hunger and it will be the end of Man. 
&gt; The current jobless situation you read about in the news is not an ordinary part of the business cycle. It is the final stretch of the linear trend that began with the birth of our species.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1" rel="support" ref="0" >There is also a Youtube video to go with this opinion.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="2" rel="support" ref="0">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rlQrYCacrKo</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="2a">I do realize that this is a very unhealthy idea to have whether or not that the idea is true or not, I just have not been able to beat it myself.</claim>

<claim type="disagreement" id="3a"  rel="partial_attack" ref="0">I do disagree with Gade a little bit.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="3b" rel="rebuttal_attack" ref="0">I don't think it would kill everybody, </claim> but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="3c" rel="rebuttal_attack" ref="0">the some few people that still know how to hunt and gather would probably survive as well people who were rich enough to have access to a lot of resources to start out with before the economy crashes.</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="3" rel="support" ref="3c">I probably believe this because I listen to Alex Jones too much.</claim>

</OP>
<reply id="cnepre9" author="iserane">
Before I respond, I'd suggest trying /r/asksocialscience for an actual academic-level answer. 
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="4" rel="undercutter" ref="title">Almost everything regarding large scale financial collapses are /r/badeconomics territory (and routinely do show up there)</claim>.

&gt;There have been 4 jobs or activities which Man has engaged in throughout the centuries

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="5" rel="undercutter" ref="0">This is almost just a semantic argument.</claim>

&gt;workers will have nowhere to go but to the unemployment line.

<premise type="logos" id="6" rel="support" ref="7">Agriculture, manufacturing, and services have been getting better literally for milennia.</premise> 
<claim type="interpretation"  id="7" rel="rebuttal_attack" ref="0">There's no reason in particular for it to be *crossing the line* soon, especially within months.</claim>

&gt;At some point, Man's artificial economic system will necessarily collapse

Necessarily? <claim type="interpretation" id="8" rel="undercutter" ref="0">This is just an assertion, not even a theoretical argument provided to back it up.</claim>

&gt;When that happens, the corporations which produce and deliver food will no longer have an incentive to do so

No explanation given for this either.

&gt;The current jobless situation you read about in the news is not an ordinary part of the business cycle

What is the current jobless situation? <claim type="interpretation" id="9" rel="rebuttal_attack" ref="0">Unemployment's relatively low...</claim>

When you say economic collapse, what precisely do you mean? 
Market failures? 
Currency issues? 
A recession or depression? 
Bottom line is that <premise type="logos" id="10" rel="support" ref="11">people have predicted economic collapses literally since economies began</premise>. 
<claim type="interpretation"  id="11" rel="disagreement" ref="title">There is no reason in particular to believe one is impending.</claim> 
<claim type="evaluation_emotional"  id="12" rel="undercutter" ref="title">All of this is /r/conspiratard mixed with /r/badeconomics.</claim>


</reply>
<reply id="cneyprf" author="Oflameo">
<claim type="agreement"  id="13" rel="agreement" ref="11">You make a really good point.</claim> 
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="14" rel="agreement" ref="7">It doesn't make sense for people to just agree to walk away and starve to death</claim>. 
<premise type="logos"  id="15" rel="support" ref="14">At that point it would just make more sense to be professional privateers.</premise> 
I am going to check out /r/badeconomics, but until then ∆.
</reply>
</thread>
