<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rc3p3">
<title> <claim type="interpretation">CMV:Patriotism is the belief that being born on one side of a line makes you better.</claim></title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rc3p3/cmvpatriotism_is_the_belief_that_being_born_on/</source>
<OP author="sniperman357">

<claim type="interpretation" id="0" rel="agreement" ref="title">American patriots have a general mentality against immigration.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1" rel="support" rid="a" ref="0">Saying these people shouldn&#8217;t be allowed to become part of the country, is the same as saying they are worse,</premise> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="2" rel="support" rid="a" ref="0">because they were born on a different side of a line</premise>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="3" rel="support" rid="a" ref="0">americans are better because of the side of the line they are born on</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="4" rel="support" ref="0">This is prominent in many ads and political champagnes, namely the slogan &#8220;Creating jobs for americans&#8221;.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="6" rel="agreement" ref="title">I understand why politics use this slogan</claim>, <premise type="logos" id="7" rel="support" ref="6">because they are trying to get americans to vote for them</premise>, but <premise type="logos" id="8" rel="support" rid="b" ref="6">this slogan is also prominent in ads made by private corporations</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="9" rel="support" rid="b" ref="6">As if creating jobs for americans is morally superior to creating jobs for people of other countries.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="10" rel="support" rid="c" ref="6">The companies launching these ads may be trying to win in the american market, so they can sell more of their product,</premise> but <premise type="logos" id="11" rel="support" rid="c" ref="6">the fact that this can increase sales shows that many americans hold the being born on one side of a line belief</premise>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="12" rel="agreement" ref="6">I am not blaming the politicians or corporations running ads running these slogans</claim>, <premise type="logos" id="13" rel="support" ref="12">they are merely trying to win votes or make money from this mentality</premise>, but <claim type="interpretation" id="14" rel="agreement" ref="12">really it is the citizens that have the belief that they are better, because of the side of a line they are born on, that are at fault</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="15" rel="agreement" ref="14">Patriotism is really just this belief.</claim>

</OP>
<reply id="cnelqn6" author="Cmall2">
<claim type="interpretation" id="16" rel="undercutter" ref="title"> in this post you are confusing patriotism with its meaner, uglier cousin, nationalism. </claim> 
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="17" rel="support" ref="16"> According to George Orwell, Nationalism is the "worst enemy of peace". </premise> 
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="18" rel="support" ref="16"> According to him, nationalism is the thought of superiority of one's nation in direct comparison to foreign nations, </premise> whereas <premise type="logos" id="19" rel="support" ref="16"> patriotism is simply the love and admiration of one's own country, independent of other countries. </premise> 
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="20" rel="support" ref="16"> Nationalism is the one that says "America is the best, most perfect country in the world, unlike those other horrible, dirty, evil foreign countries. </premise> 
<premise type="pathos" id="21" rel="support" ref="16"> Americans are the shining example of civil people in the world and everyone else is filthy and brutish and doesn't deserve entry here". </premise> 
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="22" rel="support" ref="16"> Patriotism simply says "America is a good country. its not the best, and it might be better or worse than other countries, but i still love and respect it". </premise>

&gt; it is the citizens that have the belief that they are better

<claim type="interpretation" id="23" rel="rebuttal_attack" ref="14"> they do not have a belief that they are better. </claim> 
<premise type="logos" id="24" rel="support" ref="23"> they have the belief that they are American </premise>, and <premise type="logos" id="25" rel="support" ref="23"> would prefer their country over other countries, regardless of who's better </premise>

&gt; As if creating jobs for Americans is morally superior to creating jobs for people of other countries

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="26" rel="undercutter" ref="9"> not morally superior, but makes more sense. </claim> 
<premise type="logos" id="27" rel="support" ref="26"> even if countries are peaceful and cooperative towards each other, </premise> <premise type="logos" id="28" rel="support" ref="26"> they are still in competition and no matter what, they are still separate and independent. </premise> and <premise type="logos" id="29"> in a competition, you don't provide for the opposite side. </premise> 
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="30" rel="support" ref="26"> It is simply not our place or responsibility to carry other countries' burdens. </premise> 
<premise type="logos" id="31" rel="support" ref="26"> And these slogans don't even denote any sense of superiority over a foreign country, just a preference for your own country. </premise> 
<premise type="pathos" id="32" rel="support" ref="26"> if an advertisement was "creating jobs for Americans and not for those dirty foreign leeches", </premise> <premise type="logos" id="33" rel="support" ref="26"> THAT would be claiming superiority over foreigners. </premise> 
<claim type="interpretation" id="34" rel="undercutter" ref="title"> And ultimately, patriotism means different things to different people. </claim> 
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="35" rel="support" ref="34"> i’m sure for a great many people, it is patriotic to welcome and accept immigrants as equals under our ideals of equality and freedom </premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cneqtt5" author="sniperman357">
∆ This comment changed my view, because you said that people love their country, even if their country isn't objectively the best. 
This is mostly illustrated in the following sentences "Patriotism simply says "America is a good country. 
its not the best, and it might be better or worse than other countries, but i still love and respect it", and "they do not have a belief that they are better. 
they have the belief that they are American, and would prefer their country over other countries, regardless of who's better".
</reply>
</thread>
