<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qr8gn">
<title><claim type="evaluation_emotional">CMV: People who cheat on their spouses can and should, in some cases, be forgiven</claim></title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qr8gn/cmv_people_who_cheat_on_their_spouses_can_and/</source>
<OP author="Li54">

<premise type="pathos" id="0" rel="support" ref="1">There seems to be a commonly held belief that people who cheat on their SO/partner should be dropped immediately with no further contact.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="1" rel="partial_disagreement" ref="title">I understand that physical/sexual conduct with another person can seem like a betrayal</claim>, but <premise type="pathos" id="2" rel="support" ref="1">in some cases, there are many worse things that can happen in a relationship, which couples seem to be able to work through.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="3" rel="agreement" ref="title">There are a few assumptions underlying the belief that "sex with another person = relationship over" that I don't think hold up.</claim>

* <premise type="logos_pathos" id="4" rel="support" ref="3">**Sex is the most important part of a relationship,** and therefore, betraying it and that agreement mean the relationship should end.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="5" rel="agreement" ref="title">My belief: sex is a very important part of a relationship, but not *the* most important part.</claim>
Immediately breaking up with someone because of something like this seems excessive.

* <premise type="logos_pathos" id="6" rel="support" ref="3">**Nobody makes mistakes ever,** so when they do, the relationship should end.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="7" rel="agreement" ref="title">My belief: obviously this isn't true, and a cornerstone of strong relationships is the ability to work through mistakes/issues together.</claim>

* <premise type="logos_pathos" id="8" rel="support" ref="3">**Cheaters will always cheat again,** so better to end it now.</premise> <claim type="interpretation" id="9" rel="partial_disagreement" ref="title">my view: That may be true in some cases</claim>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="10" rel="support" ref="9">other than anecdotal evidence, I haven't seen anything to support this claim.</premise> [
But would be really interested in reading anything scientific about this, actually!]

* <premise type="logos_pathos" id="11" rel="support" ref="3">**Cheaters cheat because of underlying issues with the relationship.**</premise> <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="12" rel="agreement" ref="title">My belief: if that's true, there are a lot of possibilities - not just breaking up - that could fix the problem</claim>, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="13" rel="support" ref="12">such as ... talking about the problem.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="14" rel="support" ref="12">Maybe fixing that issue will resolve the motivation to cheat.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="15" rel="partial_disagreement" ref="12">Caveat: sometimes, cheating happens because there are parts of the relationship that are fundamentally broken and/or the relationship is too far gone/unsalvageable and/or this is the straw the broke the camel's back etc.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="16" rel="agreement" ref="title">Cheating shouldn't always signify an immediate end to a relationship.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="17" rel="agreement" ref="title">In some cases, couples can and should choose to work through it</claim>.
CMV!

</OP>
<reply id="cn9b5po" author="qezler">

<premise type="ethos" id="19" rel="support" ref="20">I'l begin by saying it has never happened to me</premise>, and <claim type="agreement" id="20" rel="agreement" ref="title">you make some good points.</claim>
But I'm addicted to CMV, so here we go.

&gt;sex is a very important part of a relationship, but not the most important part. 

So it is one of the most important parts.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="21" rel="rebuttal" ref="4">To break it would be to break one of the most important parts of a marriage</claim>.
I'll continue.

*edit: <premise type="logos_pathos" id="23" rel="support" rid="a" ref="20">even if you value it not at all, cheating breaks other important parts of the relationship.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="24" rel="support" rid="a" ref="20">Like trust.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="25" rel="support" rid="a" ref="20">Loyalty.</premise> 
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="26" rel="support" rid="a" ref="20">Companionship.</premise>

&gt;Nobody makes mistakes ever, so when they do, the relationship should end. 

<claim type="agreement" id="27" rel="agreement" ref="4">You are correct that this is false.</claim>
<premise type="pathos" id="28" rel="support" ref="27">However, cheating on a spouse is *pretty big mistake*.</premise> 
<claim type="interpretation" id="29" rel="rebuttal" ref="title">Cheating, as I define it, is a choice.</claim>
<premise type="pathos" id="30" rel="support" ref="28">A bad choice which breaks one of the cornerstones of marriage.</premise>

&gt;Cheaters will always cheat again

<claim type="agreement" id="31" rel="agreement" ref="9">You are correct that this is false.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="32" rel="disagreement" ref="9">However, I would say that *cheaters are more likely to cheat again*.</claim> <premise type="ethos_logos" id="33" rel="support" ref="32">The circumstances that resulted in cheating the first time may repeat.</premise>

&gt;Cheaters cheat because of underlying issues with the relationship. My belief: if that's true, there are a lot of possibilities - not just breaking up - that could fix the problem, such as ... talking about the problem. 

<claim type="agreement" id="34" rel="agreement" ref="12">Yes.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="35" rel="rebuttal" ref="12">But "talking about the problem" is an ideal situation.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="36" rel="support" ref="34">It often doesn't work out so well that way.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="37">People get stuck in a pattern... living in the same house, married to the same person you stopped really caring about.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="38" rel="support" ref="34">Cheating is evidence that *something* must be wrong.</premise>

So, so far we can say cheating

* <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="39" rel="agreement" ref="29">is a bad choice which breaks one of the cornerstones of a relationship</claim>

* <claim type="interpretation" id="40" rel="agreement" ref="32">is an indication that such a thing will happen again</claim>

* <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="41" rel="agreement" ref="34">is an indication that there is a problem with the relationship</claim>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="42" rel="support" ref="39">Are there no situations in which the cheaters should be forgiven?</premise> <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="43" rel="rebuttal" ref="title">I'm trying to argue that if you find your spouse cheating, breaking up with them is the most logical thing to do, whatever the circumstances.</claim>

<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="44" rel="support" ref="43">I point out, cheating has a profound negative emotional effect of the person cheated on.</premise>
You have every reason to break up.

<claim type="interpretation" id="45" rel="rebuttal" ref="title">In my mind, marriage is a commitment.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="46" rel="rebuttal" ref="title">If you break that commitment, the marriage is broken.</claim>

<premise type="pathos" id="47" rel="support" ref="46">One partner isn't fulfilling all of his/her obligations (i.e. not to cheat)</premise> <premise type="pathos" id="48" rel="support" ref="46">So why should the other person be obligated to fill out his/hers?</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="49" rel="support" ref="46">Why should you stay married?</premise>

<claim type="interpretation" id="50" rel="rebuttal" ref="title">It is entirely up to the person making the decision as to what they may do.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="51" rel="support" ref="50">It's an ethical question</premise>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="52" rel="support" ref="50">everyone has their different values</premise>, so <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="53" rel="rebuttal" ref="title">it's impossible to prove definitively what you should/should not do.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="54" rel="rebuttal" ref="title">It's just a logical conclusion that breaking up is the right choice in most if not all situations.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="55" rel="support" ref="54">It's a choice.</premise>

<premise type="logos" id="56" rel="support" ref="54">But if you don't break up, you are stuck with a person who doesn't value you enough to stay loyal.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="57" rel="support" ref="54">Why would you forfeit yourself to such a relationship?</premise>

<premise type="pathos" id="58" rel="support" ref="54">Things need change.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="59" rel="support" ref="54">And the cheater is the source of the problem.</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="60" rel="rebuttal" ref="title">Change the cheater by breaking up with him/her.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cn9j8n8" author="Li54">

&#8710;

&gt; marriage is a commitment. If you break that commitment, the marriage is broken. 

This is the best argument I've heard so far.
Thanks!

</reply>
</thread>
<!--> <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="18">.</claim> </!--> 
<!--> <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="22">.</claim> </!--> 
