<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qnzap">
<title><claim type="interpretation">CMV: Surplus Value Theorem is definitive proof that capitalism is an inefficient system.</claim></title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qnzap/cmv_surplus_value_theorem_is_definitive_proof/</source>
<OP author="SouthernGlenfidditch">

<premise type="logos" id="0" rel="support" ref="3">As I understand it, and crudely explained, SVT says that in an economic system that lets people hire other people for labour</premise>, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3">waste has to be produced in order for the system to function</claim>.

Example: <premise type="pathos" id="4" rel="support" ref="3">Consider a society of 101 people: 100 workers and 1 boss.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="5" rel="support" ref="3">The boss owns the factory where the workers work</premise>, and <premise type="logos" id="6" rel="support" ref="3">they produce, say, MLP dolls that everyone wants to buy</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="7" rel="support" ref="3">The boss pays each of her workers &#163;5 for each doll that the worker produces, and a worker produces 1 doll a day</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="8" rel="support" ref="3">At the end of the day, the boss has 100 dolls, worth &#163;1000 and has paid out &#163;500</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="9" rel="support" ref="3">Wanting to make a profit on the dolls, the boss then sells the dolls for &#163;10 each.</premise>
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="10" rel="support" ref="3">She is now trying to sell &#163;1000 worth of dolls</premise>, but <premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="11" rel="support" ref="3">the only people available to sell to are the workers, who's total funds are &#163;500</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="12" rel="support" ref="3">No matter how they rearrange the money between them, they will be unable to buy more than &#163;500 worth of the dolls</premise>, and so <premise type="logos" id="13" rel="support" ref="3">the rest are waste inherent to the system and a direct result of the boss wanting to make profit.</premise>

<premise type="logos" id="14" rel="support" ref="16">This example then scales up to the whole world when you throw in multiple bosses and lots more workers but the basic idea is the same</premise>: if <premise type="logos" id="15" rel="support" ref="16">each worker is being paid less than the price of the things they produce so that their boss can profit</premise>, then <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="16">items that cannot be sold must still be produced and thrown away.</claim>

</OP>
<reply id="cn7x1ic" author="ghotionInABarrel">
&gt; The boss pays each of her workers £5 for each doll that the worker produces

<premise type="logos" id="17" rel="support" ref="18">Most people aren't paid on commission</premise>, so <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="18" rel="undercutter" ref="7">this isn't really a good example</claim>, but <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="19" rel="partial_agreement" ref="3">I think I get where you're going with it.</claim>

&gt;if each worker is being paid less than the price of the things they produce

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="20" rel="undercutter" ref="15">But the money doesn't just disappear.</claim>
For one thing, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="21" rel="support" ref="20">you're neglecting the janitor who is necessary to keep the factory functioning (and presumably gets paid) but doesn't "produce" anything.</premise>
You're also neglecting that <premise type="logos_pathos" id="22" rel="support" ref="20">when this system scales up you need to include the boss buying things.</premise>

Since <premise type="logos" id="23" rel="support" ref="24">whatever profit the boss makes goes back into the system as they spend money</premise>, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="24" rel="rebuttal_attack" ref="16">there should be at all times enough money in the system to cover the value of what it produced</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="25" rel="support" ref="26">This value may not be the price being charged for the thing</premise>, and <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="26">that's where supply and demand are involved</claim>.

I'm not going to deny that <premise type="logos_pathos" id="27" rel="partial_agreement" ref="16">sometimes (or a lot of the time) the boss just hoards their extra money and doesn't re-inject it</premise>, but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="28" rel="partial_attack" ref="16">that's more a failure of the system than the system itself</claim>.
<claim type="agreement" id="29" rel="undercutter" ref="16">The same goes for when something is priced above its market value</claim>, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="30" rel="support" ref="29">it won't sell and will be waste</premise>, but that's because <premise type="logos_pathos" id="31" rel="support" ref="29">the seller overpriced it</premise>, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="32" rel="support" ref="29">not because it was doomed to be waste as soon as it was made.</premise>

<claim type="disagreement" id="33" rel="partial_agreement" ref="3">No ideal system is really going to be inefficient</claim>, <claim type="interpretation" id="34" rel="partial_attack" ref="3">its the real ones that have problems.</claim>

If <premise type="logos" id="35" rel="support" ref="36">you mean to say that real-life capitalism is inefficient</premise>, then <claim type="agreement" id="36" rel="partial_agreement" ref="3">no one is going to dispute you</claim>, but I will point out that <claim type="interpretation" id="37" rel="partial_attack" ref="3">it's the most efficient real system we have</claim>.

</reply>
<reply id="cn7yrgj" author="SouthernGlenfidditch">

&#8710;
That makes a lot of sense!
Thank you! I can accept that <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="38" rel="agreement" ref="33">it would be a wasteless system if there were multiple factories and the boss spent all of their money!</claim>
I can definitely think of other bits of inefficiency but that wasn't the question so nevermind! :)

</reply>
</thread>
