<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qnu4z">
<title><claim type="interpretation">CMV: The highest form of relationship between men and women doomed to be romance</claim></title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qnu4z/cmv_the_highest_form_of_relationship_between_men/</source>
<OP author="Skinners_Pidgeon">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">Maybe it has to do with being an adolescent and being new to dealing with the opposite sex</claim>, but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="1">I'm beginning to fall under the assumption that the only purpose for guys to get to know girls is to eventually engage in romance.</claim>

<premise type="pathos" id="2" rel="support" ref="3">"Why else do men engage women in conversation in public?"</premise> I wonder (<claim type="interpretation" id="3">my perception might just be distorted after reading Neil Strauss's *The Game*</claim>).
"<premise type="logos_pathos" id="4" rel="support" ref="1">Why do I feel like chasing after girls and getting to know them when I have so many great guy friends already who I know care about me so much more?</premise> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="5" rel="support" ref="1">Why can't I be friends with girls (even pretty ones) and not feel insecure when I don't try to advance some romantic agenda?</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="6" rel="support" ref="1">Why do I find myself inevitably becoming attracted to them?</premise>"

I have so many more questions regarding the non-romantic side of male-female relationships, but instead of writing an abhorrent block of text nobody could possibly be expected to read, I ask just the one title question (thinking that <claim type="interpretation" id="9">the above questions are more like fragments of a bigger picture of misunderstanding</claim>) <premise type="logos" id="10" rel="support" ref="9">because I want to know what older, more mature people think</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="11">It also must distort my view to have gone to an all-boy's school for the majority of my life.</claim>

At times, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="12">I feel like the interplay between men and women is always (at least always initially) a bs game</claim> where <premise type="logos_pathos" id="13" rel="support" ref="12">the man tries to show the woman how non-threatening and valuable he is from a non-romantic standpoint before she is comfortable with allowing herself to think of him as a safe partner</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="14" rel="support" ref="15">Something about that seems so sinister, cynical, and hollow to me</premise> that <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="15">I can't stand it</claim>.
Please change this view.

</OP>
<reply id="cn7xcvt" author="sciguy2000">

Well, first off, there's <premise type="logos" id="16" rel="rebuttal" ref="1">the fact that most people aren't interested in romance with family members of the opposite sex</premise>, but I figure you're excluding that.
So, here's what I've experienced as a 19-year-old male college student.

A lot of the times, yes, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="17" rel="partial_agreement" ref="1">women and men do interact in a romantic way, one trying to impress the other to get involved in romance</claim>.
It happens.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="18" rel="partial_agreement" ref="1">There are a lot of great, good-looking people out there.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="19" rel="partial_agreement" ref="1">Jeez, my college is known for being the land of partying, gorgeous college people.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="20" rel="partial_attack" ref="1">But romance just isn't as cut and dry as that.</claim>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="21" rel="support" ref="20">The one thing I've learned about life and romance going through high school and college? There is no manual.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="22" rel="support" ref="20">None.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="23" rel="support" ref="20">And we try to define all of these interactions between the sexes as one thing or another because it's easy.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="24" rel="support" ref="20">But it really isn't.</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="25" rel="support" ref="26">I can think a girl is absolutely gorgeous and still be friends with them, mostly because I don't think she's the one for me.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="26" rel="undercutter" ref="1">That doesn't devalue them,</claim> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="27" rel="support" ref="26">just because I don't feel like I want to keep someone exclusively to myself doesn't mean I care for them any less.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="28" rel="support" ref="26">And just trying to be romantic with women, assuming the endgoal of any compatible people is romance, completely cuts out some of the most beautiful times you can have with people.</premise> 
I've taught a friend how to drive, letting her find a passion in a shitty life.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="29" rel="support" ref="34">I've spent countless all-nighters with a friend just shooting shit, due to insomnia and boredom.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="30" rel="support" ref="34">I've held a friend so close after she told me I was the biggest reason she hadn't killed herself.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="31" rel="support" ref="34">I've watched stars fall on a hilltop so clear and beautiful as I called a friend a sister for the first time.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="32" rel="support" ref="34">So many interactions.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="33" rel="support" ref="34">So many beautiful, hard, wonderful, life-changing experiences I've had because of friendships with women.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="34" rel="undercutter" ref="1">And it's no harder than being a friend with a guy,</claim> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="35" rel="support" ref="34">because we seem to forget so many times that women are people too, they are sad, happy, lonely and joyful at times, just like us.</premise>
So stop thinking about how it's supposed to be done and just let things go on.
If you want to be exclusive with a girl, go for it.
But sometimes?
<premise type="ethos_pathos" id="36" rel="support" ref="34">Sometimes you love a person without needing to hold them close to you.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="37" rel="support" ref="34">Experience that, I beg you.</premise>
Something as simple and beautiful as all that should never, ever be left unexperienced.

</reply>
<reply id="cn7xyei" author="Skinners_Pidgeon">

&#8710;

This is a great way to look at it. I come from this all-boy's school background, and I can't shake the feeling of loss when a male friend of mine gets together with a female friend.
I feel like I'm impinging on their relationship whenever I try to interact with the girl because I'm afraid that my male friend will think that there's some ulterior motive involved.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="39" rel="partial_agreement" ref="20">What all of you seem to be telling me so far is that the highest form of relationship doesn't have to be romantic</claim>, yet for some reason <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="40" rel="partial_attack" ref="20">I wonder how you've make such good friends and been able to keep it fully platonic with all of them.</claim>
I hope that's not a bad thing to wonder--<premise type="logos_pathos" id="41" rel="support" ref="40">I just thought that if you get that close with someone, they might be for you.</premise>

</reply>
</thread>
