<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rkzen">
<title>CMV: Eugenics isn't all that bad... And we don't even have to kill anyone for it</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rkzen/cmv_eugenics_isnt_all_that_bad_and_we_dont_even/</source>
<OP author="Seventh_______">
Okay, I'm talking about making the human race smarter, forever.
Intelligence is at least partially genetic and therefore passed down by parents, yes? [Yes.](http://www.the-scientist.com/?articles.view/articleNo/40459/title/Inherited-Intelligence/)

So, what if, instead of killing off the less-intelligent people (I'm against killing. Of most things.) we just limit offspring?

For example, we could use the IQ scale (for want of a better intelligence measure) to determine the number of offspring a person should be able to genetically contribute to.
Like, round the IQ to the nearest multiple of 50, then divide by 50, and that's the number of offspring you're allowed to create.

So someone with near average intelligence (near 100 IQ, 75-124) would have their IQ rounded to 100 and then divided by 50 to make 2 offspring. 
The total offspring is presumably equal to the number of people who contributed to it. A man and a woman with average IQ can have two children (not each.) and sustain their population.

Conversely, really above average IQs of 125-174 can contribute genetically towards 3 children... and so on.

This would eventually make the human race smarter, and therefore more likely to survive and advance the human race. 

I know this would be a bitch to implement and it's near impossible to actually do, but I'm just looking at the concept. I know the IQ test has its faults and every policy can be abused... I know all that.

Exceptions would be made when you accidentally have twins which causes you to go over your limit, or etc. (If a mother can make 2, and has twins, she can't make more, but if she already has one and has twins after one which makes 3, we're not gonna kill one)

Perhaps if you have a major, heritable health issue your IQ has 25 subtracted from it before being rounded? Or maybe weighted differently, like extremely high chance of cancer (almost 100 percent or something) takes off more... Something like that.

Much better than "Kill off those with IQ less than 80"

I wouldn't mind a smarter human race...

EDIT: **I am trying to argue that this process, if not abused, if followed by the people, and if we found an increasingly accurate measure of intelligence, would be ultimately a good thing to advance the human race.**

EDIT 2: "**It looks to me like you've made so many exceptions to your main view that you aren't looking to have your view changed. I'd like to talk about the title of your post, but if you have to make so many exceptions to your view, then it seems you already know it's incorrect.**" -nikeson
I suppose that's true, now....
_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnguj0n" author="sennalvera">
Every time a proposal like this comes up I am reminded of why it's such a bad idea: not because we couldn't do it, but because we don't yet have the wisdom to do it right. You've just laid out a manifesto for making the human race more intelligent, but nowhere in it have you questioned whether or not it's a good idea. *Why* do we need to be more intelligent? Why would a more intelligent society automatically be a better one? If we improve our brains in this one regard might we end up diminishing them in other, unanticipated, ways? We don't yet know enough about the biology of it to even speculate. Simply put, we are not ready for eugenics. 
</reply>
<reply id="cngv0e6" author="Seventh_______">
Yay fuzzy logic

"well we don't know *for sure* so I guess we can't ever try or find out ever"

Also, I don't really understand how it's *not* a better thing to be more intelligent. Like in any way. You can make wiser, more informed decisions to impact your future in a positive way.

Of course, we would also adjust the selection process to minimize "unanticipated ways" of diminishing our brain as we got better at figuring this stuff out.
</reply>
<reply id="cngvxiy" author="sennalvera">
You 'try and find out' with a new recipe or prototype engine design. You don't 'try and find out' with the human species. What if you're wrong? What if we end up breeding in mental instability and don't notice until too late? I may not be a genetically enhanced superhuman but I do know that our bodies and brains are a dizzyingly complex array of interconnections and balances. The brain is particularly poorly understood. Messing with it at our current level of knowledge would be insanely reckless.

&gt;Also, I don't really understand how it's not a better thing to be more intelligent. Like in any way.

No, you don't. As another commenter said, eugenics is vulnerable to our prejudices, and we've all been raised to believe that intelligence is unquestionably good. It's part of our culture and from earliest childhood we're urged to attain it. But if you could step into a time machine and ask people from different eras what the most valuable human trait was you might get some surprising answers. Many would say strength and courage; others virtue and piety; others duty and obedience. I think you need to step back and question your preconceptions. Can you give some concrete examples of problems that greater intelligence would solve?
</reply>
<reply id="cngwk2x" author="Seventh_______">
∆  
*sighs*  
Yeah.  
Edit: sennalvera points out how you shouldn't toy with thinks like human life, which I didn't consider much before my argument. That's what the delta is for. also sennalvera explained the prejudices thing in a better way
</reply>
</thread>
