<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rkplw">
<title>CMV: "What is your favorite X" does not stimulate interesting discussion and shouldn't be allowed on strictly moderated forums/subreddits.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rkplw/cmv_what_is_your_favorite_x_does_not_stimulate/</source>
<OP author="alexskc95">
Like "What is your favorite line from a TV show" or "What is your favorite movie poster."

These threads always get hugely upvoted and loads of comments because everyone likes to share things they like, but they never really produce anything meaningful. Just people gushing about "OMG X IS SO AMAZING."

On top of this, since everybody feels that their favorite is more important than everybody else's, you'll get a bunch of top-level replies with very little discussion beyond them. If there are replies, they usually just agree with the above poster. "OMG YES I KNOW." Nobody wants to be the dissent in a "positivity thread," or they just haven't heard of your favorite thing and aren't going to watch a 2h movie/play a 50h game/whatever for every single response in that thread, anyway.

There's generally very little to learn from things that are done *well.* The exception is multiple viewpoints or interpretations of something, but you can only really get that if you have a large number of people discussing the same thing, which these kinds of threads very much discourage.


_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cngs21e" author="nonowh0">
The posts that you are talking about usually come up on fan subreddits. things like /r/bigbangtheory. They rarely (but sometimes) come up on serious subreddits (like this one). 

The point of most of the fan subreddits is to talk and share stuff about whatever show/game/movie that they are interested in. *It isn't always to have meaningful/interesting discussions.* But for the sake of argument, lets say that it is: all posts must contribute to an interesting conversation.   

&gt; but they never really produce anything meaningful. Just people gushing about "OMG X IS SO AMAZING."

At first, I wasn't so sure about this point, so I searched /r/bigbangtheory for "what is your favorite" and clicked on the [first link](http://www.reddit.com/r/bigbangtheory/comments/10zjbj/what_is_your_favorite_moment_on_tbbt/). 

Some of this stuff is what you predicted: "this is a fantastic scene!" and "I know right!". But some of it was more interesting stuff:

&gt; I agree. I think last night's episode finally showed that Sheldon actually has some humanity inside and isn't just a robot. Deep down inside he really is a nice person but he doesn't know how to express it.
It sort of amplifies his actions in "The Staircase Implementation" that yes, he was thinking logically, but he's still a human being that cares about his friends very much.

or

&gt; I actually thought that was a good move. It snapped Sheldon's character back before he got ruined and saved it from being "a very special episode."
It was just enough to make the point yet not lose the rhythm of the characters' interaction.

Both of these comments contributed to a larger discussion that (imo) was very meaningful.

I think that many of the "what is your favorite..." posts eventually contribute to a larger discussion that is meaningful in it's own right, despite the fact that most of these fan subreddits aren't aiming to have meaningful discussions.  

  


</reply>
<reply id="cngskvh" author="alexskc95">
&amp;#8710;.

I suppose specific questions or niche communities can be an exception. If only because *everyone* is so familiar with the material that responses to top-level comments and discussion are guaranteed.

I still believe that more general questions still apply, though. "What is your favorite passage from Lolita" can stimulate discussion. "What is your favorite horror book," not so much.
</reply>
</thread>
