<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rppq9">
<title>CMV: Religion is not violent or not violent, its followers are.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rppq9/cmv_religion_is_not_violent_or_not_violent_its/</source>
<OP author="DurianMD">
So recently I've seen a lot of posts condemning Islam as a violent religion or a sexist religion. I point out that many Christians follow the bible which has numerous examples of sexism, but in application, there are numerous branches of Christianity that are no more sexist than secular groups. For example, Congregationalists and Universaliists. 

So, my belief is that while religion can inform the views of people, it is far more likely that religion will be used to justify actions that would have been executed any way. I think that most Jewish people don't want to stone adulterers and most Muslims don't want to stone non believers. 

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cni5c2h" author="09112001">
I look at it from a different angle — the text(s) of any particular religion either inherently promote violence or they do not. The followers of the religion, however, often tend to pick and choose which parts to follow based on their own upbringings, culture, personality, etc. So I'd rebut your statement by saying that both a religion **and** its followers can be violent or non-violent.
</reply>
<reply id="cni5hry" author="DurianMD">
Okay, tell me if I'm moving the goalposts, but I tend to think of religion as being the sum of the culture and the texts and, wait... That means that the actions of the followers are the religion in which case the religion is only as violent as its followers. In that case, if a religion's followers stopped being violent, then the religion itself would become less violent, although it would still have the textual component. 

I think I'm making an either or argument when the answer lies somewhere in between. 

∆  
</reply>
</thread>
