<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rexe3">
<title>CMV: EMTs, SAR, firefighters, police, etc. should receive “military discounts”.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rexe3/cmv_emts_sar_firefighters_police_etc_should/</source>
<OP author="ke7ofi">
For those of you who don’t know, it’s common (at least in the US) for businesses, transit agencies, etc. to give small discounts to military veterans to thank them for their service.

It seems that medical responders (even hospital staff, actually) and other emergency services do more good for society than soldiers and that such discounts should be given to them.

As for the “They’re not risking their lives for our country.” argument, police officers do that too, and for citizens rather than the country and its interests. Some might argue that soldiers do the US a disservice rather than help, but that’s [usually] the fault of their leaders and therefore not relevant to the debate.

I’m really hoping there’s a good reason behind the status quo, but we’ll see. [It looks like there’s even less reason behind it than I initially thought, actually.]

[edits in brackets]

[[My view’s been changed.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rexe3/cmv_emts_sar_firefighters_police_etc_should/cnfj9cu?context=10000) In summary, I think that EMS people are just as deserving of these discounts (and that many more people contribute enough to be placed in the same category), but I now believe - for the same reason - that these discounts shouldn’t be offered at all.]
_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnf8xlt" author="wahtisthisidonteven">
&gt;give small discounts to military veterans to thank them for their service.

I challenge the idea that these are to "thank them for their service". In actuality, military discounts serve as an advertisement to draw a certain demographic to your business. They're like coupons in a way, bringing in new customers and making them loyal by giving them 5-10% off, but still making you substantially more profit than if they'd not come in at all.

Part of the effect of this advertising is the exclusivity. People wouldn't clip the $1 coupons and come in if just anyone got $1 off. If business owners similarly extended military discounts too far, it could cut into their ability to be effective.

On a personal level, though, I agree that "military discount" becoming "public service discount" wouldn't be a bad idea. It should be noted, however, that this would extend to even people like politicians, teachers, and government administrators
</reply>
<reply id="cnfgh6f" author="Waylander0719">
What about engineers?
</reply>
<reply id="cnfh3wv" author="t_hab">
And entrepreneurs?

And just about anybody who does something productive with their day? 
</reply>
<reply id="cnfhdgm" author="wahtisthisidonteven">
And here we come back to the initial point, the discount isn't as a thank-you for something done, it is just an attempt to target a specific demographic and draw their business by making them feel like they've got an exclusive deal.

If it was actually intended to repay some kind of service, it would cut into the business' bottom line, but the vast majority of discounts do not do this.
</reply>
<reply id="cnfj9cu" author="ke7ofi">
At this point, you’ve changed my view. Most people contribute to society, so I’m now against nearly any sort of “public service” discount.

Δ
</reply>
</thread>
