<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rcsdh">
<title>CMV: Humans are going to die out because of an economic collapse</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rcsdh/cmv_humans_are_going_to_die_out_because_of_an/</source>
<OP author="Oflameo">
Bill Gade presents the argument better than I do so I will just quote him.

&gt;There have been 4 jobs or activities which Man has engaged in throughout the centuries: Hunter/Gathering, Agriculture, Manufacturing, and Services. What's next? What category can you imagine in which billions of people will be working in the future?
&gt;
It turns out that there is a final category. It is known as Unemployment. As Agriculture, Manufacturing, and Services become more efficient in the coming months, workers will have nowhere to go but to the unemployment line. At some point, Man's artificial economic system will necessarily collapse. When that happens, the corporations which produce and deliver food will no longer have an incentive to do so. The cities will suffer great hunger and it will be the end of Man.
&gt;
The current jobless situation you read about in the news is not an ordinary part of the business cycle. It is the final stretch of the linear trend that began with the birth of our species.

There is also a Youtube video to go with this opinion. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rlQrYCacrKo&amp;spfreload=10

I do realize that this is a very unhealthy idea to have whether or not that the idea is true or not, I just have not been able to beat it myself.

I do disagree with Gade a little bit. I don't think it would kill everybody, but the some few people that still know how to hunt and gather would probably survive as well people who were rich enough to have access to a lot of resources to start out with before the economy crashes. I probably believe this because I listen to Alex Jones too much.
</OP>
<reply id="cneonwb" author="biccib">
I watched the video, and I understand it.

Bill Gade's theory is not rigorous.

I agree that the economy will probably collapse some time over the next few decades from a combination of ecological pressure and automation.

But just use your common sense. Unemployment is at 90% and you're a senior politician/a ceo with influence on the government - do you A. let 90% of people *die* from starvation and exposure, or do you B. redistribute the money being made by the active 10% to take care of them via mechanisms like regulatory limits on automation or a guaranteed basic income? 

The economic collapse is plausible, but Gade's arguments are weak, not to mention contradictory, and his "if.. then" statements don't even follow a lot of the time - "If the global economic system collapses, then the agricultural sector will have no further incentive to grow crops" whut lol. So because there's no stock market or international trade, everyone will stop buying food? There are many faulty connections like this.

The economic collapse won't lead to the death of humanity, or even the end of civilization. Please throw that video away, and if you still think that the collapse will end humanity after discarding Gade's arguments then come back and talk about it.
</reply>
<reply id="cnep6dx" author="Oflameo">
That is a good point. His theory isn't rigorous and that is enough to dismiss it and give you one of these ∆.

The only problem I have left is that I still believe that there are probably some very rich and powerful people that would prefer it to be true and would go the distance causing a biological disaster to combo the ecological disaster to guarantee that that would happen. 

I can dismiss that by the fact that there are rich and powerful people would would go the distance to prevent that from happening and it probably is not a likely scenario in general.
</reply>
</thread>
