<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rosbp">
<title>CMV: Captions translating Arabic into English need to have "Allahu Akbar" displayed as "God is Greater" or "God is [the] Greatest".</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rosbp/cmv_captions_translating_arabic_into_english_need/</source>
<OP author="ChagSC">
This is a tough one to explain and may not fit this sub. Unfortunately I have no current examples to show you. 

I've noticed a few times on the news when they are showing Arabic translations into English, they translate everything except *Allahu Akbar*.

The main reason for this post is I was recently at the 9/11 Memorial Museum. One of the exhibits allows you to relive the experience of United Flight 93 in real time in a mini-theater. 

Part of this is listening to the hijackers speak, which they translate on the screen in English. Everything was translated into English except it displayed  *Allahu Akbar!* every time instead of the English translation. 

I am torn between feeling I am reading too much into it and it being a vehicle for propaganda against Islam. Hiding the fact that is it is Islam's praise of God, which is a rhetoric the religious West shares. 

Please CMV.
</OP>
<reply id="cnhxfvv" author="McKoijion">
One major reason the phrase (called the Takbir) isn't translated is because Allahu Akbar is the correct phrase in pretty much every language. If you go to Indonesia for example, Muslims will still use the phrase Allahu Akbar instead of the Indonesian translation.

A big reason why is that unlike the Bible, which can be translated into many languages, if a Quran is translated into a language that is not Arabic, it is no longer considered a holy book. Muslims believe that Allah himself spoke to Muhammed, who simply wrote down what Allah said. That means that the Arabic words are the literal word of God. Scribes have copied the exact words perfectly ever since the book was first written. If it is translated, it is no longer the exact word of God, but rather an interpretation that has been influenced by the translator's beliefs.

That's why someone can translate the everyday language, but not the Takbir.

Here is some more information about it: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quran_translations
</reply>
<reply id="cnhy6ks" author="ChagSC">
&amp;#8710; 

That completely makes sense. And much more probable than what I was thinking. I imagine it would be considered disrespectful to translate even. Thank you.
</reply>
</thread>
