<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r9169">
<title>CMV: i have a hard time feeling sympathetic towards ebola aid workers (and feel bad about it)</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r9169/cmv_i_have_a_hard_time_feeling_sympathetic/</source>
<OP author="jirachi81">
in the uk there's a story going on right now of a nurse who got transferred to a london hospital/isolation ward, and that her condition is deteriorating rapidly.

i don't take death lightly, i try and picture myself in that situation and everything i would be thinking, and it's awful to think about. at the same time though i think "what were you really expecting?"

even worse than this i'm slightly resentful over aid workers sometimes, for instance she shared a plane on the way back with other people, imagine how they must have felt upon hearing they shared the same flight? parents getting given the idea "if we happened to get hit with awful luck, we may just have to watch our kids getting lowered into a grave in a coffin", or flight workers who could easily be you or me pondering "well I may never see my family again" if they happened to shake hands on the way out

i dunno, is it really fair on those people? or her family who could have easily been exposed to it? i know she was trying to help people, but she's also creating a risk for innocent people who equally don't deserve to die.

sometimes i just feel like saying "jeez, just stop it you idiot, don't you realise how foolish you're being? why are you risking leaving your entire family behind like that? it's not worth it"

my rough thoughts, I guess
_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cndksh4" author="wahtisthisidonteven">
How is this any different than being unable to feel sympathetic for people who choose any dangerous profession? We need firemen, we need police, we need soldiers and builders and fishermen. These people are paid for what they do, and they accept that they're entering into a risky environment to do their job. They take these risks because they're necessary.
</reply>
<reply id="cndlii1" author="jirachi81">
it makes sense when you say it generally, like "there's these people out there that fight fires" and it's like, thank god

but i keep thinking about it as if it were someone really close that i knew, like a friend. if you think about it like someone you know rather than an unknown person in the news, suddenly it becomes more like "you idiot, why are you risking this? it's not worth it".

i dunno, if it happened to your friend i think you'd be more angry than sympathetic, you'd think they were selfish. i kinda view it like that, it's weird

also i guess there's point that it's a virus, they're putting innocent people at risk, like their own families, somehow it just seems even more stupid, even though SOMEONE needs to do the job, I guess

i dunno, it's grey for me, my views aren't really clear cut

</reply>
<reply id="cndm5g8" author="wahtisthisidonteven">
You said yourself that you can understand the need for this kind of work in the abstract, you're just having a difficult time bringing it home.

Being able to empathize with others and sacrifice your time, efforts, or safety in order to preserve theirs is inherent to the human condition. Leaving behind that self-centeredness and recognizing that self-preservation is not the ultimate goal is one of the marks of maturity in modern society.

An internet forum isn't going to convince you to be empathetic through reasoned argument, it is something you glean from life experience and time.

&gt;i dunno, if it happened to your friend i think you'd be more angry than sympathetic, you'd think they were selfish. i kinda view it like that, it's weird

If I had a friend that made the choice to do something like this I would be proud of them, and try to help them be as safe as possible in their pursuit.
</reply>
<reply id="cnf8o8o" author="jirachi81">
all the comments in this thread helped, but i seemed to think about this comment chain the most

&amp;#8710;
</reply>
</thread>
