<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r85br">
<title>CMV: Why America isnt a scary place to move to</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r85br/cmv_why_america_isnt_a_scary_place_to_move_to/</source>
<OP author="Hyperderpityderp">
As you can read im not an American. Ive been dreaming of starting a clinic in America in the future, or to work in a medical clinic when i finish medical school in my own country. However reddit has made me think that America seems like a really scary place to live. On the othrr hand all american people ive personally met seem happy and enjoy life. My view of America is that it is a place where you can stack mad cash if youve got the right skills, mindset, work ethic and some luck. But also a place where the possibility of ending up bankrupt lurks around every corner. Every American seems like one major illness away from bankruptcy, the tendency of some Americans to sue can cost you millions (seriously, it's something most people i know can agree with and think such sums are ridiculous) Loopholes that can screw you over  and ridiculous ways you can get screwed over by and whatnot.~~Also comcast?~~ &lt;--(wasn't too serious about this)
tl:dr  America doesnt offer the life security i enjoy in my own country, and the thought of it really scares me.

EDIT: I live in the Netherlands. Sorry, forgot that that was quite relevent to the question.
Now i've come to think about it, the way i like my government right now is more socialistic. I like my 'free' healthcare and strict regulations for my own safety.

EDIT2: Apperently my view was heavily biased by the way the media completely exagerates or emphasised on certain parts of the story which can be very misleading. Thank you all for your views, and the ones that adressed my points have been awarded a delta. Thank you all!
</OP>
<reply id="cndbvxv" author="MrGraeme">
What is your own country?
</reply>
<reply id="cndcekt" author="Hyperderpityderp">
The netherlands
</reply>
<reply id="cnddeg9" author="MrGraeme">
The US is a very large place, and it has a wide variety of environments.

It's not really logical to assume the country as a whole is safe or unsafe, seeing as each state and region can be vastly different from others.

There are a plethora of reasons as to why the US is not a great place, even a scary place- but there are just as many which support the view that the US is a safe place.

While obviously there are issues regarding the legal system in the US, as well as the things you mentioned- many of these things are incredibly rare on the national scale.

It depends on where you go in the United States. Sure, places like Chicago and Detroit will seem worse and more scary than Amsterdam or Rotterdam, but places like Boulder City and Seattle may not.


</reply>
<reply id="cndenkz" author="Hyperderpityderp">
Can you elaborate how places like Boulder City and Seattle can be  different than Chicago? I guess tax laws affecting income or things like the demographic of those places? I find that rather interesting 
</reply>
<reply id="cndfbxg" author="MrGraeme">
It has a lot to do with the economics and demographics.

Take Chicago, for example, where nearly 20% of families are living below the poverty line, compared with nearly 7% of families in Seattle who are in a similar situation. This tends to contribute to higher crime rates, as well as a lower standard/quality of living in the more economically depressed city.

Demographics also play a large part in it- areas with a higher concentration of Hispanics and Blacks tend to be more dangerous(take Chicago and Detroit, for example), whereas places with a lower concentration of these groups tend to be safer, such as Franklin MA, Bergenfield NJ, and Parma OH are some of the safest communities in the country. [1](http://www.neighborhoodscout.com/neighborhoods/crime-rates/top100safest/) [2](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Franklin,_Massachusetts) [3](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bergenfield,_New_Jersey) [4](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parma,_Ohio) [Crime data](http://www.fbi.gov/about-us/cjis/ucr/crime-in-the-u.s/2011/crime-in-the-u.s.-2011/tables/table-43) confirms what I have stated above.

In reality, there is nothing to be afraid of if you are moving to a "safe" city, but there are plenty of places in the states that are terrifying. 


</reply>
<reply id="cndfr36" author="Hyperderpityderp">
Thanks a lot for your contribution sir!

My view has definitely changed!
Yes, as far as i know Detroit is the last place i went to end up in. but i
never knew that Chicago was on the lower end of the standard  quality of life. And violence like stabbings and shotwounds in a city isn't something i want to deal with in a clinic on a day to day basis. Violence in the neigborhood wouldn't be good for business so i should avoid those places. Thank you for your help!
&amp;#8710; !
</reply>
</thread>
