<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r85br">
<title>CMV: Why America isnt a scary place to move to</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r85br/cmv_why_america_isnt_a_scary_place_to_move_to/</source>
<OP author="Hyperderpityderp">
As you can read im not an American. Ive been dreaming of starting a clinic in America in the future, or to work in a medical clinic when i finish medical school in my own country. However reddit has made me think that America seems like a really scary place to live. On the othrr hand all american people ive personally met seem happy and enjoy life. My view of America is that it is a place where you can stack mad cash if youve got the right skills, mindset, work ethic and some luck. But also a place where the possibility of ending up bankrupt lurks around every corner. Every American seems like one major illness away from bankruptcy, the tendency of some Americans to sue can cost you millions (seriously, it's something most people i know can agree with and think such sums are ridiculous) Loopholes that can screw you over  and ridiculous ways you can get screwed over by and whatnot.~~Also comcast?~~ &lt;--(wasn't too serious about this)
tl:dr  America doesnt offer the life security i enjoy in my own country, and the thought of it really scares me.

EDIT: I live in the Netherlands. Sorry, forgot that that was quite relevent to the question.
Now i've come to think about it, the way i like my government right now is more socialistic. I like my 'free' healthcare and strict regulations for my own safety.

EDIT2: Apperently my view was heavily biased by the way the media completely exagerates or emphasised on certain parts of the story which can be very misleading. Thank you all for your views, and the ones that adressed my points have been awarded a delta. Thank you all!
</OP>
<reply id="cndclt3" author="man2010">
It's going to be hard to compare America to your current country of residence without knowing what country you're currently living in, but I'll try to alleviate some of your concerns about America anyways.

&gt; My view of America is that it is a place where you can stack mad cash if youve got the right skills, mindset, work ethic and some luck.

Generally, this is correct. You mentioned before that you're currently in medical school in your own country, so depending on what country you're from this could influence how easy or difficult your medical degree would transfer to America, but for the most part if you have the right skills (like a medical degree), mindset, work ethic, and a little bit of luck then you won't have too much of a problem getting by in America.

&gt; But also a place where the possibility of ending up bankrupt lurks around every corner. Every American seems like one major illness away from bankruptcy, the tendency of some Americans to sue can cost you millions (seriously, it's something most people i know can agree with and think such sums are ridiculous)

Generally if you have half-decent health insurance you won't go bankrupt trying to pay for any medical procedures, and if you can't afford health insurance you can probably qualify for medicaid which acts as a safety net to prevent you from going bankrupt trying to pay for medical services. The six and seven figure healthcare bills you hear about from American generally aren't the actual amount that has to be paid. Also, if you plan on going into the medical field in America then you won't have any trouble affording health insurance in the first place.

The tendency for Americans to sue over anything is pretty overblown in my opinion. Yes you occasionally hear about petty lawsuits for lots of money, but the vast majority of people in America will never end up on either side of any of these lawsuits. Also, people who engage in lawsuits like this typically go after those who are rich, meaning that for you to find yourself on the wrong end of one of these frivolous lawsuits would most likely mean that you have become financially successful.

&gt; Loopholes that can screw you over and ridiculous ways you can get screwed over by and whatnot.

You're going to have to expand on this. What loopholes are you talking about?

&gt; Also comcast?

Hating on Comcast (or any major ISP besides Google for that matter) is a common circlejerk on reddit. Is Comcast the most customer-friendly business? No. Are they a reason why you should be afraid to move to the U.S.? No. This may be anecdotal but I have Comcast for my internet and cable. They're essentially the only option in my area for internet. My internet speeds are fine. I don't have any problems streaming HD videos, music, doing online gaming, downloading various types of files, etc. Is it perfect? No, but it shouldn't be a reason for you to not move to America.
</reply>
<reply id="cndd4ux" author="Hyperderpityderp">
Thank you for your view, sir! 

Yes what i mean with those loopholes are ways you can get robbed off your money.
Not too long ago i read [this](http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/2q9yb7/what_is_the_most_evil_thing_your_company_didis/cn46c6z) in an askreddit thread
some prescription saving plan that made elderly cancel their insurance and switch to a way worse plan, eventually for them not to be able to change back to their old insurance after realizing how bad their new plan really is.  
There are some more examples i would've liked to give but i can't remember them right now. I remember them being legally correct but really evil though. Stuff like this
</reply>
<reply id="cnddc7s" author="man2010">
Without you providing any specific examples it's pretty difficult to address any of these loopholes that you're talking about. That insurance thing sounds like a scam more than anything, and scams aren't unique to America at all.
</reply>
<reply id="cnddf0h" author="Hyperderpityderp">
&amp;#8710; ! You have changed my view! 
 Ok delta bot :).

So far my pay-grade was partially the reason why i wanted to move to America.
I used to think that lawsuits were pretty much thrown around all the time. It's comforting to
know that i probably won't face such things if i move. Its true that reddit makes people think that if comcast is the only provider that you're screwed but yes, i guess it's pretty overblown now i've read the alternatives to it.
Again, thank you for your view!
</reply>
</thread>
