<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r85br">
<title>CMV: Why America isnt a scary place to move to</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r85br/cmv_why_america_isnt_a_scary_place_to_move_to/</source>
<OP author="Hyperderpityderp">
As you can read im not an American. Ive been dreaming of starting a clinic in America in the future, or to work in a medical clinic when i finish medical school in my own country. However reddit has made me think that America seems like a really scary place to live. On the othrr hand all american people ive personally met seem happy and enjoy life. My view of America is that it is a place where you can stack mad cash if youve got the right skills, mindset, work ethic and some luck. But also a place where the possibility of ending up bankrupt lurks around every corner. Every American seems like one major illness away from bankruptcy, the tendency of some Americans to sue can cost you millions (seriously, it's something most people i know can agree with and think such sums are ridiculous) Loopholes that can screw you over  and ridiculous ways you can get screwed over by and whatnot.~~Also comcast?~~ &lt;--(wasn't too serious about this)
tl:dr  America doesnt offer the life security i enjoy in my own country, and the thought of it really scares me.

EDIT: I live in the Netherlands. Sorry, forgot that that was quite relevent to the question.
Now i've come to think about it, the way i like my government right now is more socialistic. I like my 'free' healthcare and strict regulations for my own safety.

EDIT2: Apperently my view was heavily biased by the way the media completely exagerates or emphasised on certain parts of the story which can be very misleading. Thank you all for your views, and the ones that adressed my points have been awarded a delta. Thank you all!
</OP>
<reply id="cndczym" author="Tuokaerf10">
Americans like to complain about their country, especially on Reddit. It's not perfect by any means, there are major positives in some Western European countries that the U.S. should try and emulate (such as healthcare). But as a whole, there's incredible opportunity and freedom to do as you please. 

Regarding healthcare, I pay $400 a month for great coverage for myself, wife, and 2 kids. If I didn't have the job I did, I could get fairly close to the same benefits for $480 a month through the new Obamacare exchange. While you probably got this for "free" from the government, you're likely to pay less in taxes in the U.S. so it somewhat probably equals out. If you can't afford healthcare, you'd probably qualify for public assistance for free care. 

As for being sued, you may encounter this if you open a business but that's what insurance is for and even then it's not common at all for a small business. As a private citizen, it'll never happen. The media and sites like Reddit blow up over edge cases as they're usually ridiculous. 

Also, keep in mind that the U.S. is huge. Values, culture, quality of living, etc. can vary wildly between states. Each state can largely choose their own path up until it conflicts with Federal laws or rules, so do some research into the social programs offered by the state you want to move to before doing so. 
</reply>
<reply id="cnddgyg" author="Hyperderpityderp">
Adressed everything. My view has changed towards yours.  &amp;#8710; !
</reply>
</thread>
