<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r7f0g">
<title>CMV: Colonel Quaritch from "Avatar" was right.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r7f0g/cmv_colonel_quaritch_from_avatar_was_right/</source>
<OP author="Curious_Miner">
Recently, I stumbled upon [this](http://i.imgur.com/MEgVf.jpg) after a discussion of Avatar with a friend. [ (Not from the movie, but from here) ](http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/posts.php?discussion=sa7rmohv1hmgymf4xdu8cait&amp;page=27#660) It summed up my feelings about the movie quite well. Throughout human history, conquerors with superior technology have succeeded over less capable and less innovative cultures. It's ruthless, yes, but the reality is conquered cultures were less capable than the victors. Therefor it is in the best interest of cultures to strive for innovation, invention, progress, technology, and science. Not only does this secure survivability, but also increases standard of living.

Colonel Quaritch, as well as the other miners, were there to extract resources which benefited this endeavor. They were striving to better their abilities through use of the metal under the tree the Na'vi inhabited. 

Arguably, Colonel Quaritch **COULD** have massacred the residents of Hometree. It was well within his ability and means. Instead, a chance to evacuate is given, and Quaritches forces **target Hometree itself, not the Na'vi** The fleet do not gun down the fleeing residents, nor do they pursue. Their goal was the resources under the tree, and not the extermination of the people.


Next, Quaritch ceases hostilities against the Na'vi until Jake assembles a massive force around the headquarters. Quaritch **COULD** have met them in battle, but instead what does he do? Tries to avoid direct bloodshed by taking out a cultural symbol, thus potentially avoiding loss of life among both Na'vi and Human. 


The culture of the Na'vi could have ended up like the Native Americans. Conquered, but preserved through merciful reservations granted by the victors. Instead they opted for resistance, and I'm interested to see what the sequel holds for them. In the mean time, I feel Colonel Quaritch's actions were rational, reasonable, justifiable, and the correct course of action. My friend disagreed, and I'm more than open for discussion to better understand the opposing view.
_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnd8t6p" author="Inelukie">
The sole reason why I disliked Quaritchs side was because he is dumb as a brick. A true meathead, leading a multi-billion expedition? How could that fail?...

The whole point of this undertaking was not to subjugate the Na'vi. They were supposed to generate profits. Losing your whole operation is pretty bad for your profits. Large operations like this are risk averse for a reason. Fighting is a risk you don't have to take. While these minerals were deemed worthy of exploitions, I can not imagine any company in our world who would not spend money to find other stuff to sell from that world. In this case, the Hometree or whatever it was had the capabilities to "store" "souls". Now ask yourself: If you had the choice between cool rocks which make your fancy chair fly or true immortality: What do you think is worth more money?

For me this whole story was about arrogance, ignorance and greed. They had the chance to earn so much more money, to mutually benefit from this encounter. Instead they played their simple-minded scheme and lost.

If you want to be the strong and awesome conquerer, you shouldn't be so dumb about it, you actually lose. That's pretty damn embarassing.
</reply>
<reply id="cnd8y1g" author="Curious_Miner">
∆

&gt; In this case, the Hometree or whatever it was had the capabilities to "store" "souls". Now ask yourself: If you had the choice between cool rocks which make your fancy chair fly or true immortality: What do you think is worth more money?

I... I confess, that did not occur to me either. Yes, that capability would be MOST beneficial. In this regard, yes, Colonel Quaritch ALSO failed to acknowledge this capability and the benefit Humanity could derive from it.
</reply>
</thread>
