<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r6fw9">
<title>CMV: Food is close to inedible when the expiration date printed on the container is near, within a couple of days.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r6fw9/cmv_food_is_close_to_inedible_when_the_expiration/</source>
<OP author="BUDDZILLA">
Right now, I have a carton of egg nog with an date on it that says "01/05/15". If the date today is 01/03/15, I feel that given the date on the container that the egg nog within is near a point where you should no longer ingest it. It is my opinion that since the contents of the container are near expiration, that the "decomposition" process has begun and should be thrown out.

"Sell by" dates only offer me more uncertainty as to when I should stop ingesting the contents.

**TL/DR: Expiration dates are times when the contents of a container are spoiled. So, I think you should throw them out prior to this date. Additionally, "sell by" dates are worse because you have no idea when the contents will expire.**

Edit: My V has been C'd. The dates don't mean even close to what I thought they did, and I could just use some common sense instead of some ink printing on a container. Thanks to all who responded. 
_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnczhfc" author="nosecohn">
In almost all cases, the dates aren't related to food safety.

The US Department of Agriculture has [a guide to the different dating terminology](http://www.fsis.usda.gov/wps/wcm/connect/19013cb7-8a4d-474c-8bd7-bda76b9defb3/Food_Product_Dating.pdf?MOD=AJPERES) that includes this:

&gt; “Use-by” dates usually refer to best quality and are not safety dates. Even if the date expires during home storage, a product should be safe, wholesome and of good quality if handled properly.

[WebMD has a guide](http://www.webmd.com/a-to-z-guides/features/do-food-expiration-dates-matter?page=2) for how long after the printed date it's generally safe to eat certain food.

The US Food and Drug Administration [specifically allows](http://www.fda.gov/aboutfda/transparency/basics/ucm210073.htm) food to be stored and sold past any date printed on the package because:

&gt;  A product that is dangerous to consumers would be subject to potential action by FDA to remove it from commerce regardless of any date printed on a label.

So, yeah... you have a misconception. But don't feel bad. It's a common one. The NRDC and the Harvard Food Law and Policy Clinic published [a report on the matter:](http://www.nrdc.org/food/files/dating-game-IB.pdf)

&gt; The current system of expiration dates misleads consumers to believe they must discard food in order to protect their own safety. In fact, the dates are only suggestions by the manufacturer for when the food is at its peak quality, not when it is unsafe to eat.

And Time magazine published [an article that expands on the report.](http://healthland.time.com/2013/09/18/is-your-food-expired-dont-be-so-quick-to-toss-it/)

&gt; Most consumers mistakenly believe that expiration dates on food indicate how safe the food is to consume, when these dates actually aren’t related to the risk of food poisoning or foodborne illness.
</reply>
<reply id="cnd9lcc" author="BUDDZILLA">
&amp;#8710;

Thank you. I knew my view was a little irrational.. But this throws a wrench into some particular thoughts I had that I didn't detail in my post. Thanks a lot fella. 
</reply>
</thread>
