<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r6fw9">
<title>CMV: Food is close to inedible when the expiration date printed on the container is near, within a couple of days.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r6fw9/cmv_food_is_close_to_inedible_when_the_expiration/</source>
<OP author="BUDDZILLA">
Right now, I have a carton of egg nog with an date on it that says "01/05/15". If the date today is 01/03/15, I feel that given the date on the container that the egg nog within is near a point where you should no longer ingest it. It is my opinion that since the contents of the container are near expiration, that the "decomposition" process has begun and should be thrown out.

"Sell by" dates only offer me more uncertainty as to when I should stop ingesting the contents.

**TL/DR: Expiration dates are times when the contents of a container are spoiled. So, I think you should throw them out prior to this date. Additionally, "sell by" dates are worse because you have no idea when the contents will expire.**

Edit: My V has been C'd. The dates don't mean even close to what I thought they did, and I could just use some common sense instead of some ink printing on a container. Thanks to all who responded. 
_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cncxsps" author="hyperbolical">
The expiration date already has the number fudging you're worried about built in. 

It's more like the day that the "decomposition" process begins, not the culmination.
</reply>
<reply id="cncxtml" author="BUDDZILLA">
How do you know this?
</reply>
<reply id="cncxxk2" author="hyperbolical">
http://www.fsis.usda.gov/wps/portal/fsis/topics/food-safety-education/get-answers/food-safety-fact-sheets/food-labeling/food-product-dating/food-product-dating

Additionally, it's common sense with many products, such as milk. When milk spoils, there is a rather extreme taste and smell difference that would be hard to miss. 
</reply>
<reply id="cnd9pxa" author="BUDDZILLA">
&amp;#8710;

Thanks for your response. I am unfortunately dcursed with the absolute weakest sense of smell one could have. So other than seeing chunky milk, all I can do is taste it.. Which is not a good way to start the day ha. Even so, I had let my rampant nonsense take over my common sense- no pun intended- and your comment sort of threw me back to something simpler. So thank you again.  
</reply>
</thread>
