<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r6a86">
<title>CMV: Playing Smash Bros. with items turned off is lame.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r6a86/cmv_playing_smash_bros_with_items_turned_off_is/</source>
<OP author="throwaway4evil">
It's standard in the competitive Smash Bros. community to only play the game with items off. This is idiotic for a multitude of reasons.

**1. It makes the game less fun.**

Would you want to play Mario Kart without items? Fuck no. That removes all of the excitement and variation in the game. Same applies to Smash.

Sure enough, there was a post in r/nintendo or r/wiiu last week asking if there could be a competitive Mario Kart scene and most of the responses were "not unless they remove items". But then what's the point? Where's the fun? Just play another goddamn racing game if you want to play Mario Kart without items and just play another goddamn fighting game if you want to play Smash Bros. without items.

EDIT: This part of my view has been changed.

**2. It's restricting the intended purpose of the game.**

Why would you remove features from the game that are meant to be used? You're taking the game and making it into something it's not. It's like deliberately ordering a supreme pizza and picking off all the ingredients. Fucking pointless and borderline disrespectful to the developers (I'll admit this last part is a bit dubious, but, well...they did work to put it in the game as a main function of the game and it makes up a good portion of their creative output. It's kinda lame to just ignore that aspect of it).

EDIT: This part of my view has also been changed.

**3. Not only do items not hinder the competitive aspect of the game; they add to it, making their restriction the hindrance.**

This is the big one. This is why competitive Smash players leave items off in the first place: Because "the random aspect makes the game less competitive". Um...how? I mean, I guess the justification is that the randomness of item types and placement reduces the focus on the players' abilities, but to that I say two things:

**3A. No, it doesn't remove focus on players' abilities.**

Do you not even consider that, y'know, the person who gets the item still has to use it *correctly*? And you can still dodge it? And, assuming the item doesn't spawn right next to a player, you still have to make the dash to the item before someone else ***OR*** decide not to go for it at all. This is where the game becomes *more* competitive with the use of items. You have to actually take them into account. I imagine a common argument against items is something like "oh well you suck if you can only win with items on." Have you considered that maybe *you* suck because you can't win without them turned off?

I guess what I'm saying here is that while items add a slight element of chance, they more than make up for it with a multiple separate aspects of player skill.

**3B. Even if there is a random aspect to the game...so what?**

It's not as though it's a coin toss or a lottery where it's based entirely on luck. It's just the kinds of items and where they're placed. The addition of luck is part of the fun *and* part of the challenge.

Luck and competition are not mutually exclusive. Even with items turned off. It's not even possible for them to be. There's always going to be the possibility of an otherwise champion player making a stupid, fatal fuckup, or a glitch in the game causing an otherwise unwarranted victory. I understand wanting to reduce that element of chance, but removing items does so to the point that the fun in the competition is lost.

At the very least, there should be separate, mainstream Smash tournaments that keep items on.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cncx9n7" author="coastermaniac">
&gt; It makes the game less fun

That is strickly personnal opinion

&gt; It's restricting the intended purpose of the game.

If they give you the option of removing items it doesn't change the purpose of the game.

&gt; Not only do items not hinder the competitive aspect of the game; they add to it, making their restriction the hindrance.

I'm sorry but adding elements players have NO CONTROL ON makes the game extremely unfair in the case of competitive play.

&gt; No, it doesn't remove focus on players' abilities.

You are right that some items require skill to use but most of them give a big advantage to the player (trophys, pokeball, smash ball)

&gt; Even if there is a random aspect to the game...so what?

The whole point of a competition is to match skill on an even playing field.  This is why you see most matches played on FD with no items because it is pure skills involved.

Say a player practiced for months for a tournament, is better than the opposing player and a smash ball or a pokeball happens to spawn near the losing player giving him a HUGE advantage as the other player has to deal with 2 ennemies/an unavoidable attack making him lose.

Now do you think the guy who was lucky enough to have the item spawn near him is a better PLAYER than the other one ? 

You need to see smash as both a competitive and party game.

I do both, smash with 3 other guys, random characters, maps and full items is super fun casual smash.

But when I want to test my skills (which to me is also super fun) with friends it's 1v1 no items on maps with no interferance.
</reply>
<reply id="cncy9hn" author="throwaway4evil">
&gt;That is strickly personnal opinion

It is, but I'd tried to elaborate upon it.

&gt;If they give you the option of removing items it doesn't change the purpose of the game.

I'm mostly with you on this one, but kind of not. The game *was* built to be played with items on, but the fact that items can be turned off does imply that the developers made it that way specifically for people who want to play it with them off. ∆

&gt;I'm sorry but adding elements players have NO CONTROL ON makes the game extremely unfair in the case of competitive play.

They do have control over them. The player with the item has to use it properly. Everyone else has to dodge it.

&gt;trophys

Dodge the trophies.

&gt;pokeball

Dodge the Pokemon.

&gt;smash ball

Get to the Smash Ball first.

&gt;Say a player practiced for months for a tournament, is better than the opposing player and a smash ball or a pokeball happens to spawn near the losing player giving him a HUGE advantage as the other player has to deal with 2 ennemies/an unavoidable attack making him lose.

Too bad for him. Should've gotten to the Smash Ball first or dodged the Pokemon.

&gt;You need to see smash as both a competitive and party game.

I do. I just don't necessarily see playing it with items on as strictly "party" and non-competitive.
</reply>
</thread>
