<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r6a86">
<title>CMV: Playing Smash Bros. with items turned off is lame.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r6a86/cmv_playing_smash_bros_with_items_turned_off_is/</source>
<OP author="throwaway4evil">
It's standard in the competitive Smash Bros. community to only play the game with items off. This is idiotic for a multitude of reasons.

**1. It makes the game less fun.**

Would you want to play Mario Kart without items? Fuck no. That removes all of the excitement and variation in the game. Same applies to Smash.

Sure enough, there was a post in r/nintendo or r/wiiu last week asking if there could be a competitive Mario Kart scene and most of the responses were "not unless they remove items". But then what's the point? Where's the fun? Just play another goddamn racing game if you want to play Mario Kart without items and just play another goddamn fighting game if you want to play Smash Bros. without items.

EDIT: This part of my view has been changed.

**2. It's restricting the intended purpose of the game.**

Why would you remove features from the game that are meant to be used? You're taking the game and making it into something it's not. It's like deliberately ordering a supreme pizza and picking off all the ingredients. Fucking pointless and borderline disrespectful to the developers (I'll admit this last part is a bit dubious, but, well...they did work to put it in the game as a main function of the game and it makes up a good portion of their creative output. It's kinda lame to just ignore that aspect of it).

EDIT: This part of my view has also been changed.

**3. Not only do items not hinder the competitive aspect of the game; they add to it, making their restriction the hindrance.**

This is the big one. This is why competitive Smash players leave items off in the first place: Because "the random aspect makes the game less competitive". Um...how? I mean, I guess the justification is that the randomness of item types and placement reduces the focus on the players' abilities, but to that I say two things:

**3A. No, it doesn't remove focus on players' abilities.**

Do you not even consider that, y'know, the person who gets the item still has to use it *correctly*? And you can still dodge it? And, assuming the item doesn't spawn right next to a player, you still have to make the dash to the item before someone else ***OR*** decide not to go for it at all. This is where the game becomes *more* competitive with the use of items. You have to actually take them into account. I imagine a common argument against items is something like "oh well you suck if you can only win with items on." Have you considered that maybe *you* suck because you can't win without them turned off?

I guess what I'm saying here is that while items add a slight element of chance, they more than make up for it with a multiple separate aspects of player skill.

**3B. Even if there is a random aspect to the game...so what?**

It's not as though it's a coin toss or a lottery where it's based entirely on luck. It's just the kinds of items and where they're placed. The addition of luck is part of the fun *and* part of the challenge.

Luck and competition are not mutually exclusive. Even with items turned off. It's not even possible for them to be. There's always going to be the possibility of an otherwise champion player making a stupid, fatal fuckup, or a glitch in the game causing an otherwise unwarranted victory. I understand wanting to reduce that element of chance, but removing items does so to the point that the fun in the competition is lost.

At the very least, there should be separate, mainstream Smash tournaments that keep items on.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cncz7ep" author="FlowDeluxe">
In a practical sense, items would lead to a lot of disappointment in the outcome of competitive matches. Imagine how it would feel to see a  player with better skills lose just because their opponent got a pokeball with Kyogre in it. Or they got the hammer. Or the invincibility star. Or any of the other items that introduce an unfair advantage. 

I agree that items can make the game more fun, especially if the people playing all have different skill levels (I personally think that playing with no items against an opponent with a similar skill level is extremely fun). But, people don't always play games and sports at a competitive level because they are having fun. They do it because it’s a thing they're good at that they can get paid for. The fun is a nice bonus. 

I think a key thing to realize here is that fun probably isn't the reason the majority of people play competitive matches. Whenever you do something competitively, you want that thing to have as little luck involved as possible. That's why the only gambling games done professionally / competitively are the ones where the players have the ability to apply some strategy (there are professional poker and blackjack players, but not professional roulette players or slot machine players). Smash with items off is something you can practice at, discover what is predictable, develop a strategy, and prepare for a competition. Smash with items on is a crapshoot. No one in their right mind will enter a competition they are one lucky-for-your-opponent Palkia pokeball away from losing. The only way I could even entertain your argument is if in competitive play only some small subset of the items were allowed (just the dragoon and the blaster could be interesting). But the more items that are used increases, the more the unpredictability of what can happen in any given match also increases and in a game with 49 players, there is a tipping point. Even if there is skill involved in using certain items, many of them introduce too much of an imbalance for a competitive player to be comfortable with, especially if there is money involved.

As far as people not using the game the way it is intended, I don't know what to tell you. This is kind of just how humanity progresses. The inventor of basketball did not have it's current NBA incarnation in mind. And Henry Ford did not have the Ford Focus in mind when he designed the Model T, but aren't we all glad people changed things along the way so that we have what we have now? An inventor can create something, but once they give it to the world, it belongs to the people. They can play Smash whichever way they want.
</reply>
<reply id="cnczavd" author="throwaway4evil">
&gt; Imagine how it would feel to see a player with better skills lose just because their opponent got a pokeball with Kyogre in it. Or they got the hammer. Or the invincibility star. Or any of the other items that introduce an unfair advantage.

If they really had better skills they could've dodged the hammer or the invincible player...

&gt;I think a key thing to realize here is that fun probably isn't the reason the majority of people play competitive matches. Whenever you do something competitively, you want that thing to have as little luck involved as possible. That's why the only gambling games done professionally / competitively are the ones where the players have the ability to apply some strategy (there are professional poker and blackjack players, but not professional roulette players or slot machine players).

Yeah that makes sense to me. But then you say

&gt;Smash with items on is a crapshoot.

So what you're meaning to say is that Smash with items on is more comparable to a roulette wheel or slot machines than to poker or blackjack? That sounds kinda bogus to me...

&gt;As far as people not using the game the way it is intended, I don't know what to tell you. This is kind of just how humanity progresses. The inventor of basketball did not have it's current NBA incarnation in mind. And Henry Ford did not have the Ford Focus in mind when he designed the Model T, but aren't we all glad people changed things along the way so that we have what we have now? An inventor can create something, but once they give it to the world, it belongs to the people. They can play Smash whichever way they want.

True. ∆
</reply>
</thread>
