<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r6a86">
<title>CMV: Playing Smash Bros. with items turned off is lame.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r6a86/cmv_playing_smash_bros_with_items_turned_off_is/</source>
<OP author="throwaway4evil">
It's standard in the competitive Smash Bros. community to only play the game with items off. This is idiotic for a multitude of reasons.

**1. It makes the game less fun.**

Would you want to play Mario Kart without items? Fuck no. That removes all of the excitement and variation in the game. Same applies to Smash.

Sure enough, there was a post in r/nintendo or r/wiiu last week asking if there could be a competitive Mario Kart scene and most of the responses were "not unless they remove items". But then what's the point? Where's the fun? Just play another goddamn racing game if you want to play Mario Kart without items and just play another goddamn fighting game if you want to play Smash Bros. without items.

EDIT: This part of my view has been changed.

**2. It's restricting the intended purpose of the game.**

Why would you remove features from the game that are meant to be used? You're taking the game and making it into something it's not. It's like deliberately ordering a supreme pizza and picking off all the ingredients. Fucking pointless and borderline disrespectful to the developers (I'll admit this last part is a bit dubious, but, well...they did work to put it in the game as a main function of the game and it makes up a good portion of their creative output. It's kinda lame to just ignore that aspect of it).

EDIT: This part of my view has also been changed.

**3. Not only do items not hinder the competitive aspect of the game; they add to it, making their restriction the hindrance.**

This is the big one. This is why competitive Smash players leave items off in the first place: Because "the random aspect makes the game less competitive". Um...how? I mean, I guess the justification is that the randomness of item types and placement reduces the focus on the players' abilities, but to that I say two things:

**3A. No, it doesn't remove focus on players' abilities.**

Do you not even consider that, y'know, the person who gets the item still has to use it *correctly*? And you can still dodge it? And, assuming the item doesn't spawn right next to a player, you still have to make the dash to the item before someone else ***OR*** decide not to go for it at all. This is where the game becomes *more* competitive with the use of items. You have to actually take them into account. I imagine a common argument against items is something like "oh well you suck if you can only win with items on." Have you considered that maybe *you* suck because you can't win without them turned off?

I guess what I'm saying here is that while items add a slight element of chance, they more than make up for it with a multiple separate aspects of player skill.

**3B. Even if there is a random aspect to the game...so what?**

It's not as though it's a coin toss or a lottery where it's based entirely on luck. It's just the kinds of items and where they're placed. The addition of luck is part of the fun *and* part of the challenge.

Luck and competition are not mutually exclusive. Even with items turned off. It's not even possible for them to be. There's always going to be the possibility of an otherwise champion player making a stupid, fatal fuckup, or a glitch in the game causing an otherwise unwarranted victory. I understand wanting to reduce that element of chance, but removing items does so to the point that the fun in the competition is lost.

At the very least, there should be separate, mainstream Smash tournaments that keep items on.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cncxf4c" author="Millea">
&gt;It makes the game less fun.

Fun is 100% subjective. You may like it more with items, and that's fine.

&gt;Just play another goddamn racing game if you want to play Mario Kart without items and just play another goddamn fighting game if you want to play Smash Bros. without items.

What if they like the other mechanics? Items aren't 100% of the game, and aren't 100% of what distinguishes it from other games.

&gt;It's restricting the intended purpose of the game.

What's the intended purpose of the game? Well, it's a versatile game that applies to a very, very wide audience. Some people prefer some things and some people prefer other things. If I play a game, I want to maximize the amount of fun I have while doing it. Some people think items add to the fun, like you, and others think that they remove the fun.

&gt;3. Not only do items not hinder the competitive aspect of the game; they add to it, making their restriction the hindrance.

Would you say that olympic racewalking is inherently more competitive than olympic running?  Restrictions don't make it any more or less competitive.

&gt;Do you not even consider that, y'know, the person who gets the item still has to use it correctly?

Going into specific examples, let's say an item spawns next to Player A that let's them, if used correctly, knock out Player B. Player A will need to skillfully use this item to knock out Player B, correct?

Now, let's say that the game has been even until then, and both people have 1 life left. Whoever is better will win.  However, Player A gets an item that will let them, with the right timing, knock out Player B. 

Player A also has the option to pretend the item doesn't exist and play normally.

Therefore, Player A arbitrarily gets 1 extra option compared to Player B, and a higher chance of success. 

Now of course, this is a hypothetical situation, but you can probably see how this can apply to a regular game. 

&gt;No, it doesn't remove focus on players' abilities.

It can add interest. However, in a normal game, 100% of focus is on players' actions. Everything that happens is an action by either Player A or Player B.  Adding items adds stuff that is done by neither Player A nor Player B, but instead done by the game.  

&gt;Even if there is a random aspect to the game...so what?

If you add a random element to a game, you'd better have a good reason. An arbitrary randomness is usually not good.  

What if every attack had a 1 in 100 chance of hitting twice as hard, for example? It would be balanced, it just would be there fore no reason.

&gt;There's always going to be the possibility of an otherwise champion player making a stupid, fatal fuckup,

That isn't random chance. That's a mistake the player makes. 

&gt;or a glitch in the game causing an otherwise unwarranted victory.

These are avoided at all costs. Sometimes games are even replayed if the glitch is severe enough.

&gt;At the very least, there should be separate, mainstream Smash tournaments that keep items on.

I think that that could be good. However, what determines mainstream? Whatever people want to play is mainstream, and there's not too much that can change what people want to play besides changing the game.
</reply>
<reply id="cncy58k" author="throwaway4evil">
&gt; What if they like the other mechanics? Items aren't 100% of the game, and aren't 100% of what distinguishes it from other games.

For Smash, I'll give you this one. The game is it's own game with its own very detailed mechanics, even if items are turned off. Mario Kart, on the other hand, doesn't really have much substance without items and I still feel like if you want to play a fighting game without items, you'd have a better time playing just about any other fighting game that is built with pure brawling in mind, but I guess this is purely subjective. ∆ 

&gt;Restrictions don't make it any more or less competitive.

...so are you agreeing with me here?

&gt;Therefore, Player A arbitrarily gets 1 extra option compared to Player B, and a higher chance of success. Now of course, this is a hypothetical situation, but you can probably 
see how this can apply to a regular game.

Yeah, and I see nothing wrong with this. Sometimes a player just gets lucky and it increases their chances a bit. It's not like Player A's chances of victory skyrocket to 100%. Player B has to assess their situation and act accordingly to avoid losing.

I mean, does competitive Scrabble not work because the tiles are given at random? No. You have to make due with what you've got.

&gt;It can add interest. However, in a normal game, 100% of focus is on players' actions. Everything that happens is an action by either Player A or Player B. Adding items adds stuff that is done by neither Player A nor Player B, but instead done by the game.

This is valid, but part of the idea is for those players to act based on what's done by the game.

I guess it's like adding in a third party to the mix. Kinda like a DM, only it's a computer.

&gt;If you add a random element to a game, you'd better have a good reason. An arbitrary randomness is usually not good.

Makes the game more exciting. Changes the odds in a game that still requires skill.

&gt;That isn't random chance. That's a mistake the player makes.

A mistake that was totally unanticipated by the other player. They got lucky. I suppose it's different in that it's not random luck generated by the computer, but it's still an element of luck.

&gt;I think that that could be good. However, what determines mainstream? Whatever people want to play is mainstream, and there's not too much that can change what people want to play besides changing the game.

True true.
</reply>
</thread>
