<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r5o9o">
<title>CMV: The term "steep learning curve" is used incorrectly what people really mean is "shallow learning curve"</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r5o9o/cmv_the_term_steep_learning_curve_is_used/</source>
<OP author="applemonkeyman">
I forget where I first learned this but it has stuck with ever since and as person who deals with graphs and plots all the time (biochemist) it drives me nuts when ever I hear it.

The term "learning curve" has been used in science since the early 1900s (according to [wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Learning_curve)).  The term was used to plot a persons learning over their experience (see example [here](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Alanf777_Lcd_fig02.png)).  The example here shows how a person rapidly gains proficiency (or learning) and eventually levels off.  This could be a representations of how a person learns some thing easy, like tic-tac-toe.  Note here that the curve is quite steep, ie the slope is very large (a large change in y over a small change in y).  [Here](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Alanf777_Lcd_fig08.png) is a comparison between a steep (in red) and a shallow (in blue) curve.  The shallow curve means that proficiency (or learning) is gained more slowly over time compared to the steep curve.

Now words are often used differently in science and in common parlance, theory is a good example.  In common parlance theory means a guess, whereas in science theory means a body of knowledge including all known facts, hypotheses, and natural laws relevant to a particular field of study or  a proposed explanation of a set of related facts or a given phenomenon.  In general, when the term "steep learning curve" is used in common parlance it used to describe something difficult to learn.  Eg "The video game Dark Souls has a very steep learning curve".  What this sentence is meant to convey is that the game is hard to learn and master, which is clearly described by a shallow learning curve, not a steep one.

In conclusion saying "This game is hard, it has a steep learning curve" is equivalent to saying "I could care less" when what one meant was "I couldn't care less"
</OP>
<reply id="cncqhhb" author="ghostmcspiritwolf">
I want to comment specifically on the idea that an idiom can be used incorrectly. The purpose of language is effective communication. If a person expresses an idea and the people listening to that person understand it, then by what metric can we say that the language used was "incorrect?" If a friend were to ask me how difficult it is to learn a certain skill and I told her that there's a steep learning curve, she would understand what I mean: that it's difficult to begin to learn. If I said there was a *shallow* learning curve, she would likely either assume the opposite or simply be more confused.



My basic point here is this: the fact that language changes over time doesn't necessarily make newer linguistic constructions incorrect. Many words and phrases we now use daily and consider to be perfect English are "corrupted" or "bastardized" forms of older words or phrases. The only reason that these are considered more correct is the perception of their age.
</reply>
<reply id="cncqwxa" author="applemonkeyman">
Clearly the use of words can change, often time to mean the exact opposite, eg "bad" and "awesome".  However, my argument is more about the pedanticism of it all.  I make it a point in conversations to correct people on the use of the learning curves, doing my part (as small and insignificant as that is) to change the language back to the literal meaning of the word.  As an idiom perhaps nothing can be wrong, heres a ∆, but I will still fight the culture on it used.
</reply>
</thread>
