<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r5o9o">
<title>CMV: The term "steep learning curve" is used incorrectly what people really mean is "shallow learning curve"</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r5o9o/cmv_the_term_steep_learning_curve_is_used/</source>
<OP author="applemonkeyman">
I forget where I first learned this but it has stuck with ever since and as person who deals with graphs and plots all the time (biochemist) it drives me nuts when ever I hear it.

The term "learning curve" has been used in science since the early 1900s (according to [wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Learning_curve)).  The term was used to plot a persons learning over their experience (see example [here](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Alanf777_Lcd_fig02.png)).  The example here shows how a person rapidly gains proficiency (or learning) and eventually levels off.  This could be a representations of how a person learns some thing easy, like tic-tac-toe.  Note here that the curve is quite steep, ie the slope is very large (a large change in y over a small change in y).  [Here](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Alanf777_Lcd_fig08.png) is a comparison between a steep (in red) and a shallow (in blue) curve.  The shallow curve means that proficiency (or learning) is gained more slowly over time compared to the steep curve.

Now words are often used differently in science and in common parlance, theory is a good example.  In common parlance theory means a guess, whereas in science theory means a body of knowledge including all known facts, hypotheses, and natural laws relevant to a particular field of study or  a proposed explanation of a set of related facts or a given phenomenon.  In general, when the term "steep learning curve" is used in common parlance it used to describe something difficult to learn.  Eg "The video game Dark Souls has a very steep learning curve".  What this sentence is meant to convey is that the game is hard to learn and master, which is clearly described by a shallow learning curve, not a steep one.

In conclusion saying "This game is hard, it has a steep learning curve" is equivalent to saying "I could care less" when what one meant was "I couldn't care less"
</OP>
<reply id="cncp4k9" author="airdog1992">
In my experience, "steep learning curve", is used in the condition where a person has a lot to learn and very little time to do it.  In the movie, "The Devil Wears Prada", the protagonist is given two binders of faces and names and has to learn all of them in the space of one day in order to be of value at an event.  That is a "steep learning curve".  It's not a factor of the difficulty (necessarily), but rather the volume of information that has to be learned in the very short amount of time.
</reply>
<reply id="cncqjqk" author="applemonkeyman">
This may be case where the steep learning curve is appropriate, however it seems to me that it would be more correct to say that the person needs to have a steeper learning curve then the average person on order to get the job.  Other people could gain the same proficiency if given more time/experience.  If you compare the learning curves of two different activities, lets same checkers vs chess, then it is clear that the rate at which you gain proficiency is different, with checkers have the steeper curve.  In the case of the "The Devil Wears Prada" that secretarial job is clearly harder and more complex then other secretarial jobs and I would say it has a shallower learning curve in comparison
to other secretarial jobs.

Personally, I more almost exclusively hear the term steep learning curve in reference to some activities' difficulty or complexity, not the rate it need to be learned.  However I will grant you at least a partial ∆ for this corner case.
</reply>
</thread>
