<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r5o9o">
<title>CMV: The term "steep learning curve" is used incorrectly what people really mean is "shallow learning curve"</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r5o9o/cmv_the_term_steep_learning_curve_is_used/</source>
<OP author="applemonkeyman">
I forget where I first learned this but it has stuck with ever since and as person who deals with graphs and plots all the time (biochemist) it drives me nuts when ever I hear it.

The term "learning curve" has been used in science since the early 1900s (according to [wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Learning_curve)).  The term was used to plot a persons learning over their experience (see example [here](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Alanf777_Lcd_fig02.png)).  The example here shows how a person rapidly gains proficiency (or learning) and eventually levels off.  This could be a representations of how a person learns some thing easy, like tic-tac-toe.  Note here that the curve is quite steep, ie the slope is very large (a large change in y over a small change in y).  [Here](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Alanf777_Lcd_fig08.png) is a comparison between a steep (in red) and a shallow (in blue) curve.  The shallow curve means that proficiency (or learning) is gained more slowly over time compared to the steep curve.

Now words are often used differently in science and in common parlance, theory is a good example.  In common parlance theory means a guess, whereas in science theory means a body of knowledge including all known facts, hypotheses, and natural laws relevant to a particular field of study or  a proposed explanation of a set of related facts or a given phenomenon.  In general, when the term "steep learning curve" is used in common parlance it used to describe something difficult to learn.  Eg "The video game Dark Souls has a very steep learning curve".  What this sentence is meant to convey is that the game is hard to learn and master, which is clearly described by a shallow learning curve, not a steep one.

In conclusion saying "This game is hard, it has a steep learning curve" is equivalent to saying "I could care less" when what one meant was "I couldn't care less"
</OP>
<reply id="cncqcjt" author="elliptibang">
&gt;In conclusion saying "This game is hard, it has a steep learning curve" is equivalent to saying "I could care less" when what one meant was "I couldn't care less"

If the speaker is referring to a curve whose Y-axis represents the amount of learning that has to be done over a period of time measured by the X-axis, then "steep" is a perfectly sensible way to describe the shape of a curve associated with a task that is especially difficult for someone who is new to it. That may not be the curve you're imagining, but you haven't given us any reason to accept that *your* curve is the only one "correctly" described by the term "learning curve."

Similarly, it isn't at all obvious that the phrase "I could care less" is an *incorrect* way of expressing apathy. Nobody seems to have any problem with the fact that "I've been better" generally means something like "I'm not doing very well right now." What is it about "I could care less" that causes people to pick on it the way they do?
</reply>
<reply id="cncr89a" author="applemonkeyman">
This is the same argument as /u/airdog1992, who I agree with in this corner case, so heres ∆.  But I almost exclusively hear the term steep learning curve in reference to some activities' difficulty or complexity, not the rate it needs to be learned.

I think that the issue with "I could care less" as an expression of apathy is that apathy and empathy are dichotomous.  To say "I could not care less" is to have zero empathy, where as to say "I could care less" is to imply a small but non-zero amount of empathy.  Additionally it is generally used in a context, often a hyperbole, to express no empathy and when could is used rather than couldn't it is a clear case of a verbal typo.  Health on the other hand has more of a continuum . 
</reply>
</thread>
