<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r4u3k">
<title>CMV: Nobody who works in a cubicle or other job where you rarely interact with anyone other than your co-workers should have any dress code beyond "cover your naughty bits" and "don't wear offensive stuff"</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r4u3k/cmv_nobody_who_works_in_a_cubicle_or_other_job/</source>
<OP author="Mavericgamer">
To be clear: I'm talking about research/design/programming/IT/call center jobs, where you aren't in the public eye or aren't representing the company with your physical body. If you're going and making house calls as an IT guy then this doesn't apply.

Basically, I think that it's absurd to have a company tell you that only certain pieces of clothing are acceptable to wear to type on a keyboard or operate a phone. As long as the worker is getting their job done, how they dress should be completely irrelevant, so long as they aren't distracting or offending other people at the office.

To head off some arguments: I don't believe that wearing a collared shirt and pants that aren't jeans are representative that you "respect" the job any more than I believe that sweatpants and a t-shirt are signs that you disrespect the job.

What I think would change my view would be any sort of evidence that there's a benefit to having a workplace full of programmers or a call center always wearing slacks or skirts and nice tops.

EDIT: Something I forgot in OP, but should be mentioned: Clothing worn for safety is exempt from this. If a lab that works with noxious/dangerous chemicals requires goggles and gloves/aprons/whatever else, that is obviously justified. I'm specifically talking about dress codes in environments that aren't hazardous, and serve only to limit the wardrobe of the people in the office.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cncry40" author="beer_demon">
&gt; I think that it's absurd to have a company tell you that only certain pieces of clothing are acceptable to wear to type on a keyboard or operate a phone.  

An employer doesn't only have to monitor calls, tickets or code, but also behaviour, and clothing affects behaviour.  Sometimes clothing diversity can encourage conflicts or segment the workers into groups and this can reflect on atmosphere and this affects productivity directly.  For example where I work you have IT people of different backgrounds : classy, low class, metalheads, geeks, very socially awkward people, sexy girls and allsorts.  By having a minimum dress code you are leaving these differences outside to a point.  
Of course they don't all need semi formal wear, but at least sandals, shorts, short skirts and vests and heavy metal t shirts are not allowed.  
</reply>
<reply id="cnd85gu" author="Mavericgamer">
&gt;For example where I work you have IT people of different backgrounds : classy, low class, metalheads, geeks, very socially awkward people, sexy girls and allsorts. By having a minimum dress code you are leaving these differences outside to a point.

As much as this is anathema to my personal belief system, I can see why this would be both desirable for a diverse workforce and a decently explainable function of a dress code.  ∆
</reply>
</thread>
