<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r4b8f">
<title>CMV: A teenager can be just as intelligent as an adult (on certain topics) because age and experience don't equal intelligence.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r4b8f/cmv_a_teenager_can_be_just_as_intelligent_as_an/</source>
<OP author="Ravenman2423">
Okay so this is an argument I have all the time, being a teenager myself (17). usually what happens is I'll be discussing a topic with an adult (usually a family member or teacher), then we disagree, then they say something that infuriates me like "oh I thought the same thing when I was your age" or "you'll grow out of it." 
even online, there is this annoying stigma that all teens are idiots but at the same time think they know everything. 

sometimes, it makes sense. some subjects obviously require experience. Relationship advice, for example. I've never been in a relationship so if I were to try and give an adult, or anyone for that matter, relationship advice, it would make sense to tell me "you're too young"/"your opinion will change"/"you'll grow out of it". 

but when arguing about politics, religion, or any subject that really doesn't require experience to understand it better, saying something like "you're just a teen" or "I used to think like that" is an excuse and it usually means you have nothing more to say but aren't willing to "lose" this discussion to a stupid teen. 

 personally I'm, unsurprisingly, an atheist. I come from a semi-religious Jewish family. me and my dad have this argument ALL THE TIME. you know the one. and it almost always ends with me bringing up an extremely valid point and him laughing and saying "oh its just a phase. you're just a teen. you're so young. you have no idea." it fucking pisses me off. 

A teenager can argue about politics or religion just as well as a 25 year old can and just as well as a 50 year old can. it only depends on the person and how much they are willing to put into learning about the subject. 


_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnch3ur" author="Holypoopsticks">
Isn't your entire post based on your personal experience? If we take that away from your argument here, what do you really have left?

But seriously. Experience tends to have a tempering effect on information that can often be difficult to quantify. Just as you've arrived at your own point of view on experience (through your experience), events change the way we can view identical information. 

If someone researches loss for instance, it may be easy to develop an academic view of the subject, but that knowledge does not confer what the actual experience of loss is like, or how difficult it can be to deal with. In the same way that knowing how to lose weight doesn't often translate into success with losing weight.

The greatest benefit my own experience has conferred on me is a great awareness of what it's like to be wrong. I've been wrong about a lot. It has gradually made me less and less certain over the years and so I'm a lot less concerned than I once was about whether or not I'm right. It also tends to make me more open to being wrong, so if someone points out a flaw in my reasoning I'm quicker to give up my old point of view in favor of seeing things differently.

A study conducted by Richard West at James Madison University found that contrary to what one might expect, people who scored very high on SATs or other standardized methods of evaluating cognitive or collegiate ability had a surprising vulnerability to certain kinds of test questions, such as:

A bat and ball cost a dollar and ten cents. The bat costs a dollar more than the ball. How much does the ball cost?

While our initial thought might be that the ball costs ten cents, this is actually incorrect. The correct answer is that the bat costs a dollar and five cents and that the ball costs five cents.

Intelligent people, Richard West found, were more prone to relying on heuristics (or mental short cuts) to solve problems and that this made them MORE likely than the average person to be vulnerable to certain cognitive biases.

In some instances, it is the very clarity with which we see that world that is our biggest barrier to seeing it accurately. This is where experience is most helpful. It's not just having the book knowledge that is important. It's having the relevant life experience that brings that knowledge into its full three dimensions.

As your own arguments have developed, you've become frustrated with the ability of others, who often may not argue well. This would likely not have developed had you not honed your own skills through direct experience. At your age you've likely not honed these skills as far as you will at some point either. In other words, as skilled as you feel at developing your arguments now, you'll be better in a year. Even better than that in two or three. You can't help it. You'll have a greater well to draw from then, just as you have a greater well to draw from now than you did a couple years ago.

All of this isn't in defense of those who dismiss your arguments out of hand as a result of their prejudice about your age. That's a failing on their part. But just because others aren't fair with you in terms of acknowledging the validity of your arguments on their face value doesn't mean that experience isn't a relevant factor in deepening understanding of all kinds of things. Knowing the depth of how wrong we can be, experiencing it personally and relevantly, does temper (rightly so) the convictions we hold deeply, and (applied well) lessens our hold on the truths we think we have a handle on.
</reply>
<reply id="cnchdrn" author="Ravenman2423">
this is easily the best comment here. you changed the way I look at the whole thing. wow. thank you. this is the kinda thing I was hoping for when I made this post. theres not much more to say. 
EDIT: forgot delta &amp;#8710;
</reply>
</thread>
