<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r3fa4">
<title>CMV: Attempting to convert people to your religion (or lack of) is a MORAL thing to do.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r3fa4/cmv_attempting_to_convert_people_to_your_religion/</source>
<OP author="PumpkinFeet">
The reasons for this are different depending on whether you are religious or not. I am intentionally not stating my own beliefs as it's not relevant (EDIT: actually it's pretty obvious!)

If you are religious, the chances are high that your religion only allows believers into heaven/paradise after our earthly lives end. Some may go even further and state that if you don't believe, not only will you not go to heaven, you will end up in hell. People who follow these religions have a moral duty to do all they can to help people get into heaven/avoid hell. If some otherwise decent guy is an atheist, doesn't he deserve to be converted so he can get into heaven? And as for hell,  no-one- not even Hitler- deserves an ETERNITY of torture. 

I admit that religious people who do not believe in hell or heaven have no moral obligation to try and convert people.

Atheists generally believe that their worldview leads to greater human happiness. A rough spectrum of examples of religion decreasing human happiness (from significantly decreasing to only a little): ISIS, Hamas v Isreal, sick children being prevented treatment due to religious parents, parents disowning a child for coming out as gay, spending Sunday at church instead of doing something more fun. Atheists therefore have a moral obligation to spread their viewpoint in order to make the world a better place. Atheists who insist on never trying to convert a religious person are doing the world a disservice- what if the person you didn't want to convert goes on to drive their own child to suicide because they said 'god doesnt make mistakes' regarding their child's transexuality?

Of course there are atheists who do NOT believe that atheism leads to greater human happiness. Again, I admit that these people have no moral obligation to convert people (from their point of view).

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnc4l6o" author="FaerieStories">
Essentially your argument is that our moral obligations stem entirely from our individual beliefs. Assuming you do not believe in hell (though maybe you do, I don't know) you are claiming that even though you don't believe this place exists, you think that someone who genuinely *does* believe such a place exists has the moral obligation to prevent people from being sent there - even though you would say that they are mistaken that there is such a place.

So my response to that is this: if someone *genuinely believed* that a deity had told them to kill another person (or multiple people) in order for both they and he to achieve salvation, would you argue that it is moral for them to do so? If your answer to that question is 'no', then doesn't this contradict your argument that people should act solely based on their own beliefs about what is or isn't right?
</reply>
<reply id="cnc4sis" author="PumpkinFeet">
My answer to that is 'yes'- it is moral *from their point of view*. I want to clarify here that I absolutely do not agree with moral relativism, their act is clearly not moral (in an absolute sense) but from their point of view it is.

However, I do admit that this is a confusing issue. Due to reasons outlined in my post I would never consider a christian a dick for trying to convert me- but I would consider them a dick for killing because God told them too. 

Ok Ive thought about it a bit more, and damnit you have me cornered. In an absolute sense, if it's immoral to kill in the name of God (which it is) then it follows that it's also immoral to convert people to religion, in an absolute sense. ∆

I think what I was trying to get at in my post is that it's the moral duty of atheists to convert religious folk, I just came at it from the wrong angle. What are your thoughts on that, out of interest?
</reply>
</thread>
