<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r39y4">
<title>CMV: Insults such as 'You're gay' are not an affront to gay people</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r39y4/cmv_insults_such_as_youre_gay_are_not_an_affront/</source>
<OP author="Rippsonite">
I've seen some discussion about this topic, where many kids and adults may call people something they aren't to try and insult them. For example: 'That's so gay' and 'You throw like a girl' type insults. Many people come to the conclusion that these type of insults are homophobic and misogynistic, but I don't believe that's necessarily the case at all.

I think the most insulting thing about being called a girl for a boy is the affront to his own identity. He is being called something he is not. He doesn't think its insulting because he hates girls and thinks they're inferior, but rather because his identity as a boy is being taken away.

Women in general also hate being associated with masculinity. They tend to want to be smaller than their partners because they feel masculine if they are taller. They religiously pluck facial hair and shave away body hair because that's manly. But they probably don't hate men.

Similarly, being called gay is a huge insult to many guys not because they are all homophobic, but because they are being called something they are not.

I think the best way to see it from my point of view is looking at how offensive it is for trans people when they are mis-gendered (Purposely). It is a deliberate refusal of their identity. No one says a trans woman is a misandrist if she hates being referred to as 'he'. The people calling them 'he' are also unlikely to hate men, but say it to hurt the trans person. 

So CMV, insults such as those above aren't necessarily homophobic or misogynist. They sting because they are an affront to identity more so than because being gay or a woman is a bad thing.

_____


</OP>
<reply id="cnc1vs2" author="blackflag415">
Calling someone gay is homophobic because you are associating them with the stereotypical traits of gay people - effeminate, etc.   It has nothing to do with being called something you are not.  

For example, I am Jewish.  Yet I would still be offended if someone said 'You're cheap like a Jew' or 'You Jew'ed down the price.'  Despite them calling me something I am - Jewish - they are associating me with highly prejudiced stereotypes.   

&gt;Women in general also hate being associated with masculinity. They tend to want to be smaller than their partners because they feel masculine if they are taller. They religiously pluck facial hair and shave away body hair because that's manly. But they probably don't hate men.

Pretty big generalizations about billions of people.  
</reply>
<reply id="cnc20er" author="Rippsonite">
I don't think its homophobic to associate people with the stereotypes though, because when you want to insult someone, the quickest way to portray that someone is acting effeminate etc is to call them gay. Everyone knows that while all gay people don't behave a certain way, there certainly is a clear mainstream way gay people are portrayed. Its not an insult to gay people so. 

When you get offended by 'You're cheap like a Jew' the negative aspects of 'cheap' are what offend you, not the Jew part right? You are insulted by the negative stereotypes more so than being called a Jew. Why be offended about being called a Jew?

I'm quite sure the generalizations about women wanting taller partners is very true. The facial hair one is not as rooted in fact, I'll give you that. I still think it makes sense though.
</reply>
<reply id="cnc25wa" author="blackflag415">
Please choose one:

&gt;Its not an insult to gay people so. 

&gt;because when you want to insult someone, the quickest way to portray that someone is acting effeminate etc is to call them gay.

For you say it's not an insult, then you say it is.  I'm confused.  If you are using someone's identity as an insult how is that not offensive to them?

&gt;there certainly is a clear mainstream way gay people are portrayed. Its not an insult to gay people so. 

The way the mainstream portrays groups is always true?  You think minstrel shows accurately portrayed black people? 

&gt;When you get offended by 'You're cheap like a Jew' the negative aspects of 'cheap' are what offend you, not the Jew part right? You are insulted by the negative stereotypes more so than being called a Jew. Why be offended about being called a Jew?

I'm offended because stereotypes about Jews being cheap have been an excuse to persecute, discriminate against, and kill Jews since the middle ages.  

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stereotypes_of_Jews#Greed

&gt;I'm quite sure the generalizations about women wanting taller partners is very true. The facial hair one is not as rooted in fact, I'll give you that. I still think it makes sense though.

Where I live, Japan, it is quite common for men to shave body hair and pluck eyebrows.  Japan is a society of 130 million people and the third largest economy in the world, not some obscure tribe in the Amazon.  What's true for you is not true for all people and it is illogical to assume so.  
</reply>
<reply id="cnc2cc6" author="Rippsonite">
&gt;  If you are using someone's identity as an insult how is that not offensive to them?

When you put it that way, it does seem very insulting. I can understand how it can be an affront to gay people. &amp;#8710;

</reply>
</thread>
