<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r1omi">
<title>CMV: I don't think anyone should have to pay child support. Ever.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r1omi/cmv_i_dont_think_anyone_should_have_to_pay_child/</source>
<OP author="TheEmptyVessel">
My logic basically stems from the idea of "If you can't afford to have child, you can't have a child." Let me explain.

In my opinion, if one parent wants to keep the child and the other doesn't, then unless they can be proven unfit for parenting -this includes financial instability- then good for them, go for it. The only time I could see child support being necessary is if they parent needs the extra money to support their child(ren). But I'm sorry, you can't have a child if you can't support it and you sure as hell can't take the money from someone else regardless of their involvement in the child's creation. 

Obviously it's a different story if they are splitting custody, then an arrangement should be made about how the money should be split.

If only the mother wants the child then she can have it and raise it by herself or with whomever she wants.

If only the father wants the child then it's up to the mother if she wants to have it and the forfeit custody to him after birth. If she does then it's the father's responsibility alone. No strings attached.

I realize that it's to stop guys from knocking up women and then running off and leaving her to raise it but she can just get an abortion if she can't raise it. Or put it up for adoption/ find a willing guardian (ex.: friend, parent etc.) if she doesn't want to do that. Not to mention the fact that both of them should have taken precautions to avoid pregnancy beforehand, though I admit nothing's fool proof.

Anyway, I haven't been thinking about this very long so I could be completely missing something so CMV.

Edit: Whoa this is controversial. Thanks everyone for commenting.
A few people pointed out that if the parents are already together and one tries to walk out they should still have to pay. Yes, I agree because there was an understanding that both would provide for the kid. I'm talking about right after the pregnancy or even right after birth. If one person wants to keep it and the other doesn't, that's their decision and they need to pay for it.

Edit: 2

Mkay. View changed thnx guis. &amp;#8710;. No but I guess it makes sense to hold both parties accountable if they understood the risks in the first place, which everybody does. I'm not entirely comfortable with the idea, but they sort of agreed to the risks when they consented.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnby5pl" author="tricerabear">
1) It is not possible to perfectly predict whether you can "afford to support a child," as people lose their jobs, unexpected expenses arise, and life is generally messy. 60% of bankruptcies are precipitated by medical expenses. The "don't have a child if you can't afford it" line is just ignorant. The welfare queen is a myth, and poor people know it's expensive to have children and generally are trying to avoid having them, hampered by ignorance and lack of access/education about birth control. 
2) "Just get an abortion" is a totally unreasonable thing to say. Having a living thing inside of you changes the calculation, and people seem to get attached to it. While at time A, before you are pregnant, you would  choose not to become pregnant, at time B once you are pregnant you may strongly desire to keep the child rather than have an abortion or putting it up for adoption.

 If you insist on looking at it as strictly contractual, you could say that both partners accept the risk of having to support a child when they consented to sex. They both knew conception was a risk, and are aware that many people who get pregnant decide to keep it. They are both responsible for bringing it in to the world.
</reply>
<reply id="cnbyy1j" author="TheEmptyVessel">
&gt;1)

I know we can't perfectly quantify that, I meant more of a "Is there any reason to believe this person cannot to raise the child" Examples could be being homeless, a history of child abuse etc. something obvious.

&gt;2)

I'm sure people do get more attached and it probably changes things in a way I will never understand. However, how someone feels about their child and how much they want to be with them shouldn't be put before the child's well being. If you can't afford it, you can't afford it. If welfare, tax breaks and things like that -which are great- don't cut then I don't see a way around that.

&gt;If you insist on looking at it as strictly contractual...

I do (sorry). Ok. I know a lot of people have said this but your argument was really well structured and I liked the way you explained it. I'm still very uncomfortable with the idea of "every time you have sex you accept the risks that could end in paying for a child" but I guess it makes sense. I suppose if everyone understands that then they can be held accountable. While I haven't pulled a 180 you've really nullified my view. Thanks.

&amp;#8710;
</reply>
</thread>
