<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r17g1">
<title>CMV: If you pay a flat fee for Internet, it is a nice and acceptable thing to leave an unsecured WiFi network for neighbors and travelers.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r17g1/cmv_if_you_pay_a_flat_fee_for_internet_it_is_a/</source>
<OP author="selfhatingyank">
Many times in my life, I have been helped out by a neighbor or business owner who left an unsecured or no-password WiFi network. I am aware that this practice is somewhat controversial due to hacking risks, but I have heard friends and neighbors say that if you aren't paying by the byte, there is no harm in allowing others to use your WiFi. Although there are horror stories about people being SWATted by those on their WiFi network, I don't think the risks of that are (statistically) much higher than many other technology risks, including using a guessable password (like 1234) or browsing the Internet on library or Starbucks WiFi. I'd prefer some statistics and would be more likely to award a delta for a statistically demonstrable argument.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnbjfmc" author="lostminty">
Well, it is your internet connection so you can do with it what you want. But being yours, you are responsible for it.

So, if you do not take preventative measures to mitigate risk of misuse then how can you not be held accountable?

There are easily analogies which could be used to demonstrate the need to be responsible for what one gives away for free.

An example of this in law is seen in Occupational health and safety regulations for laboratories.

eg, if someone broke into your lab to steal chemicals or what have you, and the exits were locked (as opposed to the entrances) then they could sue you.
</reply>
<reply id="cnbjid5" author="selfhatingyank">
Good analogy. I never thought of it that way in terms of the potential liability that it could bring up. Leaving my WiFi unprotected leaves me responsible for whoever uses it.

Have a ∆
</reply>
</thread>
