<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r0eyf">
<title>CMV: There is No Free Will</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r0eyf/cmv_there_is_no_free_will/</source>
<OP author="Microbrewlogic">
With our ever advancing knowledge of neuroscience and the chemistry involved with it, I do not see any place for the idea that any animal, including humans, is truly capable of making choices. We are capable of recognizing choices, that is obvious, but I'm not convinced that the chemical pathways for neurons leaves any room for decisions to be made other than the ones that are made.There is no more room in the chemical pathways for us to "choose" to do anything any more than there is for bacteria or plants to do the same.

Chemistry behaves the way it does regardless of what we want it to do, and our decisions are made by chemical controlled signaling between cells. Is there any room for our nerves to come to any other result than the one they do given that chemical pathways we have no control over are the primary factors in the decisions we make? I don't think so, but I'm open to changing my view!
</OP>
<reply id="cncjlq6" author="edgyasfuck">
Science has a long way before we can confidently conclude that the universe operates deterministically (i.e., there is only one physical outcome for a given action/event). As /u/PlexiglassPelican mentioned, the Consequence Argument (i.e., we do not have free will if there's an absence of genuine alternative possibilities, or the ability to do otherwise) is compelling, but it only holds water if determinism is proven true. 

Often invoked here are Frankfurt-type examples, which attribute moral responsibility to an agent given the presence of determinism. However, the problem with those is thinking you have made a free choice is different from actually making a free choice.

I believe we have free will, namely event-causal Libertarian free will (see: Robert Kane). This view is an incompatibilist view, meaning free will is *not* compatible with determinism. The crux of the debate lies in whether determinism is true. Until that's proven true or false, the debate will endlessly continue. I'm also surprised no one has mentioned moral responsibility, because that's an important factor in attributing freedom to a choice or action.
</reply>
<reply id="cncmzwy" author="Microbrewlogic">
∆ I agree, those are some extremely convincing points. Honestly, after thinking harder about this, I'm going to have to change it to "I don't know if free will exists, rather than thinking it doesn't exist"

You changed my view! :-D

Now how do I post a Delta on my tablet? Give me a moment here.
</reply>
</thread>
