<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r07cv">
<title>CMV: There is no sound biblical argument that makes being trans-gender morally wrong.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r07cv/cmv_there_is_no_sound_biblical_argument_that/</source>
<OP author="SobanSa">
I'm not some hippy liberal christian, I'm a serious southern baptist Sunday school teacher. I think that after examining the Bible, there is no argument that being transgender is wrong. Indeed, there are only three main prongs of attack, all of which are incorrect.

The first prong of attack is the homosexuality argument. However, if someone really is the opposite gender, then it would by definition not be homosexual.

The second prong of attack is the rule against cross dressing. However, if someone really is the opposite gender, it's not cross dressing.

The third prong of attack is against physical mutilation of the body. I think there are other things wrong with this argument. However, that someone is transgender does not imply that they will or have to 'mutilate' their body. They may be happier if they do, but being transgender does not entail it happening.

None of these imply that being transgender it's self is in any way wrong. It is always something else that commonly goes along with transgender issues that makes it wrong.

Edit: This argument depends upon a non-biological definition of gender. If gender is biological, then the attacks make a lot more sense. However, this raises the question, "Can we define gender as biological based on the Bible?" 
</OP>
<reply id="cnbg0pn" author="BlackHumor">
Before I start here, I want to say that I'm an atheist and my objective in arguing is to argue that the Bible is immoral on this point, not to say that being trans is really wrong.

At the end of Genesis 3 God curses all parties involved with eating the fruit of the forbidden tree. The curses of the snakes and men are not relevant here, but here's how he curses women:

&gt;16 To the woman he said, “I will make your pains in childbearing very severe;
    with painful labor you will give birth to children.
Your desire will be for your husband,
    and he will rule over you.”
</reply>
<reply id="cnbjdh0" author="SobanSa">
... and?
</reply>
<reply id="cnbjoop" author="BlackHumor">
He says pretty clearly that women bear children. His curse of women is biological in nature so he must be thinking of women as biological.
</reply>
<reply id="cnbk1da" author="SobanSa">
∆

That is a very good point I had not thought of. I'm not sure how it's going to develop, but that idea is a good point.
</reply>
</thread>
