<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r07cv">
<title>CMV: There is no sound biblical argument that makes being trans-gender morally wrong.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r07cv/cmv_there_is_no_sound_biblical_argument_that/</source>
<OP author="SobanSa">
I'm not some hippy liberal christian, I'm a serious southern baptist Sunday school teacher. I think that after examining the Bible, there is no argument that being transgender is wrong. Indeed, there are only three main prongs of attack, all of which are incorrect.

The first prong of attack is the homosexuality argument. However, if someone really is the opposite gender, then it would by definition not be homosexual.

The second prong of attack is the rule against cross dressing. However, if someone really is the opposite gender, it's not cross dressing.

The third prong of attack is against physical mutilation of the body. I think there are other things wrong with this argument. However, that someone is transgender does not imply that they will or have to 'mutilate' their body. They may be happier if they do, but being transgender does not entail it happening.

None of these imply that being transgender it's self is in any way wrong. It is always something else that commonly goes along with transgender issues that makes it wrong.

Edit: This argument depends upon a non-biological definition of gender. If gender is biological, then the attacks make a lot more sense. However, this raises the question, "Can we define gender as biological based on the Bible?" 
</OP>
<reply id="cnb8dy3" author="joerobo">
Well, I am E. Orthodox, and to be honest if you just look at what the bible says and does not say, explicitly, there is not much useful information to be garnered.  This is the deep and inherent flaw to Sola Scriptura (as well as the fact that everyone just can come up with whatever they want it to say, but thats a whole different can of worms).

If you are willing to look past the literal letter of the scripture, its rather clear.  Marriage is explicitly enshrined as an institute for reproduction, multiple times.  Further more sexual immorality is explicitly condemned, in the context of homosexuality among other things as being part of this.  

This is the more pressing issue however- the Church likely would never consider a person to ever be any gender than the one God made them.  Or in other words, it would be condemned as homosexuality, becuase you cannot change the gender that God gave you.  (You can't really actually change it with science, either, but don't say that to loud, people get threatened)

The single biggest reason though, is that changing your gender is in effect spitting in the face of God.  If he is all knowing, and all loving, you were made the way you were for a purpose.  In changing your gender you are saying 'God, you got it wrong.'  I am aware that people who feel this way do not choose to, and are often times very nice people.  Too bad, thats not a good enough reason.  We all have 'crosses to bear', and the big idea is the more faithfully you bear it the better things go for you once you die.  I would go so far as to say that there likely have been gay/trans Saints in church history; the became saints precisely because they controlled their passions and urges, and mastered them.  Not because they gave in.  

Here's my final note- I have studied the bible in its original Greek, I know church history and dogma fairly well, I have a copy of all the canonical cannons sitting about 8 feet away from me. To ask 'can we define gender as biological based on the Bible' is akin to asking 'can we declare UFOs as real based on the encyclopedia brittanica'.  No, you cannot, as the writers would have rejected the notion of transgender prima facie.  Progressive ism and the gospels are in fundamental opposition; and cannot and will not ever be reconciled.  And as someone who speaks greek fluently, and has read the septugiant in its original, the number of groups coming up with their own translations that specifically twist, mistranslate, and omit to fit their agendas is disgusting.

But I don't feel the need to tell anyone this.  I am content to know they will rot for eternity.
</reply>
<reply id="cnb9oup" author="SobanSa">
You have a lot of great thoughts! :D

Your post seems to assume a biological definition of gender. Is that because of authoritative sources that I as a protestant don't accept? If so, what sources are they?  
</reply>
<reply id="cnbcnok" author="joerobo">
http://www.frpeterpreble.com/2012/07/transsexuals-and-orthodoxy.html

I'd specifically direct you to the 4rth paragraph which cites 6 separate ecumenical cannons that existed well pre-schism directly addressing the issue.
</reply>
<reply id="cnbde55" author="SobanSa">
Thank you! It looks like the biological definition of gender comes from a authoritative source within E. Orthodoxy. While I don't necessarily accept it, it certainly gives good insight to the problem. Have a ∆. I don't consider it a biblical argument, but it is a good argument.
</reply>
</thread>
