<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2r07cv">
<title>CMV: There is no sound biblical argument that makes being trans-gender morally wrong.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2r07cv/cmv_there_is_no_sound_biblical_argument_that/</source>
<OP author="SobanSa">
I'm not some hippy liberal christian, I'm a serious southern baptist Sunday school teacher. I think that after examining the Bible, there is no argument that being transgender is wrong. Indeed, there are only three main prongs of attack, all of which are incorrect.

The first prong of attack is the homosexuality argument. However, if someone really is the opposite gender, then it would by definition not be homosexual.

The second prong of attack is the rule against cross dressing. However, if someone really is the opposite gender, it's not cross dressing.

The third prong of attack is against physical mutilation of the body. I think there are other things wrong with this argument. However, that someone is transgender does not imply that they will or have to 'mutilate' their body. They may be happier if they do, but being transgender does not entail it happening.

None of these imply that being transgender it's self is in any way wrong. It is always something else that commonly goes along with transgender issues that makes it wrong.

Edit: This argument depends upon a non-biological definition of gender. If gender is biological, then the attacks make a lot more sense. However, this raises the question, "Can we define gender as biological based on the Bible?" 
</OP>
<reply id="cnb5yjj" author="riggorous">
I'm not a Sunday school teacher, so I have a question: does the Bible treat sex and gender as different phenomena? Because if the Bible treats sex and gender as the same thing, then having a vagina, for instance, means that your gender is female, and as such a person with a vagina who engages in sexual acts with other vaginal people is homosexual, and who wears clothing meant for men is cross-dressing, whatever they believe themselves to be. I'm definitely a hippy liberal, by the way, which doesn't excuse my ignorance.
</reply>
<reply id="cnb60ec" author="SobanSa">
There is no one who is arguably transgender in the bible, so it's difficult to say.
</reply>
<reply id="cnb669b" author="riggorous">
Then it's likely that past commentaries have interpreted sex and gender as the same thing, which is the root of the controversy. Sorry, I haven't been of much help.
</reply>
<reply id="cnba2x5" author="SobanSa">
You have been of some help. ∆ In that if sex and gender are considered the same thing, then it implies a biological definition of gender.
</reply>
</thread>
