<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qzudy">
<title>CMV: Physical media such as DVDs, blu-rays, and music CDs are pointless to purchase, because they will be obsolete within 10 years</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qzudy/cmv_physical_media_such_as_dvds_blurays_and_music/</source>
<OP author="DalekMD">
Although there is something kind of special about owning a physical copy of a favorite movie or album, I no longer see any reason to purchase a piece of physical media in today's world of technology that includes such a vast array of services. There are two main reasons:

1) Streaming and subscription services have exploded at a staggering rate. Look at Spotify and Netflix as the prime examples. For an incredibly cheap price, or sometimes at no price at all, you can listen to almost any song your heart desires, or watch any movie that strikes your interest. Yes, it is true that both of these services do not have literally everything, but as the years go on, these services will only get better, to the point where it is virtually impossible to not have access to a movie or song.

2) Storage devices will only continue to increase in storage capacity. Why own a disc that takes up physical space in your household when you can download all of your TV shows, movies, and music onto your computer? Many people today are creating their own home servers with tons of storage space to hold all their media. Granted, this is a bit difficult for those who are not tech savvy, but a few years from now, I'm positive that obtaining a server for your media and being able to place media on it will become an incredibly simple process.

As one final, less important point, physical media is restricted in its quality. What you purchase is what you get. For example, DVDs are not capable of playing movies in full HD. In order to get the best quality, you need to repurchase your DVDs in blu-ray. But even now, blu-rays are being outdone by 4k quality! How long will this continue for?

I'd love to hear your opinions, because despite this, I do have an irrational attraction to physical CDs.
</OP>
<reply id="cnb75td" author="cdman">
In addition to what others have said, almost always your rights are much more restricted when using streams (or other digital downloads for that case - like games, ebooks, etc). Usually they are considered **rented** instead of **bought** so you may not do a lot of things which people expect to do with their property. For example:

* you (almost certainly) will be required to pay a monthly/subscription fee to continue to access the given video/music/etc which on the long term works out to a larger sum than if you would have just bought the individual items
* if the business entity dissapears (goes bankrupt, is sold, etc) you will loose access to all the **rented** media
  * ^ this already has happened to several games which require a central server to play
* the provider may remove a given film/video/music/etc from their catalogue for any reason
  * ^ again, this has happened to several games, music streaming services and ironically with the Amazon Kindle when they removed Orwell's 1984 from their customers devices
* you are not allowed to backup "your" media from this services (to guard against the above failure cases) because legally you are only **renting** it
* you are not allowed to re-sell your media (because you did not buy it legally)
* you are not allowed to lend it to friends / relatives / etc
* streaming services are almost always tied to your physical identity (compared to a cash-purchased physical item). This means that if somebody decides to harass people who have certain tastes ("First they came for..."), they can identify you

This is not to say that streaming services are all bad (they are great for sampling for example) but in my personal opinion a large majority of their user base misunderstands the nature of the service and what they get (and what they give up) when they pay for it.
</reply>
<reply id="cnbubzc" author="DalekMD">
&amp;#8710;

Awarding you a delta because you made me realize just how restrictive streaming services can be. It seems like you are at their mercy, and when it comes to your favorite shows, music, movies, etc, the only surefire way to keep them forever is to buy a copy for yourself.
</reply>
</thread>
