<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qz1fp">
<title>CMV: The most financially successful film released in 2014 was likely Planes: Fire and Rescue</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qz1fp/cmv_the_most_financially_successful_film_released/</source>
<OP author="flamecubes">
**TL;DR: Planes 2 likely made 24 times is production cost back in worldwide box office, blu-ray + dvd and merchandising. Transformers 4 (the highest grossing film worldwide) made roughly 15 times its production cost back. So, Planes 2 is the most successful film this year.**

*****

While arbitrary, I define financial success as the cumulative revenue a film is responsible for generating (box office, merchandising, secondary markets) as a multiple of its production cost. I also eliminate films costing minimal amounts of money to produce (e.g., a youtube video or independent film not in wide release).

As a target, the highest grossing film worldwide was Transformers: Age of Extinction, which [grossed] (http://www.the-numbers.com/movie/Transformers-Age-of-Extinction#tab=summary) approximately 1.137 billion in its initial worldwide release and domestic US DVD and Blu-ray sales.  Additionally, lets assume that the film grosses another 87 million in worldwide secondary sales, and around 2 billion in merchandising in the next few years. These figures aren't public, but are based on estimates from the original trilogy published by [Variety] (http://variety.com/2014/film/news/transformers-the-anatomy-of-a-cross-platform-money-maker-1201245881/). Transformers [cost] (http://boxofficemojo.com/movies/?id=transformers4.htm) $210 million to make. So, **Transformer's 4's revenue:production cost ratio is around 15.2** (3.2b:210m).

To beat this figure, Planes: Fire and Rescue would have to have a cumulative revenue more than $760 million (15.2 x [its production cost] (http://boxofficemojo.com/movies/?id=planes2.htm) of $50 million).

We know that its [worldwide box office] (http://boxofficemojo.com/movies/?id=planes2.htm) was $147 million. It [made] (http://www.the-numbers.com/weekly-video-sales-chart) 22 million in domestic US blu-ray and dvd sales. Additionally, using a traditional international dvd/blu-ray sales multipler, we can estimate roughly 35 million of international sales. So cumulatively, the film has made roughly $204 million from box office and secondary markets.

Now, the film would have to make roughly $556 million from merchandising in order to pass Transformers 4 in revenue:production cost ratio. I would argue that this film will do so easily. Data shows that the Cars series (averaged) [http://www.cnbc.com/id/43525949]. 2 billion per year. The original Cars film made $10 billion in merchandising in 5 years (see previous cite). This $2 billion estimate was also made before Disney expanded its theme parks to include Cars-specific attractions. It is unclear if the Cars/Planes series is still generating $2/yr, and $10 billion/film. However, the merchandising channels have been plowed by former films, and Disney is primed to take advantage of the release of Planes films. So, it would not be unrealistic to think that Planes 2 would generate at least 10% of the merchandising revenue generated by Cars. If Planes 2 generates a mere 10% of the merchandising revenue that Cars 1 generated, it would generate **1.2 billion** in total box office, dvd + bluray, and merchandising. **This gives it a 24-times revenue:production cost ratio, about 1.6 times Transformers 4's ratio of 15.**

Therefore, Planes 2 is likely the most financially successful film of the year. If its merchandising is greater than 10% of Cars 1's total, then it may have been much more successful than any other film this year.


_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnb1cxi" author="Wehavecrashed">
What about the fault in our stars? It made $124 million domestically on a $12 million budget. Plus it made another $170 internationally and $30 million in dvd and blu ray sales and it would have driven significant sales of the book. The book sold 5 million copies worldwide in the first half of 2014 before the film was even released, the book was released in January 2012.  

330,000,000/12,000,0000=27.75. 

Planes 2 likely made 24 times is production cost back in worldwide box office, blu-ray + dvd and merchandising. TIFIOS likely made 27 times its production cost back in worldwide box office, blu0ray + dvd sales, not including merchandising or book sales.  

I'd be interested to see how much money the 5 million book sales made but those numbers alone show that TIFIOS was far more successful than Planes: Fire and Rescue. 
</reply>
<reply id="cnb1oes" author="flamecubes">
You win, I didn't believe it until I saw it. TFIOS was really cheap to produce. &amp;#8710;

</reply>
</thread>
