<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qwnfj">
<title>CMV: Japan ought to ban abortion</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qwnfj/cmv_japan_ought_to_ban_abortion/</source>
<OP author="LogicRulesOverAll">
Recently I read this article (1) discussing the impacts of Japan's sexual apathy. One of the greatest impacts is the deficit of new born children. Japan's reproduction rate is well below the necessary replacement rate of 2 children per adult. If such a retrogression continues, Japan will face extraordinary challenges in the future.

In the midst of this crisis, the Japanese are continuing to abort viable fetuses. If all of these unwanted fetuses were born, the retrogression will certainly pull back thus possibly saving the country if not at least giving them more time to find a solution.

I'm most certainly not married to this idea, and I would be glad to have my view changed.

1 http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/worldviews/wp/2013/10/22/japans-sexual-apathy-is-endangering-the-global-economy/?tid=pm_world_pop

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cna9p2z" author="CapnTBC">
Couldn't they just bring in more immigrants to compensate? Instead of forcing women to have unwanted children the immigrants would be having children. 
</reply>
<reply id="cnaa3bl" author="LogicRulesOverAll">
&amp;#8710;

This is a really good point that I haven't considered. I imagine Japan would be extremely benefited by allowing many more immigrants into their country. I think this solution is superior to my idea.
</reply>
</thread>
