<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qwdic">
<title>CMV- Mentally handicapped people should be held to more or less the same standard as neurotypical employees when working at their job.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qwdic/cmv_mentally_handicapped_people_should_be_held_to/</source>
<OP author="JackFantastic">
(Before I start a disclaimer: I posted this with the intention of learning more about something I'm not very educated about. Nothing I say was meant to denigrate or offend anyone and if it does I sincerely apologize.) 

I used to work at a retail store with a policy to not discriminate against mentally handicapped individuals when it comes to hiring. I find such a policy to be a generally good thing and definitely helpful in enriching the lives of less fortunate people. But to help elucidate my issue let me tell you about the two employees I worked with. 

Changing names obviously, so let's call them Ricky and Julian. I never asked specifically about their illnesses so all I can report on are my observations. 

Julian was a much older man, probably 50+ and he seemed to function about as well as a nine or ten year old. He was a sweet man who loved interacting with the customers, tried his hardest, and was nice to everyone. I liked Julian and didn't mind helping him out when he was having a tough time, for example he needed help working the time clock because he couldn't read very well. If Julian was the only handicapped person I ever worked with, my opinion would be different. 

The problem was Ricky. He was a little younger and seemed to be a bit more higher functioning. I'm not sure how to quantify the difference between these guys, but with Julian you felt like you were talking to someone who wasn't all there, while Ricky felt like he was all there, just slow? 

Anyway this guy was just a jerk. I feel bad for thinking that because I'm sure his life is filled with many more challenges than mine, but it still rubbed me the wrong way. He didn't try hard to do his job, he didn't stay focused on tasks, and would flatly refuse to do anything he didn't want to do. I saw him many times frustrate the front side supervisors because he would literally wander around the store hiding when he didn't want to work. He wasn't incapable, he could do it and do it well when he wanted. He was just an insensitive contrarian. 

That kind of behavior from a neurotypical employee resulted in termination. I watched coworkers get fired for less, but it seemed like no matter what he did it was impossible to fire Ricky without seeming discriminatory, and I think that's wrong. 

Julian worked his hardest and happily completed his tasks, I have absolutely no problem working with him. 
Ricky acted like a petulant child and actively made other people's job harder, but we were stuck with him because we either couldn't or wouldn't fire him for underperforming and blatantly disobeying.


</OP>
<reply id="cna72rc" author="moonflower">
I don't know what the arrangement is in your country, but in some countries the goverenment pays the employers to employ mentally disabled people, so it's not costing your employers anything to give Ricky a ''job'' whether he actually does any work or not ... it's just somewhere for him to go each day so that he might be able to do something other than sit at home and claim welfare benefits directly.

 If he didn't have this ''job'' that's what he would be doing, so maybe he does a little bit of work sometimes which is useful, and maybe he is less bored than he would be at home, so it benefits everyone.

Maybe he is not held to the same standard as regular employees because the company isn't paying him like they are paying you ...?
</reply>
<reply id="cna7fq7" author="JackFantastic">
∆

Though it might not cost the employer any money, it definitely lowers the quality of the workplace having a coworker who won't do his or her share but still takes home the same paycheck. If there's 5 people in the dept including Ricky that just means the other four have to do 120% of the work and that still isn't quite fair. 

Though I'll award your delta, since if it is in fact the case that his compensation comes from some sort of assistance program rather than the store's funds itself. That at least makes it make a little more sense why they would be less quick to terminate him for dereliction of duty. 
</reply>
</thread>
