<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qu6fg">
<title>CMV: Making a product or service illegal only creates a black market which is generally more harmful than what is being made illegal</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qu6fg/cmv_making_a_product_or_service_illegal_only/</source>
<OP author="DanielFGray">
Making something illegal doesn't make people want it any less, there has only been a deterrent created. Stealing is illegal, but that doesn't mean people don't *want* to steal that new thing that just hit the market or that thing they need but can't afford, it just means that deterrent is more effective than their want of the thing.

Likewise, making a drug illegal does not magically make people not want to do that drug, you've just made a deterrent. A deterrent isn't going to stop a heroin addict from getting his fix and overcoming withdrawal, you've just changed where he gets it from and how much it costs and the risks associated with it. The user now has to go to a sketchy dealer, the dealer has many tiers of other sketchy dealers all the way up to the cartel behind it all, and that cartel is arguably more destructive than the drug itself and so is the "war" against the drug.

Making abortion illegal isn't going to stop women from wanting an abortion, you've just made it much less likely for them to get it done safely. If that woman was raped and she doesn't want to carry a reminder of her attacker, she isn't going to care that some piece of paper says she's not allowed to do that, she's going to find a some shady doctor with a revoked license to do it for her, or she's going to take a coat hanger to herself.

Edit: I am mostly speaking about victim-less crimes. Eg, the aforementioned, possession of weapons, consensual prostitution, and (perhaps most controversially) digital piracy. 
</OP>
<reply id="cn9rm4s" author="kingpatzer">
What you are specifically talking about are "vice" crimes. There's a reason for that term. Vice crimes are activities that are made illegal because they offend the moral standards of the community. Prostitution, drugs, alcohol, and so forth. 

Abortion is an edge case in that those who oppose abortion will contend that there is in fact a victim and the act is not merely a moral offense. 

My understanding is that your statement with regard to vice crimes is actually fairly well established as a fact in criminology. That is, a community banning a desired activity on the basis of mere moral objection must find the activity to be so objectionable as to warrant bearing both the cost of enforcement and the cost of illegal supply. Depending on the severity of enforcement and criminal penalties, the cost of illegal supply can extend to social costs associated with a black market. 

I'm not a criminologist and I only took one class quite a while ago, but I remember this was presented as accepted wisdom at that point in time. 
</reply>
<reply id="cnalqz6" author="DanielFGray">
&amp;#8710; You're right, my argument mostly applies to vice crimes, it doesn't apply as a blanket statement. I actually want to give delta to everyone who pointed that out, but you get it for actually pinpointing it really applies best to vice crimes. 
</reply>
</thread>
