<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rmy6e">
<title>CMV: Philosophy has no tangible value as an academic field of study.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rmy6e/cmv_philosophy_has_no_tangible_value_as_an/</source>
<OP author="RazzzerBlade">
As an independent form of study, philosophy doesn't seem to have any practical applications. What value does philosophy have in the modern age, right now, aside from contemplating things. Is it truly worth it to invest a significant amount of time and money studying this field? 

There do not seem to be any tangible applications or appreciable benefits from studying philosophy aside from personal growth and the expansion of one's intellectual perspective, which I argue can be gained without studying philosophy in a rigorously academic manner.  

I often have read the argument that it is impossible to argue that philosophy is useless without using philosophy, or something along those lines.

I acknowledge this. Yes, I am engaging in the use of philosophy right now, at this very moment. However, this does not provide an argument as to why it would be worthwhile to STUDY philosophy. 

What do you gain from studying philosophy that could not be gained from thoughtful introspection? 

Certainly, important tools have originated from philosophical study, such as the scientific method, and science could be described as a subset of philosophy itself but that isn't an argument against the lack of tangible benefits to be gained from studying philosophy.

You don't need to study philosophy to become a capable scientist. You shouldn't need to study philosophy to cultivate a reasonable set of moral principles, or to be thoughtful about the circumstances and situations you encounter in your life. 

EDIT: I didn't expect so many answers! I'll try to read them all before I get too tired.

_____


&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnhjqws" author="nerdsarepeopletoo">
Let me take a crack at this, as someone with a philosophy degree (Minor + Master's) and a job in which I find practical uses every single day for things I studied in Philosophy.

One thing I found studying philosophy is that a lot of people (even philosophers) have a bit of a useless conception of what philosophy is or does. There's always talk of 'Big Questions' and 'Deep Problems' or whatnot, and I think that misses the point. Philosophy is a set of methods and concepts that you learn and practice and wield, and those methods and concepts are extremely useful in all sorts of circumstances.

What you really learn (or rather, the most practically valuable thing you learn) is to become an *expert* in analytical thinking. That means things like: identifying hidden assumptions in people's reasoning, noticing informal and formal logical fallacies and generating counterexamples, identifying and isolating distinct concepts that people have mistakenly superimposed, assessing things like the knowability or provability of a claim, identifying and avoiding circular reasoning, formulating alternative possible explanations when data underdetermines the given theory and on and on. 

&gt;What do you gain from studying philosophy that could not be gained from thoughtful introspection? 

The problem with thoughtful introspection is that you're vulnerable to your own bias. It's very difficult to poke holes in your own reasoning because you always think you're right. Studying philosophy is an opportunity to practice poking holes in arguments that can be very nuanced and very airtight (you don't get this so much in 1st/2nd year courses), and then have a trained philosopher read and poke holes in your reasoning too. You get to read arguments against other arguments and see how expert thinkers think.

&gt; You don't need to study philosophy to become a capable scientist.

Obviously not, you need to study science (though you would be surprised how many leading scientists actively study philosophy). Science is a set of methods and concepts that helps you explore the relationships between things in the world. Philosophy, on the other hand, is a set of methods and concepts that helps you explore *reasoning*. You call on science when you need to answer questions about how the world works, and you call on philosophers when you need to know about how to reason correctly in unfamiliar conceptual territory.

Most people don't need philosophy to tell them what to do on a day-to-day basis, because most people don't encounter important and unfamiliar moral choices on a day-to-day basis. But Hospitals hire philosophers (Bioethicists) to help them decide on policies and decisions that affect people's lives in novel and controversial ways (e.g. stem cells, abortion, the policies for people in vegetative states, etc.). Likewise, most people's lives are sufficiently common and boring that thoughtful introspection will do them just fine; but, for example, cutting edge businesses (e.g. tech or service start-ups) rely on previously untested reasoning, and it can be very useful to have a capable, trained set of eyes on your thought process before you pull the trigger.

TL;DR Philosophy is like the science of reasoning, and it can be very useful when you have to reason in unfamiliar or novel ways, such as new business ideas, medical practices, and even science
</reply>
<reply id="cni1gsy" author="RazzzerBlade">
&amp;#8710; 


I see what you mean now.

I think this post really helped me realize how silly and ill-conceived my understanding of philosophy actually is. 

Plus I really appreciated the careers that were listed along with the post. I had a hard time thinking of any careers related to philosophy that one could obtain with a degree outside from careers in academia, and, honestly, as a college student, I think that my view on what sort of fields are valuable is disproportionately influenced by what careers can be obtained from a particular field. 
</reply>
</thread>
