<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qncj3">
<title>CMV Me joining the army is not a waste of time nor does it conflict with my personality</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qncj3/cmv_me_joining_the_army_is_not_a_waste_of_time/</source>
<OP author="Hamza78ch11">
I've always had a respect for the men in uniform and I've always wanted to join. Recently I've disagreed with the practices of the U.S. military but that doesn't mean that I hate the Warriors, just the people that force them into it. I'm an immigrant and a Muslim neither of which is or should be a deterrent from joining. I want to be a doctor, not because of familial pressure but of a genuine need to help. So here's where I am now: currently in first year of college studying biology, enough AP credits to be a tiny bit ahead of my classmates, an itching to explore this giant world God gave me, I'm also poor and medical school in the military (from what I understand) pays for smart kids. Also, please forgive me if this is wrong or arrogant or whatever, I want the respect that people give men and women in the military. 


My plan was to graduate College and join the USHS (the military medical school) and become and Army doctor. The only reservation that I had was that it would be a waste of my time because I want to be a neurosurgeon and that's a looooooooong and rigorous path and that I might be losing precious time by joining the military. My mom doesn't want me to join for that reason. 
Other things that I've considered: I love the idea of a brotherhood but I don't agree with the ideology, the military putting me through Med school will help me jump start life, I'm very inexperienced and haven't seen much of the world and this I think will help me. 

I look forward to having my views challenged! Thanks!
</OP>
<reply id="cn7tqy5" author="AgnosticKierkegaard">
&gt;My plan was to graduate College and join the USHS (the military medical school) and become and Army doctor.

FYI, you don't have to go to USHS to be a military doctor.  You can go to civilian medical school, and get HPSP which is slightly different but accomplishes roughly the same thing.  

&gt;The only reservation that I had was that it would be a waste of my time because I want to be a neurosurgeon and that's a looooooooong and rigorous path and that I might be losing precious time by joining the military. 

Well, it's not worth it for the money.  You'll lose money by taking HPSP and especially with USHS (a longer commitment than HPSP).  You'll owe the military tons of time for the training, so you won't be able to enter civilian practice for years.  Civilian neurosurgeons will easily catch up to their debtless peers in the military due to the huge difference in salaries.  A civilian neurosurgeon can make over 400k easily.  A military surgeon will never see that much.  So, with NSRGY you will have a net loss in the military compared to a civilian path with loans. This is assuming you get a neurosurgery residency in the military, which is suspect.  Neurosurgery is already competitive, and the military's neurosurgery residencies are extremely limited.  You may end up as a general surgeon, or doing several GMO tours before starting your 7 year neurosurgery residency.  

&gt;Other things that I've considered: I love the idea of a brotherhood but I don't agree with the ideology

If you're not all in with the military you'll hate being a military doctor.  The only reason to do HPSP or USHS is because you want to be a doctor in the military, not because you want the money.  If you're ambivalent the risk is too great.  

&gt;I'm also poor and medical school in the military (from what I understand) pays for smart kids. 

Banks have zero problem giving out loans to medical students.  You'll easily cover your tuition, and while debt sucks you'll easily pay it off after residency.  

In short, don't do it unless you are 100% committed to spending about a decade and a half in the military in a speciality that might not even necessarily be NSRGY
</reply>
<reply id="cn7ug34" author="Hamza78ch11">
Δ That whipped me around real fast. I guess it's more about being a military doctor rather than a doctor in the military. Thanks! 
</reply>
</thread>
