<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qhw5w">
<title>CMV: I believe the Brave Little Toaster is an incredibly underrated movie</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qhw5w/cmv_i_believe_the_brave_little_toaster_is_an/</source>
<OP author="MasterofRoflness">
Ive seen a lot of animated movies in my life but in my opinion they dont stand up to the Brave Little Toaster. The animation is very solid for being made in the 1980`s and I absolutely love the inanimate objects journey to try and find their master. One very tense scene for me was when the vacuum cleaner was trying to cross the canyon. However whenever people bring up animated movies they never bring up the Brave Little Toaster. I feel like this masterpiece is largely unappreciated by a majority of people in favor of other animated movies. 

Reddit I think the Brave Little Toaster needs some more attention and some more love. CMV
_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cn6ao87" author="A_Soporific">
The Brave Little Toaster is rated "Fresh" on Rotten Tomatoes, and came fairly close to winning the Sundance Film Festival in 1987. The reason it is doesn't have attention now is because it didn't get attention back in the day. The movie was not widely released in theaters because they never found a distributor for it.

So most of us who saw it did so in comparatively limited TV showings, or picked up a VHS tape. It wasn't a made for TV movie, but that's what ended up happening to it. It has massively outsized footprint for how easy it is to find and view. Those who worked on it went on to do great things, and those who stumbled across it remember it.

So, in conclusion, The Brave Little Toaster isn't underrated as it is rated very highly, but it is obscure and can be a hard sell because key elements haven't aged well.
</reply>
<reply id="cn6atmm" author="MasterofRoflness">
Holy Crap I never knew it only went straight to VHS. That does explain a lot which kinda makes me sad it never got the loving from a massive portion of people like Iron Giant. Maybe a rerelease on Netflix will reignite the fire of the Brave Little Toaster. 

btw Um you get a delta for proving me wrong and that the movie was loved by the people but had very little in terms of distribution &amp;#8710;
</reply>
</thread>
