<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qh719">
<title>CMV: If you're able, European and subscribe even loosely to European values, you should be on the Ukrainian border, driving back Russians</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qh719/cmv_if_youre_able_european_and_subscribe_even/</source>
<OP author="TheCyanKnight">
Obviously I'm not there right now, but I'm curious if anyone can put my mind at ease that I shouldn't be.  
  
Feels to me as if Putin senses weakness in the Western world, with the US and Europe driven farther apart by issues like privacy and human rights, the US withdrawing as a dominant force in geopolitics, because people in and outside of the US are fed up with the US policing the world.   
His territorial pissings seems to be meant to elbow some room for himself on the geopolitical stage, in other words gaining power. Putin is a totalitarian, oppressive, ruthless man, and allowing him to gain more power will affect all of us.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cn63zdl" author="HJD8d9d">
I doubt anyone on the Ukrainian front actually wants a bunch of untrained Europeans to show up and start attacking anything that looks vaguely Russian. This just won't help the situation in any way. If you really want to help, sending money you earn with something you're actually good at (your job) is far more helpful. Another thing you can do is to tell your government to send (military) aid. Neither things are as cool as fighting Russians  out of a moral sense of duty, but they're far more effective.

The above assumes that the Europeans should get more involved with the Ukrainian conflict. While I agree that that might be the moral thing to do, we should be very careful not to escalate the conflict. You should not underestimate how threatened Russia feels by the West's expansion into what used to be a buffer zone. Whether that feeling and their reaction are justified or not doesn't really matter; the fact is that a proxy war between Europe and Russia would be disastrous. 

</reply>
<reply id="cn64ay7" author="TheCyanKnight">
Awarding a ∆ for making me realize that intention to fight back Russians doesn't automatically mean you can do so effectively, and that it's the most effective thing to do.  
  
My view has not utterly and definitely changed for the following reasons:  
  
Telling my government to send help is easier said than done.  
  
Not everybody will make enough that his financial support will outweigh the military support he can provide, this is a definite nuance to my general initial statement though. Supporting foreign militaries financially also has proven sketchy at best in the past, because it's hard to control where the weapons eventually end up. 
  
I still needs convincing that supporting the currently ongoing fight is actually escalating the conflict. Putin knows very well that he's transgressing. If that's quelled quickly and effectively, things will get back to normal, whereas if he gets away with it, he might push and push to see how far he can go. 
  
 
</reply>
</thread>
