<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qgpie">
<title>CMV: Progress in automation will eventually lead to a full fledge genocide on the majority of the population.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qgpie/cmv_progress_in_automation_will_eventually_lead/</source>
<OP author="Prometheus_v2">
[47% of all jobs are at risk of being automated](http://motherboard.vice.com/blog/the-rich-and-their-robots-are-about-to-make-half-the-worlds-jobs-disappear). This number will grow grow until the vast majority of people become obsolete for jobs. Since some of this automation will inevitably come to weapons, the wealthy will have the perfect opportunity to commit genocide on the 99%. By fortifying themselves in their gated communities with rows upon rows of automated defences, all unburdened by humans with consciences and families, they can simply wait for everyone to starve or get killed while they bask in their machine generated wealth. Once everyone is dead, they can simply be wiped from history. You, me, everyone will have never existed. A crime completely erased.

[I am not the only one to predict this outcome](https://www.jacobinmag.com/2011/12/four-futures/) (see the last section on "exterminism"). I don't think the other more optimistic futures expressed in that article will come to pass given current mentalities. I think it's also too late to stop it. Those who will fight it will lose. Please CMV so I can have hope again. 

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cn620d0" author="isleepinahammock">
You remember that old phrase from Forest Gump, "a man only needs so much money, the rest is just for showing off." Well that's actually quite true. 

Throughout history, people tend to use their wealth to show off how much wealth they have. The status symbols change over time, but the existence of status symbols doesn't. 

There was a time, say in the 18th century, where the elite would wear quite elaborate clothing. Check out this picture of [Louis XIV](http://www.paradoxplace.com/Photo%20Pages/France/France_History/Images/Louis-XIV-BAR800.jpg). He's dressing in elaborate, fantastical clothing to tell everyone, "look how rich and powerful I am. I can afford to waste resources on immense amounts of expensive fabric." 

Nowadays, you would never see a wealthy leader dressing like this. Clothes have become cheap, thus they are no longer useful as a status symbol. Certain elite brands are used to show off wealth, but the suit the president wears is little different in form than the suit you can buy down at Walmart. His suit is just higher quality and better fitted.

Or consider beauty standards. Back during the Victorian Era, it was very fashionable for women of class to have extremely pale skin. When most of the populace lived on farms or walked to work in a factory, most people got tan quite easily. Only the rich could afford to be pale. Nowadays, where most people work office jobs, retail jobs, food service, etc, tanning is a luxury good, a sign you have enough spare time to sit in the sun or money to go to a tanning salon.

So, what would the luxury goods be for a post-scarcity society? In such a society, the cost of most physical goods would approach zero. Raw materials would be extracted by robots. Energy would come from cheap robot-produced solar farms. Robots would assemble and repair other robots. The cost of most physical goods, in a true post-scarcity society, is near zero. Sure, a common laborer could buy a thousand copies of a 2015 Lexus, but what's the point? Even someone working at Burger King could afford to put together a copy of Louis XIV's outfit, but no one ever does. It's just seen as silly and ridiculous, possibly even a sign of mental illness.

So, what would rich people spend their money on? What are the status goods of post-scarcity society? Well, real estate could certainly be one. The cost to build a house may be zero, but land certainly isn't. Still, this can be ameliorated by high-rises. Lots of people can afford to live in a ritzy downtown area if a high-quality high rise can be built to next for nothing. Owning a single-family home in a high-quality area would be a status symbol, but just living their wouldn't.

So, without that, what do we have? About the only thing you can buy with your money at that point is human-intensive services. Sure, you *could* use a robot to clean your house, but do you want people to think you are poor? Show off your wealth by hiring a butler instead. You *could* put your kid through a MOOC to teach them algebra, but you're better than that. Hire an expensive private tutor instead. You *could* have a robot do your hair or nails, but really? What are you, a common peasant? Pay for the fancy salon instead and show off your fabulous wealth. You *could* use a driverless car, but having someone drive you around is just so much more classy. 

In short, in a world where the cost of physical goods is near zero, the only way to show off your wealth is to hire a bunch of people as a status symbol.

So, what does retain 
</reply>
<reply id="cn65fkv" author="Prometheus_v2">
∆

So instead of genocide we simply go back to feudalism. I can't say this is a perfect outcome but I guess it's both better than death and it's something I can see happening.
</reply>
</thread>
