<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rmy6e">
<title>CMV: Philosophy has no tangible value as an academic field of study.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rmy6e/cmv_philosophy_has_no_tangible_value_as_an/</source>
<OP author="RazzzerBlade">
As an independent form of study, philosophy doesn't seem to have any practical applications. What value does philosophy have in the modern age, right now, aside from contemplating things. Is it truly worth it to invest a significant amount of time and money studying this field? 

There do not seem to be any tangible applications or appreciable benefits from studying philosophy aside from personal growth and the expansion of one's intellectual perspective, which I argue can be gained without studying philosophy in a rigorously academic manner.  

I often have read the argument that it is impossible to argue that philosophy is useless without using philosophy, or something along those lines.

I acknowledge this. Yes, I am engaging in the use of philosophy right now, at this very moment. However, this does not provide an argument as to why it would be worthwhile to STUDY philosophy. 

What do you gain from studying philosophy that could not be gained from thoughtful introspection? 

Certainly, important tools have originated from philosophical study, such as the scientific method, and science could be described as a subset of philosophy itself but that isn't an argument against the lack of tangible benefits to be gained from studying philosophy.

You don't need to study philosophy to become a capable scientist. You shouldn't need to study philosophy to cultivate a reasonable set of moral principles, or to be thoughtful about the circumstances and situations you encounter in your life. 

EDIT: I didn't expect so many answers! I'll try to read them all before I get too tired.

_____


&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnhc8a5" author="Cavemonster">
&gt;What do you gain from studying philosophy that could not be gained from thoughtful introspection?

Two answers. #1 rigor and #2 it saves us from reinventing the wheel.

When you ask the question of whether philosophy is useful, you give us an example of a practical application of philosophy. We're on the same page there. To expand on that, we face a lot of practical questions about what things have value. When we create school curricula we're making value judgments, when we allot budgets. These are, at least in one facet, philosophical questions, and important ones.

But you suggest we can answer these questions without studying philosophy. Can we answer high level economic questions without studying economics and math? Can we figure out plumbing questions without training in plumbing?

These value decisions (and value is just one kind of philosophical question we deal with constantly) can be based on valid or invalid arguments. If no one studies arguments of value, why do you believe that we can naturally recognize these with no study? Why do you think we should start from scratch in all value decisions rather than seeking to understand the work that has been done in the past?

A lot of philosophy seems to be common sense just because it's been so thoroughly integrated into our culture. The place that we're currently at though is the result of a lot of work in ethics, epistemology and metaphysics. To assume we can arrive at the best answers just by thinking hard is ignoring the work that got us where we are, both in failing to understand how much labor was required to get us here, and failing to challenge some of our current baseline.

Not everyone needs to study philosophy for their day to day lives, but everyone consumes it whether they know it or not. If no one studies it, then no one will be able to teach it. If no one is able to teach it, then everyone's philosophical positions will have no rigor, will make no use of the work that has already been done before.

All our philosophical questions then may as well be answered by /r/showerthoughts or /r/trees. Without rigor and background, that's where introspection gets you.
</reply>
<reply id="cni1jz1" author="RazzzerBlade">
&amp;#8710;

Your analogies really helped. It's really just as much of a skillset obtained and refined as any other field, isn't it?


</reply>
</thread>
