<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rnr30">
<title>CMV: I think the Paris shooting makes a good case for culture of responsible gun ownership any carrying.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnr30/cmv_i_think_the_paris_shooting_makes_a_good_case/</source>
<OP author="rrockethr">
Thinking about today's news: [BBC](http://www.bbc.com/news/live/world-europe-30710777), [Wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Hebdo_shooting)

I think France is in a tough spot in how to react to this. There would be even stronger calls for an anti-islam and anti-immigration policies. These event reminds people that they cannot depend on protection by government. I think it would be a shame to allow the many, who are afraid more then anything, to be swayed by xenophobic nationalists (which might have been the goal of the attack anyway). 

I think this, regardless of whether the weapons used by the attackers were owned legally, makes a good case for promoting a culture of a reasonable gun ownership and carrying. Say if 1 out of 5 people carried a gun with them, was well trained in its use and tested in his responsibility to prevent its misuse, and society upheld the value of these people as protectors, it would benefit the society more the the current state of legislature and culture of gun ownership in most of European countries. I also think this would be much better then increase in police numbers and rights as policemen are a very homogeneous group trained to stick together and the danger of even deepening the "not one of us" (pack) mentality and escalation of "police state".
Change my view.

PS: I am not here to talk about USA and its gun problems.

EDIT: Awarded a delta to a comment which didn't refute this idea but led me to change my view that it would be best realized with paralyzing weapons rather then guns: http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnr30/cmv_i_think_the_paris_shooting_makes_a_good_case/cni3o83

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cniexe1" author="JoeSalmonGreen">
I think todays shooting shows that it is far to easy to get hold of guns rather than we need more of them. Imagine these guys hadn't be able to get hold of these weapons?
</reply>
<reply id="cnih112" author="rrockethr">
Do you think they got hold of them legally? If not then you must have some genious idea how to stop people getting them illegally, without resorting to a world-wide police state...
</reply>
<reply id="cnjc9dk" author="JoeSalmonGreen">
The easier it is to get guns legally, the easier it is to get them illegally. 
</reply>
<reply id="cnjql6s" author="rrockethr">
And also the harder to defend against them. I think the sweet spot lies somewhere when more people have guns.
</reply>
<reply id="cnjz771" author="JoeSalmonGreen">
Why?
</reply>
<reply id="cnjzwm2" author="rrockethr">
Because guns are generally the most viable tool in defending against attackers with guns and it helps to avoid creating a society of easy targets.
</reply>
<reply id="cnkeqeg" author="JoeSalmonGreen">
Isnt the best way to defend against attackers with guns to make sure there are no attackers with guns?

Is there any kind of evidence base for you position at all or just gut feeling?
</reply>
<reply id="cnkfok3" author="rrockethr">
How can you guarantee there will be no attackers with guns?

It is not gut feeling. It is simple logic based on facts. It is such an obvious thing, that people with guns have been more successful in defending themselves against attackers with guns, then people without guns, that I doubt there has been any scientific study regarding this.
</reply>
<reply id="cnkfye5" author="JoeSalmonGreen">
&gt; It is simple logic based on facts.

Show me one of those facts.

It is simple logic that the more legal guns in a society, the more illegal guns that will exist. It's also quite obvious that normal civiliants with guns are going to be little better at defending themselves than unarmed civilians, and that the responsibility of dealing with terrorists or any other type of criminal is that of law enforcement.

I'd rather have 10 more well trained firearms teams than 100,000 more armed civilians. Maybe I'm wrong though, maybe you can show me some kind of statistical correlation between lax gun controls and crime rates.

There are lies, dam lies and statistics sadly though, so I'm sure we could each punch holes in the others data, but at least then we'd be moving the debate forward. As it stands saying thing are obvious or logical without providing some kind of evidence is pretty pointless in any discussion that isn't purely mathematical.

</reply>
<reply id="cnkga7h" author="rrockethr">
How is it going to help you that police is coming in 5 minutes when there is an attacker with a gun in the next room coming your way?

Again: How can you guarantee there will be no attackers with guns?

How is *correlation* between lax gun control and *crime rate* relevant to this? We are not talking about general crime and generally correlation is pretty useless observation on its own. 

Would you agree that "people with guns have been more successful in defending themselves against attackers with guns, then people without guns"?
</reply>
</thread>
