<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rnr30">
<title>CMV: I think the Paris shooting makes a good case for culture of responsible gun ownership any carrying.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnr30/cmv_i_think_the_paris_shooting_makes_a_good_case/</source>
<OP author="rrockethr">
Thinking about today's news: [BBC](http://www.bbc.com/news/live/world-europe-30710777), [Wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Hebdo_shooting)

I think France is in a tough spot in how to react to this. There would be even stronger calls for an anti-islam and anti-immigration policies. These event reminds people that they cannot depend on protection by government. I think it would be a shame to allow the many, who are afraid more then anything, to be swayed by xenophobic nationalists (which might have been the goal of the attack anyway). 

I think this, regardless of whether the weapons used by the attackers were owned legally, makes a good case for promoting a culture of a reasonable gun ownership and carrying. Say if 1 out of 5 people carried a gun with them, was well trained in its use and tested in his responsibility to prevent its misuse, and society upheld the value of these people as protectors, it would benefit the society more the the current state of legislature and culture of gun ownership in most of European countries. I also think this would be much better then increase in police numbers and rights as policemen are a very homogeneous group trained to stick together and the danger of even deepening the "not one of us" (pack) mentality and escalation of "police state".
Change my view.

PS: I am not here to talk about USA and its gun problems.

EDIT: Awarded a delta to a comment which didn't refute this idea but led me to change my view that it would be best realized with paralyzing weapons rather then guns: http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnr30/cmv_i_think_the_paris_shooting_makes_a_good_case/cni3o83

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnhlmdo" author="Thriven">
&gt;PS: I am not here to talk about USA and its gun problems.

I wont go into gun problems but rather define USA's basic laws and their impact on stopping situations like the one in Paris today.

As a person living in a country with the right to bear arms, in my experience, when an incident  like this occurs there aren't many armed civilians nearby to assist. Many large cities ban concealed firearms regardless of our liberty to own weapons. Most work places ban guns from being on the premise.

Recently there was the [2011 Tucson Shooting](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2011_Tucson_shooting). I lived right down the road from where it occurred and was involved with police and media due to the relationship of the shooter and the high school he attended. It was a wild minute as the shooter unloaded 33 rounds into the crowd. When he stopped to reload he was assaulted by a bystander with a chair.

That was in the state of Arizona which is as far conservative and gun toting as it can get. I know many people who pack as if its the wild west. However, these people never seem to be armed at the time of need.

The right to bear arms is simply gun ownership. In the event of civil war between the people and the government, the people are able to fight back. Where you are able to carry your gun is situational.

[University of Texas Shooting](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Whitman) was far more situational that would align with the OP's train of thought. A very long drawn out fire fight where police weren't equipped to deal with the gunmen. Citizens with hunting rifles fought back and kept the gunman pinned down as police entered the tower. This situation and a few others was the early starts of creating swat teams able to respond to armed gunman.

France has gun laws allowing citizens to purchase hunting rifles with permits. In the event of something like that happening in the suburbs of France, citizens could respond. 

However, the situation is so unlikely to occur as shooters rarely take to a single place and shoot from in for such a long period of time. Most shootings happen in an instant and even armed citizens aren't aware of the situation as it is occurring. Police officers and hired guards are constantly in mental preparation of responding to such a situation and know they are expected to take deadly force when they see a lethal situation occurring. If I'm carry my gun all the time but I'm simply going to a super market to pick up groceries I will be reluctant to shoot till I've assessed what is occurring.

Allowing concealed fire arms in a city like Paris to stop the threat of terrorists is a fruitless endeavor.
</reply>
<reply id="cnhmh8j" author="rrockethr">
You seem to be saying in much of these cases the people were not prepared and trained in the way I envision it and in those which they kind of were it was beneficial. Also I'm not saying this would completely stop the threat of terrorists. I don't think we are in a disagreement.
</reply>
<reply id="cnhotka" author="Thriven">
I don't know how you say we are in agreement :) I think your view is flawed completely.

&gt;Also I'm not saying this would completely stop the threat of terrorists.

&gt;These event reminds people that they cannot depend on protection by government.

You can't stop terrorist attacks. They are a cowardly form of aggression. You can't take Karate classes to prevent from being blindly hit in the back of the head when walking down the street.

This is what has caused tribes, world powers and countries to invade others and root out there enemy rather than lie and wait to be attacked. 

I'm very pro-gun ownership. I find people who have 50 of them excessive. I think a shotgun in the home or a handgun in the car in a place accessible to you in the event of a break in or attack is a good protection. You wont miss an intruder in your home with a wide spread of a shotgun. Most intruders will turn and run at the sound of the shotgun cocking.

That is all you can protect personally with guns. 

Imagining yourself fending off a gunman in a crowded theater is ultimately a dream. If you carry a gun with an 8 to 9 round magazine you better be a damn good shot because crazed gunmen usually come with automatic weapons or weapons with extended magazines and it may not be there only weapon. 

If half the citizens carried in public places MP5's with 30 round clips you may be able stop a few random encounters over the years but then again you'd have citizens turning into militants.

</reply>
<reply id="cnhpkvw" author="rrockethr">
Well then why do you think people defending themselves and their colleagues in work is so much different from defending your home?

I don't think what I would propose would stop the attacks or even decrease death counts of each attack considering accidents, but it should deter attackers so less of them should occur and when they do they are stopped sooner (say gunman going through rooms in an office space).
</reply>
<reply id="cnhz52y" author="Thriven">
At home you understand who should be in your home at that time. You have the legal right to defend it as opposed to work you would be defending yourself. Most workplaces as it stands, despite gun laws do not allow employees to carry while working. Carrying while working will usually result in a disciplinary action or immediate termination.

&gt;You seem to be saying in much of these cases the people were not prepared and trained in the way I envision it 

Honestly, if you want to speak to the details of your viewpoint you should have included that in your original post. If you haven't penned that huge detail of your point, whats the point of posting if your going to say ,"Well in my head it works".

I'm here to read your point and attempt to refute it, not draw it out from you slowly.


</reply>
<reply id="cni7yc0" author="rrockethr">
Well that is the legal situation now and obviously I think it should change if we were to head the way I described, having responsible people allow themselves to concealed carry to defend themselves and others they know aren't the attacker.

I really wasn't going to go into any details as I am not an expert (I don't even own a gun) and I'm sure the details could be ironed out by people who know more about these situations. This is partly why I am doing this CMV to see if there is some fundamental reason why it shouldn't work. I was expecting to be getting arguments about fundamental nature of things and incentives, rather then discussing exact scenarios.

EDIT: Anyway you might be interested that I CMV slightly and awarded delta to this comment: http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnr30/cmv_i_think_the_paris_shooting_makes_a_good_case/cni3o83
</reply>
</thread>
