<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rnr30">
<title>CMV: I think the Paris shooting makes a good case for culture of responsible gun ownership any carrying.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnr30/cmv_i_think_the_paris_shooting_makes_a_good_case/</source>
<OP author="rrockethr">
Thinking about today's news: [BBC](http://www.bbc.com/news/live/world-europe-30710777), [Wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Hebdo_shooting)

I think France is in a tough spot in how to react to this. There would be even stronger calls for an anti-islam and anti-immigration policies. These event reminds people that they cannot depend on protection by government. I think it would be a shame to allow the many, who are afraid more then anything, to be swayed by xenophobic nationalists (which might have been the goal of the attack anyway). 

I think this, regardless of whether the weapons used by the attackers were owned legally, makes a good case for promoting a culture of a reasonable gun ownership and carrying. Say if 1 out of 5 people carried a gun with them, was well trained in its use and tested in his responsibility to prevent its misuse, and society upheld the value of these people as protectors, it would benefit the society more the the current state of legislature and culture of gun ownership in most of European countries. I also think this would be much better then increase in police numbers and rights as policemen are a very homogeneous group trained to stick together and the danger of even deepening the "not one of us" (pack) mentality and escalation of "police state".
Change my view.

PS: I am not here to talk about USA and its gun problems.

EDIT: Awarded a delta to a comment which didn't refute this idea but led me to change my view that it would be best realized with paralyzing weapons rather then guns: http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnr30/cmv_i_think_the_paris_shooting_makes_a_good_case/cni3o83

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnhkej7" author="scottevil110">
As much of a proponent of gun rights as I am, history would seem to contradict your claim, since mass shootings occur with some regularity in the United States, where plenty of people do carry, both open and concealed, nearly all of whom have been properly trained.  

Hell, someone managed to shoot up the Navy Yard in DC.  I would wager that a few people around there were carrying guns.  

Now, you could use this incident to point out that strict gun laws are obviously incapable of stopping mass shooting events, since one just happened in a place with said laws, but I don't think you can say that more relaxed laws would have stopped it.

I think the lesson to be learned between this AND the United States is that the occurrence of mass shootings is actually pretty independent of a place's gun culture.  Just as guns can't stop it from happening, banning them obviously can't either.
</reply>
<reply id="cnhl0k6" author="rrockethr">
I'm not claiming that anything I suggested would completely prevent shooting from happening. The Navy Yard shooting is a good example. Going on a killing rampage there was practically a suicide. I'm not claiming the culture I think we should strive for would be better in dealing with suicide attacks and suicide bombers.

Also note that I'm more then about laws talking about the culture and where we should strive to develop as a society.
</reply>
</thread>
