<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rnr30">
<title>CMV: I think the Paris shooting makes a good case for culture of responsible gun ownership any carrying.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnr30/cmv_i_think_the_paris_shooting_makes_a_good_case/</source>
<OP author="rrockethr">
Thinking about today's news: [BBC](http://www.bbc.com/news/live/world-europe-30710777), [Wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Hebdo_shooting)

I think France is in a tough spot in how to react to this. There would be even stronger calls for an anti-islam and anti-immigration policies. These event reminds people that they cannot depend on protection by government. I think it would be a shame to allow the many, who are afraid more then anything, to be swayed by xenophobic nationalists (which might have been the goal of the attack anyway). 

I think this, regardless of whether the weapons used by the attackers were owned legally, makes a good case for promoting a culture of a reasonable gun ownership and carrying. Say if 1 out of 5 people carried a gun with them, was well trained in its use and tested in his responsibility to prevent its misuse, and society upheld the value of these people as protectors, it would benefit the society more the the current state of legislature and culture of gun ownership in most of European countries. I also think this would be much better then increase in police numbers and rights as policemen are a very homogeneous group trained to stick together and the danger of even deepening the "not one of us" (pack) mentality and escalation of "police state".
Change my view.

PS: I am not here to talk about USA and its gun problems.

EDIT: Awarded a delta to a comment which didn't refute this idea but led me to change my view that it would be best realized with paralyzing weapons rather then guns: http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnr30/cmv_i_think_the_paris_shooting_makes_a_good_case/cni3o83

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnhlscg" author="AdmiralCrunch9">
Think about a situation like the Aurora shooting.  A man walked into a crowded, public place, and begins shooting without warning.  Now imagine that a few people in the audience begin returning fire.  Do you think that all of them are going to correctly identify the original shooter in the confusion?  Do you think that all of the 20% of people with guns in the building will correctly guess that there is only one hostile target?  Now shots are coming from every direction, and the 80% of the crowd without guns have no idea which way they should be running to get to safety.  They are running in every direction, unpredictably entering the line of fire of the people with guns.  Now think about what happens when the police arrive and have no idea who they should consider a threat and who is a friendly, yet need to make that distinction immediately or risk being shot themselves.  

I think in many cases a confusing crossfire resulting in even more deaths is the only realistic outcome we can expect.  There will also be scenarios where all or most of the people in the area being attacked know each other well enough to recognize friend from foe, but in general these kinds of things happen in public places where people are strangers to one another.  In those situations the panic and confusion of adding more gunfire will usually make things worse.  Add in the fact that people are more likely to be killed by their own gun in either a home accident or a suicide than they are of using it to defend themselves and I don't see any reason to believe the proposed scenario would lead to a decrease in deaths.
</reply>
<reply id="cnhm32o" author="rrockethr">
Yeah I of course considered a scenario similar to the one you outline, however I think that the gun owners would be prepared to deal with these situations and their risks. The simplest thing is only to return fire if someone is firing on you or those you know have no intention to kill somebody.
</reply>
<reply id="cnhmeqt" author="AdmiralCrunch9">
That is far, *far* easier said than done.  If you aren't looking at the shooter when the shooter opens fire, then the average civilian has very little chance of correctly responding to this situation instinctively.  A lot(I would guess a majority) of people are going to perceive anyone shooting in their direction at all as a threat.  Say the shooter enters at one end of the room and someone at the other end returns fire.  How are all of the people in between to know that the second guy is trying to hit the criminal and not them?  I know you said that you think these people should be trained, but how much training do you think is reasonable to expect before we give them a gun, especially if we want to get such a huge number of people armed?  To be able to respond in a situation like that requires constant training and practice, and it's not realistic to expect so many people to do that when they aren't police or military.  It's just not realistic to expect a full fifth of our population to be able to react like SWAT team members at the drop of a hat.
</reply>
<reply id="cnhmwde" author="rrockethr">
I think it should be something of a level of the police training. Completing it should have benefits maybe even outside of the social stature.
</reply>
<reply id="cnhnbyg" author="AdmiralCrunch9">
Except police training isn't like riding a bike.  You don't just lean it once and then you're good for life.  Being prepared for an active shooter scenario is gonna need constant practice, both mental and physical.  Most police officers wouldn't even be prepared for these kind of situations, which is why we have SWAT teams that specialize in those kind of scenarios(I'd also like to point out that if we wanted to train millions of people to SWAT levels of proficiency it would be comically expensive and I have no idea who would pay for it).  Add in the fact that the situation would likely be even more stressful than the average SWAT raid since the civilians have no knowledge of any of the other participants and were completely unprepared in the moment, and do you still feel that training which would necessarily be brief and infrequent enough to allow for these people to have other jobs would be extensive enough to mitigate dangers I brought up?  Because I just don't see that happening.
</reply>
<reply id="cnhnyqb" author="rrockethr">
Well I don't think this it is required to be SWAT-level trained, it isn't hard to teach people if not sure just stay on the safe side and don't pull out the gun and shoot. It should be standard to pull out gun only when you are going to shoot, so if someone aims at you you know his intentions and everyone would know this so they won't be stupid and aiming at random people.
</reply>
<reply id="cnhoebk" author="AdmiralCrunch9">
Do you have any evidence to back up that assertion?  Because I've seen videos of people who just went through gun safety and combat training accidentally shoot themselves and each other with their paintball pistols when an ambush was simulated immediately after being told their course was over(can't remember where the videos were, I'll add them if I can find them later).

You seem to be handwaving how easy it would be to train people to go against their survival instincts and maintain a detached situation awareness in the face of death.  It takes months of training for both police and military before they are ready for active duty, and then they have constant ongoing training and evaluation to stay sharp.  Why would it be easier to train more civilians in less time?
</reply>
<reply id="cnhp5yk" author="rrockethr">
You need to consider that in shootings maybe even the death counts per shooting would be same or maybe even a bit higher, but if it decreased the number of shootings so that the total death count from shootings would decrease it would be a success - the role as a detractor is important.

It would be easier to train civilians because their role is fundamentally different from the police. They would be only in role of defenders, not chasing down criminals or anything police and SWAT do. They perhaps would rarely be able to stop the first deaths of a mass shooting, but should be more effecting in stopping subsequent deaths.
</reply>
<reply id="cnin1p0" author="AdmiralCrunch9">
You are assuming that spree shooters are going to rationally decide not to commit their crimes because they fear that they might be killed.  This is flawed logic.  Spree shooters are essentially always either killed or captured immediately following their crime in the culture that already exists.  Spree shooters know this before they do anything, and will often leave manifestos behind in anticipation of this.  Spree shooters either are irrational actors who believe themselves to be invincible or the exception, or they intend to die and want to take as many people as they can with them.  There have been many shootings in gun free areas, but there is no indication that the shooters would have just decided that they didn't want to commit mass murder because the chances of their survival or escape(which are minimal already) are lowered.
</reply>
<reply id="cninoeb" author="rrockethr">
I already said in different comments that this wouldn't be able to detract suicide attacks. However it should be able to to limit their effectivity.
</reply>
</thread>
