<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rosbp">
<title>CMV: Captions translating Arabic into English need to have "Allahu Akbar" displayed as "God is Greater" or "God is [the] Greatest".</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rosbp/cmv_captions_translating_arabic_into_english_need/</source>
<OP author="ChagSC">
This is a tough one to explain and may not fit this sub. Unfortunately I have no current examples to show you. 

I've noticed a few times on the news when they are showing Arabic translations into English, they translate everything except *Allahu Akbar*.

The main reason for this post is I was recently at the 9/11 Memorial Museum. One of the exhibits allows you to relive the experience of United Flight 93 in real time in a mini-theater. 

Part of this is listening to the hijackers speak, which they translate on the screen in English. Everything was translated into English except it displayed  *Allahu Akbar!* every time instead of the English translation. 

I am torn between feeling I am reading too much into it and it being a vehicle for propaganda against Islam. Hiding the fact that is it is Islam's praise of God, which is a rhetoric the religious West shares. 

Please CMV.
</OP>
<reply id="cnhv12w" author="gaviidae">
Sometimes words aren't fully translatable. Captioning "shit" as poop changes the meaning of the words. Shit is a curse word and doesn't really have a definition outside of that. Nigger is another word that if translated loses it's context. Captioning it as black person changes the meaning.

Allahu Akbar is similar in that those words are a phrase with meaning more than just the translated term. God is greatest isn't really a phrase in English so translating it that way changes things. 

Perhaps a better comparison is how we use the term Hallelujah. We use that word rather than translating it as Praise God. The specific wording doesn't matter it's that the phrase is praising God. Similar to Allahu Akbar.
</reply>
<reply id="cnhvo84" author="ChagSC">
That is something I had not been considering at all. Thanks. 

My concern there would be do people understand what *Allahu Akbar* means like they do *Hallelujah*. Though that is probably me over-extending the scope on this.  

I do not have the language expertise to comment on the integrity of translating *Allahu Ackbar* as *God is great* for examples like the United 93 exhibit. 
</reply>
<reply id="cnhw0tz" author="gaviidae">
It doesn't really matter what Allahu Akbar technically means though so not important for those that don't know. It's a phrase said by ~~terrorists~~Muslims that is all you really need to know to get what is happening.
</reply>
</thread>
