<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rnfn0">
<title>CMV: Explaining causation is not "blaming" the victim, and it's a worthwhile endeavor.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnfn0/cmv_explaining_causation_is_not_blaming_the/</source>
<OP author="cognitiveThizzonance">
I've been thinking about this issue for a while. The sentence in the title is an over-simplification of the view, but I'll elaborate more here. Technically it's a two-part view:
1) Explaining causation is not "blaming" the victim.
2) Explaining causation is a worthwhile endeavor.

I'd be happy to have either view changed - though if view 1 is changed, I'd probably change my mind on view 2. (It'll be easier to change my mind, in other words, about view 2 than view 1 – I’m not certain that it’s a worthwhile endeavor.)

Let me start off by saying that I understand the issues with victim blaming. There's an unfortunate tendency that I’ve noticed – particularly on the Internet, but occasionally in person as well – to blame the victims of terrible situations. We’re seeing it with responses to the police murders of black citizens (people trying to find a reason why the person was shot), and we see it with victims of rape (people say: you shouldn’t have been so drunk, or you shouldn’t have been in that area of town). There are all sorts of possible explanations as to why victim blaming occurs; one of the most convincing to me is that these occurrences cause a sort of cognitive dissonance in our minds where bad things happen to people who don’t deserve it. We like to think of our world as “just” in some way, so we come up with reasons why these people “Deserved” what they got. People rarely go so far as to say a woman “deserved” to be raped, but there’s a certain amount of “otherization” and lack of empathy that goes on – a sense that “well, that wouldn’t have happened to me, because I would’ve been more careful”. Additionally, it blames the victim for something that you should be blaming the perpetrator for. And that’s all bad.

On the other hand, it remains the case that the world is not a just place. Yes, we can work towards justice; we can work towards eliminating racism – overt or structural – and we can work towards a society in which women feel safer. And we absolutely should. In the meantime, however, it is important to understand lines of causation. I’m not going with a very complicated definition of causation here: basically a model in which two events or situations occur – A and B – and one event (B) would not have occurred the other (A) had not occurred. A caused B. (I’m aware there are logical or philosophical arguments against this model, but that’s not the view I’m trying to have changed; if you can make a compelling argument about the relevant views using those points, go ahead.)

The case I often think of concerns myself and friends of mine. I live in a large city. It is safe, for the most part, but there are certain areas that you shouldn’t walk in at night, because you might get mugged. Both myself and a friend of mine have been mugged while walking through these areas. The causation is: if we hadn’t been walking through those areas, we wouldn’t have gotten mugged. So we don’t walk through those areas at night anymore. It’s still possible that we’ll get mugged elsewhere, but in my mind, we’ve decreased our chances, which is a good thing. We didn’t deserve to get mugged before, but changing our behavior prevented us from getting mugged again.

Thus, explaining causation is not justification. It’s simply understanding the chain of events that led to another event.

Finally, my second view is that it’s a worthwhile endeavor. As I said, we avoid those dangerous areas at night now, and I feel we’ve decreased our chances of getting mugged. We understood the causation behind a negative situation, and we changed our behavior accordingly. Ideally, all areas would be safe to walk in, but they’re not, so we don’t walk in the unsafe areas anymore. Yes, this has mildly restricted our behavior – but it’s worth it to us, so that we don’t get mugged. 

I understood these are hairy issues, and maybe there’s a fine line between causation and justification. CMV.

EDIT: Fixed a sentence.


EDIT 2: Thank you - these have been really interesting and illuminating discussions, and forced me to reconsider the nuances of my view. I plan to give out more Deltas, because the latter part of my view has been changed somewhat. I don't think it's always a "worthwhile endeavor" - especially in cases of sexual assault, there's an unfortunate tendency of victims to blame themselves, and "explaining causation" to them doesn't really serve any purpose other than to increase unnecessary and unjustified guilt on their part. Many of these situations demand care and compassion. 

As far as "part 1" of my view goes, I still stand by my original statement. Granted, people have pointed out inconsistencies in the term "causation" - but as I said, I'm not really trying to have a discussion about causation as a concept. I understand that it's very complex, and of course many factors go into a certain outcome. I am well aware of probabilistic models of events/outcomes; my point was never to say that "avoid certain areas means you won't get mugged", or something like that. It concerned a marginal decrease of risk - a change in probability. Furthermore, the point itself was actually that "explaining causation is not victim blaming", and this view has not been addressed sufficiently. I've changed my view to the point that I don't think "explaining causation" is always the appropriate response (particularly in traumatic cases like sexual assault). I do still think it's often important to explain causation before the fact, as some users have suggested as an alternative, simply to give people a good idea of what precautions they might want to take. Most specifically, no one has really addressed this notion of causation vs. justification. One person has said they're the same thing, but not really offered an explanation for that. 

At any rate, I've enjoyed reading the responses so far; I'm aware this is a sensitive issue, and I'm glad discussions have remained pretty civil.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnhiymu" author="gomboloid">
your claim here is one i agree with, but i have to add a caveat that you haven't: if a victim of some offense had any role in its cause, you should **never explain that causation to someone who doesn't know you and respect your opinion**.

if your best friend got mugged walking that route, and you told him 'hey, this happened to me, too - i've avoided going there in the future' - then that could be a productive discussion.

but if it's 'joe random' on the internet that this happened to, you are acti vely making the problem worse by trying to explain causation. joe random doesn't know you and will most likely just get angry at you, further reducing joe random's belief in the truth or willing to listen to anyone saying that to him. if someone on the internet tells joe random what caused the problem, and then joe random hears 'it is your fault', he's not going to listen to anyone he thinks is telling him the same thing, even if it's his best friend.
</reply>
<reply id="cnhju0d" author="cognitiveThizzonance">
That's a very good point, and I think it's more related to conversational pragmatics or context. As you say, it's important to keep in mind the situation or relationship you have with the speaker. It's always harder to hear something if it's from someone you perceive as from an "out-group". So, although explaining causation is not justifying an outcome, certain people may see it that way and think you are being antagonistic, and this prevents a productive discussion. 

Out of curiosity, what do you think is the proper course of action in those situations? Simply to remain silent and not offer advice? 
</reply>
<reply id="cnhk9cn" author="gomboloid">
&gt; what do you think is the proper course of action in those situations?

. if you'd like to prevent joe random from getting hurt again, i'd suggest that your odds of really influencing the outcome of that situation one way or the other are so small that trying to interfere in any way isn't the best way of going about that.


"damn, that sucks" goes a crazy long way towards building trust with someone, though. if you say that, and the other guy keeps talking, then you may have a chance to use this established trust to offer a suggestion, but it's risky.

i mean, i'm here responding to strangers on the internet - so clearly i don't follow my own advice - but i've learned through my experience that trying to influence people i know directly and who seem to trust me is really freaking hard; influencing a stranger who's upset, and trying to change that - i have no idea how to do that reliably. 
</reply>
<reply id="cnhkmvi" author="cognitiveThizzonance">
Good point. I think demonstrating empathy for the situation is the most important thing, as you say.
</reply>
</thread>
