<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rmy6e">
<title>CMV: Philosophy has no tangible value as an academic field of study.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rmy6e/cmv_philosophy_has_no_tangible_value_as_an/</source>
<OP author="RazzzerBlade">
As an independent form of study, philosophy doesn't seem to have any practical applications. What value does philosophy have in the modern age, right now, aside from contemplating things. Is it truly worth it to invest a significant amount of time and money studying this field? 

There do not seem to be any tangible applications or appreciable benefits from studying philosophy aside from personal growth and the expansion of one's intellectual perspective, which I argue can be gained without studying philosophy in a rigorously academic manner.  

I often have read the argument that it is impossible to argue that philosophy is useless without using philosophy, or something along those lines.

I acknowledge this. Yes, I am engaging in the use of philosophy right now, at this very moment. However, this does not provide an argument as to why it would be worthwhile to STUDY philosophy. 

What do you gain from studying philosophy that could not be gained from thoughtful introspection? 

Certainly, important tools have originated from philosophical study, such as the scientific method, and science could be described as a subset of philosophy itself but that isn't an argument against the lack of tangible benefits to be gained from studying philosophy.

You don't need to study philosophy to become a capable scientist. You shouldn't need to study philosophy to cultivate a reasonable set of moral principles, or to be thoughtful about the circumstances and situations you encounter in your life. 

EDIT: I didn't expect so many answers! I'll try to read them all before I get too tired.

_____


&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnhcrsp" author="turole">
Let's say I want to ban abortion and have what looks like a very good philosophical argument supporting my position. Prove that I'm wrong (or vice versa if you're pro-life).

I want to introduce placebos into a doctors prescription repetoire. Is this ok? Based on what principles. I have a solid argument for why it's ok, as an imaginary policy maker I need a good argument showing I'm wrong.

Hell, to take it to extremes I want to own other people as slaves. Why shouldn't I?

The continued study of philosophy gives more insight and more power to arguments for and against the above arguments. Saying "I feel like abortion is ok through thoughtful introspection" doesn't actually help formulate convincing arguments to influence what we should actually do.
</reply>
<reply id="cnhe0wb" author="RazzzerBlade">
People are fully capable of forming well-structured arguments without having to study philosophy, though. 
People who study philosophy can form well-structured arguments, certainly, but not everyone who forms well-structured arguments necessarily studied philosophy or even needed to. Frankly, few of the people who I know who are capable of doing such have done so.
</reply>
<reply id="cnhgvae" author="turole">
People are capable of forming well structured arguments, but there might be major flaws in them without philosophical study. I'm not arguing that philosophers own these arguments, I am arguing that a philosopher is going to be better educated on past and current arguments and is more able to establish the strength of propositions.

I'll use myself as an example. I entered a debate subreddit a long while ago *thinking* I had good arguments. I found out rather quickly that I was an idiot on philosophical arguments regarding religion. Through reading professionals, taking a university level course in it, and studying older arguments I am now slightly less of an idiot (still not as well informed as many though). The same, I think, can be said for many people in many different arguments. All of the people you know can probably create good sounding arguments, but put them in a room for 20 minutes with an opposing philosopher and they would likely find out that their argument has been done before and has been thoroughly shown to be bad.

So yes, anyone can make an argument. Not everyone can make a well informed and good quality argument that doesn't have any holes in it. That's where philosophy comes in, they poke holes in each other ideas and improve upon them with the possibility of them having major effects on policy or individuals.

Edit: Not -&gt; now.
</reply>
</thread>
