<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rmwcd">
<title>CMV: Freedom of speech is being taken too far</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rmwcd/cmv_freedom_of_speech_is_being_taken_too_far/</source>
<OP author="5skandas">
In the last few weeks we've had two huge events happen in the world, both of which were caused by matters relating to "freedom of speech." The first being the hacking of Sony over The Interview, and today the shooting at the offices of a satirical magazine in Paris. I certainly value our free speech but to me there is a clear line between exercising your first amendment right ("President Obama sucks!" etc) and doing things that are known to be offensive to other cultures (Satirical cartoons of prophets, assassinating leaders, etc).

Perhaps this is a bad analogy - but if you say something antagonizing to a bully and you get your ass kicked, you should have anticipated that outcome.
</OP>
<reply id="cnhcoug" author="dtsjr">
&gt; ...there is a clear line between exercising your first amendment right and doing things that are known to be offensive to other cultures...

This is the error you've made, and it's a common one. 

The First Amendment protects against *governmental* interference with your speech. It doesn't give you consequence-free speech, but rather freedom from being restricted by the government. If you say dumb things and pay a non-governmental price, that has nothing to do with the First Amendment. Once the US government starts restricting some offensive-to-other-cultures speech, you've created a classic slippery slope.

Marc Randazza is a notable First Amendment attorney in Nevada. He discussed a kerfluffe with musings of Rush Limbaugh not too long ago. [This article that he wrote is helpful.](http://www.cnn.com/2012/03/12/opinion/randazza-limbaugh-speech/)

If something I've said hurts your feelings, then too bad so sad. If I think your religion is a joke, then deal with it. The cure for offensive speech is more speech, not bombings or violence or censorship of the offensive speech.

Edit: Typo
</reply>
<reply id="cnhcwka" author="5skandas">
Damn, you're right. I totally overlooked that when posting this. Although I did make an ignorant mistake, I will say however that I was inspired to make this post because when I hear from people all the time is that America's a 'free nation' so therefore we can say and do whatever the fuck we want without repercussion... 'Cause we're America.
</reply>
<reply id="cnhd436" author="dtsjr">
If you say FUCK ALL N***ERS loudly over the public address repeatedly at your job, you will probably lose your job. The government can't stop you from being a racist dumbass, but private entities can punish you.

If you say or write stupid things, you can be subject to public ridicule. There are consequences for actions, just not governmental interference.

You really should read that CNN op/ed I linked. It really helps clarify what it means to be a First Amendment attorney.

The "We're America" bravado with respect to freedom of speech can be confusing to non-Americans. I'm thrilled and proud that I can write and say whatever I want with essential impunity from the government. (That's with very narrow limitations, of course - I can't blog about wanting to kill a politician without a visit from the government, for example.)
</reply>
</thread>
