<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rkzen">
<title>CMV: Eugenics isn't all that bad... And we don't even have to kill anyone for it</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rkzen/cmv_eugenics_isnt_all_that_bad_and_we_dont_even/</source>
<OP author="Seventh_______">
Okay, I'm talking about making the human race smarter, forever.
Intelligence is at least partially genetic and therefore passed down by parents, yes? [Yes.](http://www.the-scientist.com/?articles.view/articleNo/40459/title/Inherited-Intelligence/)

So, what if, instead of killing off the less-intelligent people (I'm against killing. Of most things.) we just limit offspring?

For example, we could use the IQ scale (for want of a better intelligence measure) to determine the number of offspring a person should be able to genetically contribute to.
Like, round the IQ to the nearest multiple of 50, then divide by 50, and that's the number of offspring you're allowed to create.

So someone with near average intelligence (near 100 IQ, 75-124) would have their IQ rounded to 100 and then divided by 50 to make 2 offspring. 
The total offspring is presumably equal to the number of people who contributed to it. A man and a woman with average IQ can have two children (not each.) and sustain their population.

Conversely, really above average IQs of 125-174 can contribute genetically towards 3 children... and so on.

This would eventually make the human race smarter, and therefore more likely to survive and advance the human race. 

I know this would be a bitch to implement and it's near impossible to actually do, but I'm just looking at the concept. I know the IQ test has its faults and every policy can be abused... I know all that.

Exceptions would be made when you accidentally have twins which causes you to go over your limit, or etc. (If a mother can make 2, and has twins, she can't make more, but if she already has one and has twins after one which makes 3, we're not gonna kill one)

Perhaps if you have a major, heritable health issue your IQ has 25 subtracted from it before being rounded? Or maybe weighted differently, like extremely high chance of cancer (almost 100 percent or something) takes off more... Something like that.

Much better than "Kill off those with IQ less than 80"

I wouldn't mind a smarter human race...

EDIT: **I am trying to argue that this process, if not abused, if followed by the people, and if we found an increasingly accurate measure of intelligence, would be ultimately a good thing to advance the human race.**

EDIT 2: "**It looks to me like you've made so many exceptions to your main view that you aren't looking to have your view changed. I'd like to talk about the title of your post, but if you have to make so many exceptions to your view, then it seems you already know it's incorrect.**" -nikeson
I suppose that's true, now....
_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cngvgy6" author="looklistencreate">
Your responses to these questions have me wondering exactly what your proposed policy would be. You back away at any enforcement mechanism because the problems with those are pretty obvious and gruesome. Without that, though, all you're saying is that it would be nice if the people with the best genes wanted to have the most children. That's not a controversial view at all, and it's definitely not what eugenics means.

Even if the government were to encourage such behavior without enforcement, there would be somewhat of a backlash. Think of the message that's sending to people with low IQ or genetic diseases. "You are undesirable and our country doesn't want any more of you." The positive end, enticing couples with good genes to have more children, would be about as effective as population increasing measures are in countries like Denmark, Russia and Japan.

Lastly, let's not forget that many people have overcome being born to less intelligent and successful parents. All of us have ancestors who wouldn't make the cut. 
</reply>
<reply id="cngw1uq" author="Seventh_______">
I wouldn't propose a policy, I don't trust myself to see all flaws in a policy... 
&gt;Eh? I'm specifically trying to argue mostly against people who think that eugenics is wrong in any flavor... Using hypotheticals to point out a specific /not wrong/ flavor would prove them wrong... So I don't really agree that it's pointless...  

^me earlier. I don't plan on becoming a policy maker.

"What eugenics means"
-Oops, the definition says "practice" as well as "belief"
Well I believe in it at least.

I'm not saying that " it would be nice if the people with the best genes wanted to have the most children." (though I agree with that)
I'm saying that a proposed law, if implemented correctly, that limits reproduction based on actual intelligence, would be a good thing. Some people think eugenics is "bad terrible hitler"... Not so. Eugenics is totally controversial.

Ah, your second paragraph has a point. But I would hope that as genetic engineering becomes more advanced we can cherrypick (or inverse cherrypick) things like "not having extreme high risks of cancer"
I don't know who "people with heritable, extreme high risks of cancer" are trying to kid if they say their genes aren't undesirable (because they are)

And maybe it's not kind for sending that message to low IQ people (again, I would refrain from using IQ) but if it means advancing the human race by who knows how much, I'd be willing to dent a few feelings....

I don't really know about those population increasing measures, btw. I don't feel like google, I'll look up later.

But are the genes from the ancestors who wouldn't make the cut manifested? Or are they bred out, maybe through natural selection even?




</reply>
<reply id="cngwrgu" author="looklistencreate">
So without any implementation, you're just wishing that people followed your formula and had more than two kids only if they have above-average genes. I'm sure most people would agree that it would be a good thing if people with unequivocally bad genes just didn't feel like having children. That's not a controversial opinion.

I know you don't want to worry about implementation, but I can't see any possible enforcement mechanism that doesn't interfere with peoples' basic rights. If two consenting and able adults want to have a child and keep him, any government that doesn't let them is doing something horribly wrong. This is a direct consequence of your CMV and has to be addressed.

I don't see how this could be "implemented correctly." By its very nature there is no way to implement this that isn't worse than our current system.
</reply>
</thread>
