<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rkplw">
<title>CMV: "What is your favorite X" does not stimulate interesting discussion and shouldn't be allowed on strictly moderated forums/subreddits.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rkplw/cmv_what_is_your_favorite_x_does_not_stimulate/</source>
<OP author="alexskc95">
Like "What is your favorite line from a TV show" or "What is your favorite movie poster."

These threads always get hugely upvoted and loads of comments because everyone likes to share things they like, but they never really produce anything meaningful. Just people gushing about "OMG X IS SO AMAZING."

On top of this, since everybody feels that their favorite is more important than everybody else's, you'll get a bunch of top-level replies with very little discussion beyond them. If there are replies, they usually just agree with the above poster. "OMG YES I KNOW." Nobody wants to be the dissent in a "positivity thread," or they just haven't heard of your favorite thing and aren't going to watch a 2h movie/play a 50h game/whatever for every single response in that thread, anyway.

There's generally very little to learn from things that are done *well.* The exception is multiple viewpoints or interpretations of something, but you can only really get that if you have a large number of people discussing the same thing, which these kinds of threads very much discourage.


_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cngxqi0" author="jay520">
&gt; These threads always get hugely upvoted and loads of comments because everyone likes to share things they like, but they never really produce anything meaningful.

You use the word "meaning" here. However, your post writes as if you "meaning" is an objective quality with set-in-stone values. What one person finds meaningful or interesting is there own damn opinion. You may not find threads where you don't "learn" anything to lack meaning, and that's fine. We shouldn't have to force you to read those threads. 

But what right do you have to prevent millions of other people from reading and discussing those threads? If those people find meaning in such threads, then what right do you have to put an end to their enjoyment? I personally don't find any meaning in threads that discuss who would win in a hypothetical fight between Mike Tyson and Muhammad Ali. However, if there are people out there who legitimately enjoy discussing that topic, then there's no reason for me to stop them from doing so.
</reply>
<reply id="cngzhqn" author="alexskc95">
But that logic, you can just as easily say /r/gaming is full of meaning! And so is /r/atheism! Clearly, people see meaning in all those upvoted threads, otherwise they wouldn't be at the top!

That's why I specified "on strictly moderated forums/subreddits." On those websites, the leadership takes control and defines an (I'll admit, arbitrary) line as to what is and isn't acceptable, because frankly, the masses are quite often morons.

My argument is that the line should generally be drawn to also exclude such threads. If people want to create and respond to bad threads because "muh freedom of speech," there's plenty of other places on the internet for them to do that.
</reply>
<reply id="cngzlld" author="jay520">
You've done absolutely nothing to counter my argument. All you've done was repeat your original argument using different words. *Why* should the "leadership" draw the line to determine that such threads are unacceptable? If the leadership on a "strictly moderated forum" decides that such threads are acceptable, then what is the problem, and why should they change?
</reply>
<reply id="cngzyyg" author="alexskc95">
I already explained in the OP what such threads generally look like, and why.

The "default state" for a conversation is not "meaningful." It is "meaningless." If you want to claim that a conversation is of value, it is on you to prove that, not on me to disprove it.

You could make the argument that by that logic the "appropriateness" of conversations should be decided on a case-by-case bases, but that's not going to going to happen because of personal biases and because it's simply unfeasible.

I argue there should be a blanket ban on such threads because they haven't demonstrated any meaning, and appear frequently enough that a policy against them would make sense. If you can demonstrate that these threads do have a purpose and serve the best interests of the community, then I'll back down from that position.
</reply>
<reply id="cnh05vo" author="jay520">
Firstly, as I've already stated, "meaning" is subjective. What you find meaningful others find meaningless, and vice-versa.

Secondly, and most importantly, meaning is irrelevant. The purpose of threads is not to create meaning (whatever that even means). It's to serve as a platform for conversation, meaningful or not. You have absolutely no basis for preventing people from enjoying a discussion just because you *personally* find it uninteresting or meaningless.

What you're basically saying is equivalent to seeing a group of strangers on the street having a personal conversation, and then calling the cops to prevent the discussion because you find it meaningless or uninteresting.
</reply>
<reply id="cnh0lqa" author="alexskc95">
Plenty of subs do ban specific types of conversation, though. /r/games [has a fairly extensive list of disallowed content](https://www.reddit.com/r/Games/wiki/rules). /r/AskHistorians [is even harsher](https://www.reddit.com/r/AskHistorians/wiki/rules).

They're banned because they are contrary to the spirit of the sub and do not produce content that the leadership believes to be "meaningful."

I'm saying that strictly moderated subs, ie **communities whose goal it is to produce meaningful content** should ban those particular types of threads. The same way /r/games bans off-topic film references or /r/netsec bans questions.

I get that meaning is subjective, however, if any member of the community can make any kind of case for why something is useful to the community, then it should probably stay. You don't respond with "why should there be questions on /r/askhistorians?" with "well, meaning is subjective, so let's just allow everything." You respond with "the entire point of the sub is to ask questions."

Meaningless is the default state. If a thread appears frequently enough such that policy against it is considered, then you have to make a case for why it should stay, not a case for why it should be gotten rid of.
</reply>
<reply id="cnh10ws" author="jay520">
&gt; I'm saying that strictly moderated subs, ie communities whose goal it is to produce meaningful content should ban those particular types of threads. The same way /r/games bans off-topic film references or /r/netsec bans questions.

Yes, but the leaders of those subs get to decide what "meaning" is. Therefore, if they decide that "What is your favorite X" threads are meaningful, then they should be allowed, even if on a strictly moderated sub. The leaders get to decide what the spirit of the sub is. They get to decide what the point of the sub is. The fact that the sub is "strictly" moderated only tells us that *some* types of threads are prohibited; it does not tell us *which* type of threads prohibited. Thus, just because a sub is "strictly" moderated does not imply that "What is your favorite X" threads should be prohibited.
</reply>
<reply id="cnh191c" author="alexskc95">
Exactly right.

And I'm criticizing some moderator's decisions not to do that and making my case for why they should. It is absolutely their right to allow such threads. But that doesn't mean that that is what they should be doing.
</reply>
<reply id="cnh1erw" author="jay520">
Let's recall an excerpt from your earlier post:

&gt; I get that meaning is subjective, however, if any member of the community can make any kind of case for why something is useful to the community, then it should probably stay. You don't respond with "why should there be questions on /r/askhistorians?" with "well, meaning is subjective, so let's just allow everything." You respond with "the entire point of the sub is to ask questions."

By your own words, you acknowledge that "meaning" is subjective and is *defined* by the leadership of a sub. Therefore, if the leadership allows certain threads, then those threads, by definition, are meaningful and should be allowed.
</reply>
<reply id="cnh1p3y" author="alexskc95">
Yep. The problem is that what is meaningful often isn't the OP, but rather the responses and discussion that ensues. The leadership may believe that certain threads are *conductive* to what conforms to *their vision* of what meaningful content looks like, but they can be wrong.

My argument is that the "discussion" that "What is your favorite X" threads create is counter to the *vision* of the majority of moderators.
</reply>
</thread>
