<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rkplw">
<title>CMV: "What is your favorite X" does not stimulate interesting discussion and shouldn't be allowed on strictly moderated forums/subreddits.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rkplw/cmv_what_is_your_favorite_x_does_not_stimulate/</source>
<OP author="alexskc95">
Like "What is your favorite line from a TV show" or "What is your favorite movie poster."

These threads always get hugely upvoted and loads of comments because everyone likes to share things they like, but they never really produce anything meaningful. Just people gushing about "OMG X IS SO AMAZING."

On top of this, since everybody feels that their favorite is more important than everybody else's, you'll get a bunch of top-level replies with very little discussion beyond them. If there are replies, they usually just agree with the above poster. "OMG YES I KNOW." Nobody wants to be the dissent in a "positivity thread," or they just haven't heard of your favorite thing and aren't going to watch a 2h movie/play a 50h game/whatever for every single response in that thread, anyway.

There's generally very little to learn from things that are done *well.* The exception is multiple viewpoints or interpretations of something, but you can only really get that if you have a large number of people discussing the same thing, which these kinds of threads very much discourage.


_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cngtarp" author="AdmiralCrunch9">
"What is you're favorite X?" can be a great way to find new X's that you hadn't heard about yet, or were on the fence about.  Starting a new TV show for example, can be a huge time commitment, but if you see a particular show popping up at the top of those kinds of lists repeatedly, it can be a good indicator that a particular show might be worth your time.  

These kind of posts are particularly helpful when the writer gives a good rundown of other X's they've liked in the past to give context to potential readers to compare their own tastes with, or information like "don't let the first season put you off, it gets better," or "get this translation, it really preserves the meter," or what have you.

Now, many people are not going to write these kind of responses, but that is a reflection on the responders not on the validity of the question.  Even if a majority of the responses to a question framed that way are low effort or value, I will often find some good suggestions or write ups in them too.  I think it's better to focus on the real problem of bad responses rather than on the questions that can prompt them.  I'd hate to have lost out on some of the great suggestions(Better Off Ted, Kingkiller Chronicle, City of God) I've gotten over the years just because some people will also write contentless "X IS THE BEST" threads as well.
</reply>
<reply id="cngtoyt" author="alexskc95">
I have never had trouble finding things I'm interested in. When the internet is filled with film/book/music/whatever clubs, reviews, suggestion charts, recommendation algorithms, best-of lists, and communities specifically designed to find things you're interested in, I see no reason for someone to ask for *even more opinions.* The chances you won't find something you love are just about 0.
</reply>
<reply id="cnguchu" author="AdmiralCrunch9">
Those are all great ways to get suggestions, but how does the presence of other options for getting suggestions invalidate soliciting them from Reddit?  Algorithms, reviews and lists can't be interacted with in the same way that you can with other Redditers, and specialized communities are going to be more likely to have self selection prejudices that prevent you from getting introduced to things outside your wheelhouse or experience.

Beyond that, your original argument seemed to be about the utility of Reddit posts of this kind and a suggestion that they never offer anything of value, not whether or not they are the best or only source for suggestions.  Should we ban questions about recipes because there are websites devoted to cooking?  Should we ban /r/AskHistorians because better information might be gained from peer reviewed journals?  Just because something isn't a given person's preferred method of getting suggestions that doesn't mean that others should be banned from seeking suggestions in that way, or that they don't get what they're looking for when they do.
</reply>
<reply id="cngzbqy" author="alexskc95">
No, but I think we should ban suggestion threads on /r/anime when /r/Animesuggest exists. Or on /r/movies when /r/MovieSuggestions exists. These are more likely to get you better suggestions, with better explanations as to why those particular suggestions are popular, while still maintaining all that community interaction and so on.

/r/AskHistorians has something peer reviewed journals lack: Interaction with actual historians who are actually familiar with what they're reading. What does /r/games have that /r/ShouldIbuythisgame or /r/gamingsuggestions seemingly lack?

Also, I remind you that this is about "what is your favorite X" threads. Not "What is a good X (for me)."

If your opinions are anything like mine, your taste is often very different from "most people" so asking for the generic most popular favorites is really pointless when compared to actual personal suggestions for you in particular. A generic "what is your favorite movies" will get the movies that everyone's already seen upvoted to the top. So really it's not much better than the IMDB top 100.
</reply>
<reply id="cnh0b7b" author="AdmiralCrunch9">
So the rules of what should and shouldn't be allowed on Reddit should conform to what is useful to you in particular?  I get that you don't think the threads will generally introduce you to anything you're interested in, but since is inherently based off of you being an outlier, I don't think that's really relevant to what the general population should or shouldn't be allowed to discuss.

Which leads me to the thing that those suggestion subs lack: users.  /r/movies has millions of users while /r/MovieSuggestions has 25,000.  That smaller community will get fewer responses, and will likely be tailored to a more niche audience.  That is fine if that's what someone is looking for but someone looking for a more populist take should have that option as well.

And I don't think you addressed the point that the issue you raise has less to do with the questions themselves and more to do with the responses they draw.  Why moderate the question when the less restrictive response of moderating the answers by requiring an explanation or background is available?  I still would probably not agree with that approach, but it seems more reasonable than banning Best Of threads if the people want to talk about that.
</reply>
<reply id="cnh0un1" author="alexskc95">
Nobody is "the general population." "The general population" is an *idea.* Everyone's an outlier. Going by averages, everyone in the US has just under five toes, is named James/Mary Smith, is between the ages of 25-44, makes $47k a year, and has seen all the movies on Wikipedia's highest grossing films list.

We're all outliers. Have you *ever* met a "normal person" in your life? Even one? Once? I sure haven't. The closest I've ever gotten were dumb first impressions.

And on top of this, these threads aren't even useful to "the average person" because "the average person" has already seen all the movies in that thread. Otherwise they wouldn't be upvoted. That's the real kicker. Relevant responses are hidden in favor of popular ones.
</reply>
<reply id="cnh18t6" author="AdmiralCrunch9">
&gt; If your opinions are anything like mine, your taste is often very different from "most people"

I'm just pointing out that if you're self identifying as someone who has very different taste from the norm, then maybe it's not reasonable to expect a general movie or book or whatever discussion sub to moderate itself in a way that caters to your tastes and content preferences, to the exclusion of a majority of its users.

As for the popular movie issue, no one has seen every popular movie, and no popular movie has been seen by everyone.  I'll grant you that at this point most people have probably made up their minds about if they're gonna check out this "The Dark Knight" all the kids are talking about, but I still see people getting convinced to check out The Godfather, or The Wire, or Buffy the Vampire Slayer pretty frequently even though those always show up at or near the top of those kind of lists.  And then you only need to scroll down a little to get to the things that have a significant fanbase but still haven't been experienced by most people.  Shows like Terriers and You're the Worst that aren't super successful but really strike a chord with most of the few people who see them pretty regularly get enough upvotes that you don't have to scroll too far to find them.

edit: added an embarrassing number of missing words
</reply>
<reply id="cnh1k1y" author="alexskc95">
I'm saying everyone has "different taste from the norm." The norm doesn't exist.

You're right that not every person has seen every popular movie, but most everyone has heard of every popular movie, and they can themselves decide if they want to see them. I still haven't seen Jaws. But I've definitely heard of it, it's become part of our "collective culture", and I'll probably end up actually seeing it some time, sooner or later.

Generic suggestions are something MAL or IMDB or whatever can pump out. You get review and explanations and top 100 lists and everything. Personal suggestions are what people are useful for.

Your entire argument seems to hinge on "well some people don't know that IMDB has a top 100."

Yes, they do. You're criticizing their intelligence if you think otherwise.
</reply>
</thread>
