<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rkjr3">
<title>CMV: Irony aside, most people that post in CMV are uneducated, and changing their view on one point won't solve this overall problem</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rkjr3/cmv_irony_aside_most_people_that_post_in_cmv_are/</source>
<OP author="1millionbucks">
There are some instances, yes where controversial topics are discussed here and people are actually interested in hearing the opposite side. I consider myself one of those people, and was initially driven to this subreddit in the hope that I would meet other people like myself that were posting here to educate themselves. The type of man that reads a book that argues against a position he already holds, in the hopes that he can understand the entire issue in a great light.

But far and away, this is not the case. Some of the posts on here include logical fallacies even in the titles: yesterday's [atheism post](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rfea1/) used a strawman fallacy in the title to misrepresent their own position to make it easier to defend in a religion vs. athiesm debate. The OP, if you read that post, was by and large not interested in changing his opinion, and this is true of the *vast majority* of posts that come through here.

And the problem is this: it is a tremendous waste of time for every knowledgable person that posts answers in here. A lot of times, the posts are not controversial: they are simply the product of stupidity. There are a thousand places, a million internet hits, which one can browse to discover facts on the athiesm/religion debate and even the specific subtopic that was discussed yesterday. An educated person, or rather, a person seeking to educate himself, would have simply utilized this vast body of resources rather than take time to create a new resource.

Additionally, the people that tend to post in this subreddit post on this subreddit have a certain mindset already, even before submitting. Go ahead, think of something you believe that is controversial and click "Submit CMV." Your mind will already be working to inhibit opposing opinions and you will be clinging harder than ever to the bulwarks of your argument. The fact of the matter is this: it takes considerable effort to open one's mind, even on things that are not of great consequence. And most people are simply unable to accomplish this.

Thanks for your replies. I intend to reply to each response to my original post, albeit maybe not today, and I hope to award many deltas for your efforts.

Quick edit: I realized I didn't address the second part of my title claim. Albert Einstein said that 2 things are limitless: the universe and human stupidity. For every stupid person that posts on this sub to address one point of their lack of knowledge, there are foreseeably dozens more points of misunderstanding that remain. What is the overall aim of this subreddit? To educate one at a time, indeed. But on issues that can be solved via Google search or the opening of a book, how can one fill the infinite pit of human stupidity? Only controversial issues, where both opinions are agreed to be at least understandable and held widely by educated people, should be allowed. This is a real debate: anything else is just convincing a stupid person of something that they fail to understand.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cngqwb0" author="bubi09">
First off, as per rule E of submission rules, you need to reply within 3 hours of posting the thread. 

I immediately disagree with the statement in your title. Where are your sources for the claim that most people that post are uneducated? I've seen some fascinating discussions here and some posts that couldn't have been written by an uneducated person. Also, what is your definition of uneducated? 

I agree that most people here don't want their opinion changed. I posted once and went into it fully determined there was no way my opinion would be changed. Lo and behold, not half an hour later I gave away a delta. And I think that happens a lot, even if some people aren't familiar with the delta system so they admit you changed their view, but don't actually award a delta. 

&gt; it is a tremendous waste of time for every knowledgable person that posts answers in here. 

I disagree. I am knowledgeable in some areas, but I'm definitely a very opinionated person. I can honestly say that this sub is godsend for me. It is, without a doubt, my favorite sub here. Why? Because I love discussing things, especially controversial ones. I love debating and I do really like the challenge of changing one's opinion. 

I am currently involved in a CMV that has been going on for a week now. A whole week the OP and I have been going back and forth on a topic of their choosing, neither of us budging, but both (if I may say so myself) presenting their cases in an eloquent and smart way. I haven't been successful in changing their view or getting a delta, but I think this sub goes beyond that. My eyes have been opened to the way the OP lives his life and sees certain things, even if he's on the complete opposite side of me when it comes to it. And that's an enriching experience. 

&gt; For every stupid person that posts on this sub to address one point of their lack of knowledge, there are foreseeably dozens more points of misunderstanding that remain. What is the overall aim of this subreddit? To educate one at a time, indeed.

I can honestly say that educating people here is secondary to me; it's an afterthought. Yes, it's nice to know I've opened someone's eyes to something and that I've given them a piece of knowledge, but this sub mainly serves as a form of mental exercise to me. I'm practicing in expressing my views in a well thought-out manner, I'm learning how to support my claims with arguments, I'm learning about diversity and respecting other-people's opinions. Everything else is a bonus. 

I see this sub as a vessel through which *I do something for myself* while you see it as something where *you do something for others* (mainly trying to educate stupid people in vain, if I'm getting it correctly). 

Lastly (I have to run now, hopefully we can continue later), why isn't this enough for you? Why is getting a delta more important than bettering yourself in a smart and challenging way? 

Also, yes, you may say that the original idea of the sub was to have people come in with an open mind and even a wish to have their opinion changed, but...the original idea behind upvotes and downvotes was much different than what it is today as well. Doesn't mean the whole experience is lessened by it. It can still be worth a lot. 
</reply>
<reply id="cngrk8i" author="1millionbucks">
&gt; what is your definition of uneducated?

Uneducated, in this post, refers to a person that is either unwilling or not intelligent enough to find the answer to their question, when the answer to that question is simple to find.

&gt; I love debating and I do really like the challenge of changing one's opinion.

Fair enough, to each their own. I often find myself telling a person the correct answer to a question based on truth that I know, and that person argues against me. My field of expertise tends to be psychology and the theories of what powers the mind. This is a difficult subject for everyone, but it is frustrating to inform a person of the correct, factual answer as accepted by the scientific community to their question, and be rejected because they cannot understand it. That person is uneducated, and additionally, has failed to seek out answers to their question before posting here.

&gt; I do something for myself while you see it as something where you do something for others

Again, very fair point.

&gt; Why is getting a delta more important than bettering yourself in a smart and challenging way?

I often comment when I have a direct, factual answer to the question. When these answers are rejected, it is not that I am wrong, or the issue is controversial and has multiple facets that are each correct. It is that the other person either cannot accept, is unwilling to accept or is not intelligent enough to accept the true statements and answers that I have provided. It is not about the deltas, per se: I should be awarded a delta because I provided the correct answer, but it is more about the frustration of *not* getting the delta because the person cannot understand or comprehend the answer.
</reply>
<reply id="cnh0nte" author="bubi09">
&gt; a person that is either unwilling or not intelligent enough to find the answer to their question, when the answer to that question is simple to find.

But what's the point then? 95% of all questions posted on some of the most popular subs out there like ELI5, askscience or askhistorians is stuff you can find yourself with a bit of googling. But the point of Reddit and these subs is to get engage the community, let the knowledgeable ones share their knowledge (and show off a bit, let's be real) and let others learn (especially those who wouldn't have ever thought to be curious about this certain thing in the first place). 

See, I generally go into the more opinion-based threads, both for the challenge and to make up for the fact that there aren't that many topics out there where I can claim to be an expert. And yes, I've posted hard facts and got dismissed. I've also had OPs tell me point blank that I changed part of their opinion or that they see my point and still not get a delta. Some of them don't get the rules of the sub, others just forget or are assholes. Even in your reply to me, in two different places you acknowledged my point and it's clear you see where I'm coming from. Did you give me a delta? I'm not fishing for one, I'm just making a point. You yourself did the very thing you complain about others doing. 

And on the whole topic of deltas and stuff, I think objectively we should all agree that they don't matter that much. That what truly matters is we put ourselves out there, shared something we wanted to and moved on. But we're human and we like deltas, upvotes and gold because we like feeling validated and we like it when people agree with us. No point in lying about it; I'll be the first to say that I get a bit giddy every time a post of mine gets a few upvotes and that it upsets me at least a little bit when I get downvoted. It's how it goes. And I know it's only worse when it happens when I'm right. 

But I also think there's more to it than this. That 160K people subbed for a reason and that people who post every day and engage others in some very smart discussion (most of the time) are most definitely not wasting their time. 
</reply>
</thread>
