<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rkjr3">
<title>CMV: Irony aside, most people that post in CMV are uneducated, and changing their view on one point won't solve this overall problem</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rkjr3/cmv_irony_aside_most_people_that_post_in_cmv_are/</source>
<OP author="1millionbucks">
There are some instances, yes where controversial topics are discussed here and people are actually interested in hearing the opposite side. I consider myself one of those people, and was initially driven to this subreddit in the hope that I would meet other people like myself that were posting here to educate themselves. The type of man that reads a book that argues against a position he already holds, in the hopes that he can understand the entire issue in a great light.

But far and away, this is not the case. Some of the posts on here include logical fallacies even in the titles: yesterday's [atheism post](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rfea1/) used a strawman fallacy in the title to misrepresent their own position to make it easier to defend in a religion vs. athiesm debate. The OP, if you read that post, was by and large not interested in changing his opinion, and this is true of the *vast majority* of posts that come through here.

And the problem is this: it is a tremendous waste of time for every knowledgable person that posts answers in here. A lot of times, the posts are not controversial: they are simply the product of stupidity. There are a thousand places, a million internet hits, which one can browse to discover facts on the athiesm/religion debate and even the specific subtopic that was discussed yesterday. An educated person, or rather, a person seeking to educate himself, would have simply utilized this vast body of resources rather than take time to create a new resource.

Additionally, the people that tend to post in this subreddit post on this subreddit have a certain mindset already, even before submitting. Go ahead, think of something you believe that is controversial and click "Submit CMV." Your mind will already be working to inhibit opposing opinions and you will be clinging harder than ever to the bulwarks of your argument. The fact of the matter is this: it takes considerable effort to open one's mind, even on things that are not of great consequence. And most people are simply unable to accomplish this.

Thanks for your replies. I intend to reply to each response to my original post, albeit maybe not today, and I hope to award many deltas for your efforts.

Quick edit: I realized I didn't address the second part of my title claim. Albert Einstein said that 2 things are limitless: the universe and human stupidity. For every stupid person that posts on this sub to address one point of their lack of knowledge, there are foreseeably dozens more points of misunderstanding that remain. What is the overall aim of this subreddit? To educate one at a time, indeed. But on issues that can be solved via Google search or the opening of a book, how can one fill the infinite pit of human stupidity? Only controversial issues, where both opinions are agreed to be at least understandable and held widely by educated people, should be allowed. This is a real debate: anything else is just convincing a stupid person of something that they fail to understand.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cngro6m" author="AzeTheGreat">
One of your points seemed to be that they shouldn't post because the counter arguments to their view are so easily available elsewhere.  However, I think you should consider the fact that changing one's mind is incredibly difficult, and often being forced to argue will be more successful than simply reading opposing viewpoints.  Thus, those people who *do* post here are the one's who want to put effort into their views, and maybe want them to change.  Those who only have the most superficial desire to change their views are the ones who look online and then simply dismiss the opposition as "wrong" without actually considering it. 
</reply>
<reply id="cngrzps" author="1millionbucks">
&gt; changing one's mind is incredibly difficult

Precisely why seeking out other sources first is a better idea. Super religious? Read a Dawkins book. Super atheist? I'm not sure where you would go but there are definitely books that support the idea of religion. The point is this: a book is far better at changing someone's mind than a commenter on the internet. It has been well thought out and edited and considered at length: the internet commenter is strength in numbers, and that is all.

&gt; who look online and then simply dismiss the opposition as "wrong" without actually considering it.

How is this different than reading the comments here and promptly dismissing them? Often, OPs will ignore and not quote any part of a replier's text, and simply comment the same logic they believed before; in effect, not acknowledge the replier. This is toxic to the subreddit, and it happens frequently in questions where the answer is readily accessible.
</reply>
<reply id="cngsgqo" author="AzeTheGreat">
&gt;Precisely why seeking out other sources first is a better idea...The point is this: a book is far better at changing someone's mind than a commenter on the internet. It has been well thought out and edited and considered at length: the internet commenter is strength in numbers, and that is all.

I would fundamentally disagree here.  First: plenty of books are not well thought out, and while standards are certainly higher than internet comments they can contain their fair share of issues.  Secondly, as you briefly mentioned yourself, it can be extremely difficult for someone who has only been exposed to a single view to actually know how and where to look for opposing viewpoints, thus allowing other people to present these is beneficial.  Finally, I disagree that reading a book is as effective at altering a viewpoint as an actual discussion.  Why?

When reading a book it is incredibly easy to simply look at the ideas and dismiss them as "wrong".  I already addressed this, but look at it in contrast to a discussion.  A book demands no response, the reader is free to simply skim over it.  Thus, if someone wants their viewpoint changed through a book they must constantly remind themselves not to just dismiss it.  In contrast, a discussion demands a response.  While it is certainly possible that people ignore the arguments and simply restate their points (as you stated), the form of the information means that they have to give it *more* consideration because they have to respond/refute it in some way.

In essence, I would argue that nothing is really great at changing viewpoints, but discussions are inherently better at reminding people that they *want* to change, and forcing thought processes that are more likely to cause a change in opinion.

&gt;An educated person, or rather, a person seeking to educate himself, would have simply utilized this vast body of resources rather than take time to create a new resource.

My argument is that it is entirely possible that these people *are* seeking to educate themselves, *do* know about other sources, but also mnow that just observing opposing viewpoints will never be enough to actually change their opinion.  Thus, they come here, hoping for discussion to promote change.
</reply>
<reply id="cngt0v8" author="1millionbucks">
&gt; plenty of books are not well thought out

Yes, avoid them! Book reviews are a thing! Just because there are bad books does not mean that there are not good ones. And the good ones are vastly, vastly better than internet comments.

&gt; it can be extremely difficult for someone who has only been exposed to a single view to actually know how and where to look for opposing viewpoints

Nonsense, this imaginary person is an idiot. If you can name one common issue that could foreseeably be seen on this subreddit, that you have no idea what an opposing viewpoint could even be, please name it.

&gt; When reading a book it is incredibly easy to simply look at the ideas and dismiss them as "wrong".

Never had this experience. Not that I haven't seen a book be wrong: just that I have never not even considered the idea. And if such a person exists that does this, that dismisses a book, which devotes pages to arguing a single idea, he will gain nothing from an internet comment.

If you are reading the book to have your opinion changed, then you will not simply dismiss everything in it. If you do, you are just wasting your own time.

&gt; a discussion demands a response

Fair enough, but a discussion has its own weaknesses. If the opposing person argues a point badly, then the person is less likely to agree with it than if they had read the book and heard the argument in a well though out way.

&gt; discussions are inherently better

To each their own, but I cannot agree with this. Books go much further in depth than a discussion, or in Reddit's case, a series of discussions, ever can.
</reply>
<reply id="cngtqzb" author="AzeTheGreat">
&gt;If the opposing person argues a point badly, then the person is less likely to agree with it than if they had read the book and heard the argument in a well though out way.

Yes, avoid them! Comment karma is a thing! Just because there are bad comments does not mean that there are not good ones.  (I do not do this to mock you, just to point out that your counter argument applies equally to your argument.)

&gt;And the good ones are vastly, vastly better than internet comments.

Good books are absolutely superior to internet comments in terms of content and depth of exploration, there is no contention there.  However, it is not the content I am worried about but the form in which the argument is presented.

&gt;Nonsense, this imaginary person is an idiot.

Is having your view changed, hopefully for the better, some priveledge reserved for those in the upper echelons of intelligence?  Is there some issue with someone who isn't intelligent, who may even have trouble arguing, trying to see different viewpoints?

&gt; If you can name one common issue that could foreseeably be seen on this subreddit, that you have no idea what an opposing viewpoint could even be, please name it.

I'll concede here since I couldn't think of anything.  I suppose I was approaching it more from the perspective of niche views where searching for the alternative isn't likely to return anything; in retrospect this doesn't fit the common aspect that you desired.

However, I would like to offer an additional point: if someone has not been succesfully swayed by any of the sources they have read, if all of the common arguments have "failed", then it becomes increasingly difficult to find different and novel arguments that might sway their view.  CMV offers a platform where, due to the many people involved, these novel arguments are more likely to emerge, sheerly through statistics. 

&gt;If you are reading the book to have your opinion changed, then you will not simply dismiss everything in it. If you do, you are just wasting your own time.

I would argue that this is a subconscious process.  Our schema causes us to inherently reject ideas contrary to what we believe.  It is quite easy to slip back into this state of rejecting opposing ideas when all you're doing is reading and you're not forced to either formulate an opposition or accept the counterpoint.

&gt;And if such a person exists that does this, that dismisses a book, which devotes pages to arguing a single idea, he will gain nothing from an internet comment.

I will argue, again, that it is not about the content or depth of discussion, which is undeniably better in most books, but rather the form that it takes that allows an internet comment to change views differently, possibly more effectively.

Our ultimate disagreement seems to boil down to the fact that you see books as having superior content and depth, with which I would agree, but you do not believe that the differences in form can allow discussions to be more effective at changing views.  Could you please explain why you do not think demanding a response forces more thought and consideration, and is thus more likely to cause a shift in views?
</reply>
<reply id="cngufgd" author="1millionbucks">
&gt; Yes, avoid them! Comment karma is a thing! Just because there are bad comments does not mean that there are not good ones. (I do not do this to mock you, just to point out that your counter argument applies equally to your argument.)

No internet comment's argument will be as good as a book's.

&gt; **if** someone has not been succesfully swayed

A reasonable person that read the book carefully and at least considered all its points, and still walked away believing in himself, will not seek any other source to change his mind.

But if the person has not considered the points, then perhaps you're right, a discussion might be a better medium for that person. I would personally argue that this person is just not open to change and a discussion is likely a waste of the other debater's time.

&gt;more likely to emerge, sheerly through statistics.

I actually read a book about how the hive mind is inferior to the singular thoughtful person or collaborative group: You are Not a Gadget. It was a mostly bad book, the author was incapable of proper organization of his thoughts to the point of rambling, but it did make a very good case in arguing this specific point. 

&gt; I would argue that this is a subconscious process. Our schema causes us to inherently reject ideas contrary to what we believe. It is quite easy to slip back into this state of rejecting opposing ideas when all you're doing is reading and you're not forced to either formulate an opposition or accept the counterpoint.

When we read things that could potentially fundamentally shift our world-view, even in a discussion, this type of thing is easily disregarded. In a reddit discussion, a person would simply not reply again: in a human conversation, a person could shut down his ears. It is not preventable in any medium, and thus takes an intelligent person, that realizes that he could be wrong, to hold an open mind, because it does requires a decent amount of mental willpower. I think we agree on this.

&gt; the differences in form can allow discussions to be more effective at changing views.

People learn in different ways: perhaps a discussion would be better. But the hive mind is historically terrible at argumentation. A person is easily overwhelmed by arguing with 20 different people, and could withdraw because he feels that he is being attacked on all sides.

&gt; you do not think demanding a response forces more thought and consideration

Don't think about elephants. It is impossible to obey this command. In the same way, simply reading a book puts the ideas into one's head, and elicits a response there. A person that rejects this can easily reject an internet comment by simply not replying and attacking a different argument in which he feels more safe in his correctness.
</reply>
<reply id="cngw6b2" author="AzeTheGreat">
&gt;No internet comment's argument will be as good as a book's.

I acknowledge that the depth will not be the same, but they can still present the same argument (simpler).  But, like I've said repeatedly, I'm looking specifically at the form it takes.

&gt;A reasonable person that read the book carefully and at least considered all its points, and still walked away believing in himself, will not seek any other source to change his mind.

Why not?  I would say that we should always be seeking information to either further support our ideas or to contrast them.  It's the only way we can further approach the "Truth".

&gt;I actually read a book about how the hive mind is inferior to the singular thoughtful person or collaborative group:

This goes against what my gut would say, but if it seems to be a substantually supported position then I guess I would concede that looking at books would provide more unique arguments.


&gt;In a reddit discussion, a person would simply not reply again: in a human conversation, a person could shut down his ears.

Hmm.  Perhaps you and I just function fundamentally differently then.  When I'm reading a book I frequently find myself just absorbing ideas without critically analyzing it.  Obviously this isn't inherent to books, it's just how I tend to interract with that medium.  Conversely, in a discussion I'm always evaluating in my mind, deciding whether I agree or disagree and how to form my counterpoint.  Frequently in the process of forming my counterpoint I'll think of multiple counterpoints to what I was about to say, in the process refining my view and progressing much further than just a book would make me.  Statistically I would assume there are other people like me, and thus posts where arguments could be easily found online *can* be valuable, and *are* a geniune attempt from some people to change their minds.

&gt;A person is easily overwhelmed by arguing with 20 different people, and could withdraw because he feels that he is being attacked on all sides.

Well that sounds like a problem with CMV and not necessarily the people who want their views changed.

Our disagreement seems to be based on the fact that we seem to process information from different sources differently.  I'm completely willing to accept this, but I think it's necessary to note that it is quite possible a significant portion of the population feels the same way as me, and thus these posts are beneficial. 


</reply>
<reply id="cnh5pt9" author="1millionbucks">
&gt; Our disagreement seems to be based on the fact that we seem to process information from different sources differently. I'm completely willing to accept this, but I think it's necessary to note that it is quite possible a significant portion of the population feels the same way as me, and thus these posts are beneficial.

I agree. We have discussed this to the point where nothing further can be gained. I hope you enjoyed our discussion and maybe learned something new :)
</reply>
<reply id="cnh8vcl" author="AzeTheGreat">
It definitely showed me hiw differently some people process things.  Good discussion :)
</reply>
</thread>
