<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2ro0ti">
<title>CMV:Essential Oils are bullshit</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2ro0ti/cmvessential_oils_are_bullshit/</source>
<OP author="GoldenTaint">
My wife has recently gotten deeply involved/obsessed with the healing properties of essential oils.  I am cursed with a common problem in that I am an extremely skeptical person.  I can't help but look at this product and see a pyramid scheme that takes advantage of the gullible.  All the shit my wife watches on these oils is carefully worded to make sure they don't make actual healing claims, I'm told this is because they aren't FDA approved and could get in trouble.  I've looked a little and haven't found anything debunking these oils but i still cannot help but feel they are total BS.  I would love to get more information from unbiased sources on this.  

Please change my view without just anecdotal testimonies. 
</OP>
<reply id="cnho6mi" author="Mavericgamer">
I'm not an expert on essential oils, but I know a thing or two about cons.

Here is how I suggest that you approach this: Find your wife's supplier/whatever, and ask them the difficult questions. How does it work? What ailments does it cure? What about the chemistry of these oils makes it work? How does the bacteria/virus/fungus/etc react to these oils in laboratory conditions in a double-blind test?

Basically, if this is another dupe, they'll lead you up the pyramid until you find someone who can either answer your questions, or will start dodging them. Which of these they do will be the proof you need, one way or another.
</reply>
<reply id="cnhot32" author="GoldenTaint">
This is exactly where I'm at in my view on this stuff but there don't seem to be any answers to these questions, other than claims that they cure just about everything.  Got a headache?  Just rub some of this on your foot.  
</reply>
<reply id="cnhp1pb" author="Mavericgamer">
That sounds dangerously like Aromatherapy. I feel like something similar was featured on an episode of Penn &amp; Teller's *Bullshit!* but I'm at work and can't find the clip currently.
</reply>
</thread>
