<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rkjr3">
<title>CMV: Irony aside, most people that post in CMV are uneducated, and changing their view on one point won't solve this overall problem</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rkjr3/cmv_irony_aside_most_people_that_post_in_cmv_are/</source>
<OP author="1millionbucks">
There are some instances, yes where controversial topics are discussed here and people are actually interested in hearing the opposite side. I consider myself one of those people, and was initially driven to this subreddit in the hope that I would meet other people like myself that were posting here to educate themselves. The type of man that reads a book that argues against a position he already holds, in the hopes that he can understand the entire issue in a great light.

But far and away, this is not the case. Some of the posts on here include logical fallacies even in the titles: yesterday's [atheism post](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rfea1/) used a strawman fallacy in the title to misrepresent their own position to make it easier to defend in a religion vs. athiesm debate. The OP, if you read that post, was by and large not interested in changing his opinion, and this is true of the *vast majority* of posts that come through here.

And the problem is this: it is a tremendous waste of time for every knowledgable person that posts answers in here. A lot of times, the posts are not controversial: they are simply the product of stupidity. There are a thousand places, a million internet hits, which one can browse to discover facts on the athiesm/religion debate and even the specific subtopic that was discussed yesterday. An educated person, or rather, a person seeking to educate himself, would have simply utilized this vast body of resources rather than take time to create a new resource.

Additionally, the people that tend to post in this subreddit post on this subreddit have a certain mindset already, even before submitting. Go ahead, think of something you believe that is controversial and click "Submit CMV." Your mind will already be working to inhibit opposing opinions and you will be clinging harder than ever to the bulwarks of your argument. The fact of the matter is this: it takes considerable effort to open one's mind, even on things that are not of great consequence. And most people are simply unable to accomplish this.

Thanks for your replies. I intend to reply to each response to my original post, albeit maybe not today, and I hope to award many deltas for your efforts.

Quick edit: I realized I didn't address the second part of my title claim. Albert Einstein said that 2 things are limitless: the universe and human stupidity. For every stupid person that posts on this sub to address one point of their lack of knowledge, there are foreseeably dozens more points of misunderstanding that remain. What is the overall aim of this subreddit? To educate one at a time, indeed. But on issues that can be solved via Google search or the opening of a book, how can one fill the infinite pit of human stupidity? Only controversial issues, where both opinions are agreed to be at least understandable and held widely by educated people, should be allowed. This is a real debate: anything else is just convincing a stupid person of something that they fail to understand.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cngrsft" author="NightCrest">
&gt; Only controversial issues, where both opinions are agreed to be at least understandable and held widely by educated people, should be allowed.

I actually read a comment about 4 months back that I liked so much I saved it and I think it's a really good counter for this point.

&gt; This sums up my entire experience with this sub.

&gt; Either it's a topic I have a very strong opinion about and I just skim through the discussion and my view remains unchanged 90% of the time.

&gt; Or it's something random like this, something I haven't even thought about. I read the OP and think how OP presents some very good arguments and I agree with him. Then my rollercoaster ride starts - every reply usually changes my opinion to the other side. I leave the thread confused and just a bit more enlightened on how stupid it is to be stubborn and deal in absolutes.

&gt; These seemingly unimportant and simple CMVs are an incredibe gateway to healthy critical thinking. On a basic level, we all know nothing is black and white but having your opinion changed 10 times in 2 minutes makes you realize that what you consider to be the most fundamental truths could easily be challenged.

&gt; Anyone who's ever studied philosophy should be aware of this, but it took me subscribing to CMV to realize that you shouldn't try to change people's strong beliefs (if you think they're wrong), you should make their mindset evolve. And the best way to do this is to show then just how easy it is to change a new/minor opinion of theirs with facts.

- /u/teokk

[Source comment](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2f68nt/cmv_garfield_shouldnt_hate_mondays_because_he/ck6l6ix)

(btw, if this changes your view, you should probably award them the delta and not me)
</reply>
<reply id="cngs5g0" author="1millionbucks">
/u/teokk is commenting on a different kind of post. He is talking about a post where he has no opinion already, and instead is immediately thrusted into a situation where people are trying to pull him one way or another.

I am talking about questions where the answer is readily available online: the person has an established opinion that, usually, they know is in contrast with the majority, but either does not take the effort to find the majority answer or is unwilling to accept it. This is a scenario in which the majority answer, or at least the scientific answer, is held to be correct, while the OP's position is held to be incorrect, rather than a situation where both sides can be correct in some degree.
</reply>
<reply id="cngsdcf" author="NightCrest">
I realize you're focusing on a different type of post, but by saying

&gt;**Only** controversial issues, where both opinions are agreed to be at least understandable and held widely by educated people, **should be allowed**

you're saying all threads that don't meet those criteria should be removed (which would include the posts where some people have no opinion on), and I think that would be a great loss to the subreddit for the reasons /u/teokk presented.
</reply>
<reply id="cngt4l3" author="1millionbucks">
/u/teokk's comment was in response to an authentic debate: no one really had a set opinion going into it. That kind of discussion would still be okay, in my opinion. 

I agree that I worded it badly in the main post. Perhaps, questions which have a readily accessible and definite answer that is simple to find should not be allowed, would be a better way to phrase it.
</reply>
<reply id="cngu3re" author="NightCrest">
OP clearly had an opinion going in or they wouldn't have posted the topic in the first place. Also, I think trying to properly define what questions do and don't have readily accessible and definite answers is quite the undertaking. It's a bit much to expect everyone to know everything about every single thing they may bring up. I know I've cited misinformation that I thought was accurate, got corrected on it, did more research and changed my view on it (not as an OP, but still), so disallowing that entirely I think would deprive many people of valuable information they otherwise might not have come across on their own.

I think the moment you start to trying to declare stances as "invalid," really all stances can come into question.

Also, you mentioned you felt they waste people's time, but personally, I come here mostly because I enjoy debating people. If I change some views or get views changed, all the better, but as long as the conversations are enjoyable for me, I don't feel *my* time has been wasted.
</reply>
<reply id="cngukuu" author="1millionbucks">
&gt; quite the undertaking

Very true. All your points are fair.
</reply>
</thread>
