<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rk7my">
<title>CMV: Driving a car is insanely risky and probably the most dangerous thing you do in your everyday life.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rk7my/cmv_driving_a_car_is_insanely_risky_and_probably/</source>
<OP author="einmaliger">
I find it difficult to understand how so many people enjoy driving a car or can even relax while doing it. I am almost continually tense while on the road thinking about what's at stake (and I've been driving for almost 20 years).

While I have never been in an accident, I often find myself thinking how dangerous even small motions of a driver can be. For example, a sudden small jerking movement of an arm on the steering wheel leading the car into oncoming traffic can lead to almost certain instant death. I cannot think of any other action in my daily life where so many small actions (of me or other people) can be lethal.

Even leaving accidents and catastrophic scenarios out of consideration, driving a car seems extremely risky to me: For many, maybe most people their car is the most expensive single item that they own. Even small mistakes like a lack of concentration or a tiny miscalculation while parking into a small space, can lead to high damage and expensive repairs.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cngou5v" author="nonowh0">
Cars allow us to get to places that we otherwise wouldn't be able to get to. This is a *big deal*. 

With the world as interconnected as it is today, we have to be able to get from place to place. Yes, driving is fairly risky. As you say, it is the most dangerous thing you do in your everyday life. But these are risks that we have to take in order to live the way we do. 

Cars let us live far away (10+ miles) from our workplace/the center of town. This means that we can buy cheaper houses, as land is less valuable the farther you get from the city. Cars also allow cities to grow to very large sizes. If we didn't have cars, cities wouldn't be able to grow farther than walking/horse carriage distance. These are just a few things that cars do for us.  

Basically, what I'm trying to say is that cars are necessary to the world at large. We have to accept the risk associated with driving.
</reply>
<reply id="cngpqws" author="einmaliger">
This is in fact the only reason that makes me sometimes use my car.

I spend most of my time in large cities with good public transport where subways, trains and trams get you everywhere. My point is that using the car to get anywhere is only justified if the cost of going there by any other means is very high. It seems that many other people disagree and asses the benefits of driving higher than the dangers in almost all cases.

I think that even using a cab (which obviously is a car) is less dangerous as the drivers are professionals and probably more experienced than I am.
</reply>
</thread>
