<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rk7my">
<title>CMV: Driving a car is insanely risky and probably the most dangerous thing you do in your everyday life.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rk7my/cmv_driving_a_car_is_insanely_risky_and_probably/</source>
<OP author="einmaliger">
I find it difficult to understand how so many people enjoy driving a car or can even relax while doing it. I am almost continually tense while on the road thinking about what's at stake (and I've been driving for almost 20 years).

While I have never been in an accident, I often find myself thinking how dangerous even small motions of a driver can be. For example, a sudden small jerking movement of an arm on the steering wheel leading the car into oncoming traffic can lead to almost certain instant death. I cannot think of any other action in my daily life where so many small actions (of me or other people) can be lethal.

Even leaving accidents and catastrophic scenarios out of consideration, driving a car seems extremely risky to me: For many, maybe most people their car is the most expensive single item that they own. Even small mistakes like a lack of concentration or a tiny miscalculation while parking into a small space, can lead to high damage and expensive repairs.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cngox6v" author="HJD8d9d">
It seems to me that what this comes down to is the difference between the chance something goes wrong, and the consequences it has when it goes wrong. The consequences of a small mistake while driving could be catastrophic. However, only 1-2 out of every ten thousand people die from a car accident each year in the U.S. So while the consequences of a mistake while driving are high, the actual chance of anyone dying in a car accident are fairly low. Furthermore, small but stupid mistakes can have severe consequences in many situations. Forget one letter and you can transfer a large amount of money to the wrong person. Make a jerking movement with your arm while eating and you could end up with a fork in your eye. Both of these things can and have happened due to tiny mistakes, but they're not the reasons banking or eating breakfast are insanely risky.

You might still be right tough, statistically driving could be the daily activity that's most likely to directly kill you. But I think that the rather low car fatality rate doesn't justify saying that driving a car is insanely risky. But you've probably thought of all of the above, so why do you still think it's that risky? 
</reply>
<reply id="cngq2ra" author="einmaliger">
I think that there are more realistic scenarios that make driving mistakes probable (being tired, losing concentration on a long drive, being distracted by something) than scenarios that make you stick your fork in your eye.

Also I'm not only thinking about lethality, but about any large losses that have a high probability.

[edit: wording]
</reply>
</thread>
