<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rk7my">
<title>CMV: Driving a car is insanely risky and probably the most dangerous thing you do in your everyday life.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rk7my/cmv_driving_a_car_is_insanely_risky_and_probably/</source>
<OP author="einmaliger">
I find it difficult to understand how so many people enjoy driving a car or can even relax while doing it. I am almost continually tense while on the road thinking about what's at stake (and I've been driving for almost 20 years).

While I have never been in an accident, I often find myself thinking how dangerous even small motions of a driver can be. For example, a sudden small jerking movement of an arm on the steering wheel leading the car into oncoming traffic can lead to almost certain instant death. I cannot think of any other action in my daily life where so many small actions (of me or other people) can be lethal.

Even leaving accidents and catastrophic scenarios out of consideration, driving a car seems extremely risky to me: For many, maybe most people their car is the most expensive single item that they own. Even small mistakes like a lack of concentration or a tiny miscalculation while parking into a small space, can lead to high damage and expensive repairs.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cngpiso" author="Mavericgamer">
You have a strange definition of "risky"; while it's true a mistake can cost you your life, they often don't (cars have been getting safer since the 1920s) and the fact is that because so many people spend so much time driving, we are better at it than a lot of other things and so are much more likely to not make those mistakes (though, sadly, they do happen).

I define "risky" as a high likelihood that something out of your control can kill you in the given activity, and the things that can kill you and aren't in your control to some degree in a car are very infrequent. Playing Russian Roulette is risky because there is a 1 in 6 chance that a bullet is going through your head. Driving there is a 1 in 1 million chance that you're going to be killed in an accident, maybe a 1 in 10,000 chance that you'll be in an accident at all.
</reply>
<reply id="cngqipq" author="einmaliger">
By "risky" I mean that the total, accumulated risk is greater than the benefits of driving a car, at least in a large number of scenarios. It seems to me that people generally underestimate the risks and that the percieved benefits are higher than the real ones. I think that you should not use your car in most cases.

[edit: wording]
</reply>
<reply id="cngqxkn" author="Mavericgamer">
Why not?

I work a good 25 miles from my house. Walking is completely infeasible, motorcycles are *more* risky, and a bike is just as risky if not moreso due to the lack of bike lanes around my area.

The amount of time I save by driving means that I can invest my effort into bettering the world.

Someone else actually gave the values of riskiness for driving versus other modes of transport; you're less likely (per mile traveled) to die in a car than virtually any other form of transportation. The fact is that home and other inside places protect you from your environment, which is trying to kill you, and travel has always been risky. You are far less likely to die on a road trip or flight from Kansas to Oregon than you were using a wagon to take the Oregon Trail, because there is way less time available for nature to mess with you.
</reply>
</thread>
