<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rgs7o">
<title>CMV: Assuming there is no afterlife, then life is ultimately meaningless and pointless because we die.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rgs7o/cmv_assuming_there_is_no_afterlife_then_life_is/</source>
<OP author="mybromarcusaurelius">
*Note: Please assume that there is no afterlife when responding to my post. I am not religious. Thank you. ALSO: By "meaningless," I mean "meaningless" to the person who is doing the dying. To the person who is alive and who will then die, life is meaningless. 

CMV. Assuming there is no afterlife, life is ultimately meaningless and pointless because we die. Death is the great eraser. Living life is as irrational as reading a book that, after finished, is immediately erased from your memory. It is comparable to that, too. 

It makes no difference if I, a 23 year old, die now or live until I am 100 and die. Either way, after my brief spark of existence I become nothingness. Not only do I remember nothing; I AM nothing. To me, it is as if my life had never happened. 

I'll put it another way. Imagine the time before you were born. Have you remembered it yet? Of course not. You didn't exist. This is the state that we return to after death--a state of nothingness similar to the state we were in before birth. When I die, I return to this state after a brief period of consciousness, and I return to it permanently. I might as well have never lived. 

To anticipate a few responses:

(1) Helping others doesn't matter. They will die too. And then their descendants will die, on and on and on, until eventually the universe is destroyed or our galaxy collapses in an inevitable heat-death. Even if 1,000,000 people were helped by me, assuming they all die, then my life is still pointless and meaningless. For I will be dead and won't know what I did, and once they die, they won't know either. 

(2) Attaining fame doesn't matter and doesn't truly make me "immortal." I'll be dead, and again, death is nothingness. Thus, I won't be around to enjoy my fame. 

(3) Enjoying the moment is possible, but doesn't make life have a point. For once I die, all memories and all point is gone. 

Please change my view from this depressing sentiment. 
</OP>
<reply id="cngpero" author="DoodleKaboodle">
How can life be pointless, if life is, from your (ie an existential) perspective pointless, when it constitutes everything that can, and will ever exist? Consider the quote:

"The journey itself to the heights is enough to fill a man's heart. One must imagine Sisyphus happy."

Now I wont get too much into the story behind this, but this is a quote from Albert Camus, he actually shared your perspective, but extrapolated something very different. 

Sisyphus is a character is Greek mythology, he was a King, a rather despotic leader actually. One day he disobeyed the Gods, and so as punishment, they made him push a boulder to the top of a hill, and when he got to the top, allow it to roll back down to the bottom. Making all his work pointless. This, Camus thought, was analogous to our lives, everything you do will amount to nothing.

However, as the quote would explain, Camus thinks that the fact that we exist, however meaningless this may seem at first, gives us purpose. That purpose? To simply lead a virtuous and enjoyable life. This can seem quite paradoxical at first, a way to think about it would be when Satre said "existence predates essence", Camus would agree, but would go on to say that existence creates a somewhat artificial essence in and of itself. 

While this may not change your view, maybe I have even supported it, but you must understand this is not a depressing view at all. Rather it is a liberating one. I would strongly suggest reading the book by Camus, "The myth of Sisyphus", of which that quote is the last line of. Satre is also a badass, if you wanna check his stuff out, I would recommend "Existentialism is a humanism".
</reply>
<reply id="cngv0de" author="mybromarcusaurelius">
This... All of this. Love every part, especially the Camus part, and will award you a delta tomorrow as soon as I have access to my laptop. Saving the answer in my phone for now for perpetuity. 

I'll be checking out the Camus book! 
</reply>
</thread>
