<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2ro0ti">
<title>CMV:Essential Oils are bullshit</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2ro0ti/cmvessential_oils_are_bullshit/</source>
<OP author="GoldenTaint">
My wife has recently gotten deeply involved/obsessed with the healing properties of essential oils.  I am cursed with a common problem in that I am an extremely skeptical person.  I can't help but look at this product and see a pyramid scheme that takes advantage of the gullible.  All the shit my wife watches on these oils is carefully worded to make sure they don't make actual healing claims, I'm told this is because they aren't FDA approved and could get in trouble.  I've looked a little and haven't found anything debunking these oils but i still cannot help but feel they are total BS.  I would love to get more information from unbiased sources on this.  

Please change my view without just anecdotal testimonies. 
</OP>
<reply id="cnhp0bu" author="goribilli">
OK, so, yes, in most cases, essential oils are bullshit when it comes to all this craze about natural healing products and whatnot. But there are some that are SO AWESOME!!! Props to you for being skeptical! Let me see if I can change your view on a couple of oils...

Lavender Oil: This is primarily used for relaxation and anxiety relief. There have been several studies performed over many years that have more or less proven this pretty well. I use it myself sometimes after laundering the bedclothes, putting a bit in the pillowcases. I used to foster a really crazy Yorkie, and a tiny dab of the oil on her paws made her unbelievably relaxed and calm.

Tea Tree Oil: This is good for minor infections and small wounds. It's endorsed by many doctors, and is even featured on WebMD for these uses (to a lesser extent a LOT of other healing things, but these haven't been studied well.) 

Peppermint Oil: While there aren't a lot of conclusive studies available for it, this shit is awesome for digestive issues in my experience when combined with other ingredients. The best medicine I ever had for digestive issues was infused with the stuff. Also, peppermint oil is AMAZING for deterring mosquitoes.

Anyway, the stuff is useful, and typically smells awesome. As long as she isn't destroying her own pocketbook, I think your wife will be fine. The three oils I mentioned (plus a few others) I buy myself at discounts, usually on Amazon, for the uses I mentioned. I don't know what kind of pyramid schemes you're referring to, but anything that is a pyramid scheme is probably bad. :(
</reply>
<reply id="cnhppsw" author="GoldenTaint">
From my experience:

Lavender Oil: My has rubbed the crap on me to "make me sleepy".  It does NOT work for me.  Last night, wife put some on a raging baby that we were watching.  It did NOT work. 

Peppermint Oil: Wife heard this same thing and, following internet advice, placed a drop upon her tongue.  She said it was the most intense shit's she's ever had. 
</reply>
</thread>
