<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rgs7o">
<title>CMV: Assuming there is no afterlife, then life is ultimately meaningless and pointless because we die.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rgs7o/cmv_assuming_there_is_no_afterlife_then_life_is/</source>
<OP author="mybromarcusaurelius">
*Note: Please assume that there is no afterlife when responding to my post. I am not religious. Thank you. ALSO: By "meaningless," I mean "meaningless" to the person who is doing the dying. To the person who is alive and who will then die, life is meaningless. 

CMV. Assuming there is no afterlife, life is ultimately meaningless and pointless because we die. Death is the great eraser. Living life is as irrational as reading a book that, after finished, is immediately erased from your memory. It is comparable to that, too. 

It makes no difference if I, a 23 year old, die now or live until I am 100 and die. Either way, after my brief spark of existence I become nothingness. Not only do I remember nothing; I AM nothing. To me, it is as if my life had never happened. 

I'll put it another way. Imagine the time before you were born. Have you remembered it yet? Of course not. You didn't exist. This is the state that we return to after death--a state of nothingness similar to the state we were in before birth. When I die, I return to this state after a brief period of consciousness, and I return to it permanently. I might as well have never lived. 

To anticipate a few responses:

(1) Helping others doesn't matter. They will die too. And then their descendants will die, on and on and on, until eventually the universe is destroyed or our galaxy collapses in an inevitable heat-death. Even if 1,000,000 people were helped by me, assuming they all die, then my life is still pointless and meaningless. For I will be dead and won't know what I did, and once they die, they won't know either. 

(2) Attaining fame doesn't matter and doesn't truly make me "immortal." I'll be dead, and again, death is nothingness. Thus, I won't be around to enjoy my fame. 

(3) Enjoying the moment is possible, but doesn't make life have a point. For once I die, all memories and all point is gone. 

Please change my view from this depressing sentiment. 
</OP>
<reply id="cnfqwin" author="duckwantbread">
All your points seem to be on quite a selfish level (no offense). For example your point about fame is that you won't be around to enjoy your fame, so what? Life isn't about being the best, it's about other people as much as yourself. 

Space is limitless. If we play our cards right and put our minds together we could exist forever, we could form colonies on different planets far away from our galaxy, so that when our galaxy dies we will live on in distant galaxies. Many of us won't be scientists but that doesn't make our lives worthless. Think millennia back when there were less than a million people on the planet, the concept that many of them would end up being the ancestor to a very important historical figure must have seemed impossible yet that is what must have happened. If some ancient man and woman hadn't had a kid then that kid wouldn't have had a kid, and then follow that bloodline all the way down to someone great like Einstein. If even one of those people had decided to give up on life and not have sex with the person he/she liked Einstein would never have existed. You might say there would have been another Einstein, and you're right there probably would have been but imagine everyone gave up, suddenly the chance of an Einstein ever existing is dropping to zero. Then we never advance and we never get off our planet or even have a basic grasp on the science we think is simple stuff nowadays. 

Now maybe you'd think 'OK so I'm here to influence future generations so that we can hopefully live forever in distant worlds, who cares? There's billions of us, I'm hardly unique'. You are right you aren't unique, but you are incredibly rare. I'm sure you've seen the image of our solar system where the Earth is just a pixel on the screen, life only exists on that one pixel, the rest of the solar system is barren nothingness, spread every human out across our solar system and we could all comfortably live in our own floating space mansions with acres of garden because there are so few of us compared to the vast universe we live in. Hell the stars far outnumber us yet all of us humans have the potential to do far more in our lifetime than a random star will ever have in it's thousands of years of life. 

Even if you choose not to have a child you could still influence someone's life, if you show malice to people maybe you drive a man to depression. Show him compassion maybe he decides there is good in the world and he goes on to contribute to science or to become a great musician that inspires thousands of others, or maybe he just becomes a great father that raises a great kid that goes on to do great things. 

Hundreds of people you show compassion to probably won't even register it, but that doesn't matter, if even one person takes on board a good action that you've done and becomes a better person for it (and trust me, even if you don't ever know about it, it will happen) then you have contributed to humanity's future advancement and possible immortality. We won't get to see it but does that really matter? We weren't made to live forever even if we could be in the future, we were made to take joy from the little things and I honestly believe that is an evolutionary trait. If we didn't take joy in the little things then humanity long ago would have said 'what's the point?' given up, and died out. Instead we take pleasure from silly things like a 2 minute song that gets stuck in our head, or a person that says 'have a nice day', and that gives us the motivation to carry on and be productive, contributing to humankind's future advancement. We are part of the largest team effort in the world, whether we know it or not every positive action we make is working towards building a better world for future generations, it could be 2000 actions from now where something important happened, but you could unwittingly be the start of that 2000 action chain that leads to greatness with something as simple as a hello.


</reply>
<reply id="cnfrdxb" author="mybromarcusaurelius">
Life is lived from the perspective of the person living it. So the question of whether life has meaning while lived is obviously a selfish one. No apologies on that front. 

Very much enjoyed the rest of your answer and will think about it, thank you 
</reply>
</thread>
