<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rgs7o">
<title>CMV: Assuming there is no afterlife, then life is ultimately meaningless and pointless because we die.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rgs7o/cmv_assuming_there_is_no_afterlife_then_life_is/</source>
<OP author="mybromarcusaurelius">
*Note: Please assume that there is no afterlife when responding to my post. I am not religious. Thank you. ALSO: By "meaningless," I mean "meaningless" to the person who is doing the dying. To the person who is alive and who will then die, life is meaningless. 

CMV. Assuming there is no afterlife, life is ultimately meaningless and pointless because we die. Death is the great eraser. Living life is as irrational as reading a book that, after finished, is immediately erased from your memory. It is comparable to that, too. 

It makes no difference if I, a 23 year old, die now or live until I am 100 and die. Either way, after my brief spark of existence I become nothingness. Not only do I remember nothing; I AM nothing. To me, it is as if my life had never happened. 

I'll put it another way. Imagine the time before you were born. Have you remembered it yet? Of course not. You didn't exist. This is the state that we return to after death--a state of nothingness similar to the state we were in before birth. When I die, I return to this state after a brief period of consciousness, and I return to it permanently. I might as well have never lived. 

To anticipate a few responses:

(1) Helping others doesn't matter. They will die too. And then their descendants will die, on and on and on, until eventually the universe is destroyed or our galaxy collapses in an inevitable heat-death. Even if 1,000,000 people were helped by me, assuming they all die, then my life is still pointless and meaningless. For I will be dead and won't know what I did, and once they die, they won't know either. 

(2) Attaining fame doesn't matter and doesn't truly make me "immortal." I'll be dead, and again, death is nothingness. Thus, I won't be around to enjoy my fame. 

(3) Enjoying the moment is possible, but doesn't make life have a point. For once I die, all memories and all point is gone. 

Please change my view from this depressing sentiment. 
</OP>
<reply id="cnfzhma" author="jkandu">
Here is the converse of that: Imagine you are a person that lives forever. We assume there is no afterlife, so you live forever, as a human with all human restrictions in perpetuity (assume also no heat death of the universe). There is a fundamental limit on the amount of memories you can have. There is a fundamental limit on the amount of "wisdom" (whatever that means) you can gain. Eventually, after hundreds, or maybe thousands, or maybe billions of years, you will not even remember your formative years. 

Think about that. You would eventually become so disconnected from the world. Even if all of humanity was immortal with you, you would only ever be living with a memory of, say, the last 100 years (i mean, maybe, 1000, but even if you could remember a trillion years, that won't matter in a quadrillion years). You at some point would become a tape that is forever being re-written. 

Does this make life any more meaningful? I don't see how. Even if you realize your effective memory, you are doomed to limited knowledge. And you can't escape it. When I think about immortality, I am not sure that I want it. 

The only way that immortality would be meaningful is if we can keep some of the past memories indefinitely. Unfortunately, in our universe, this isn't possible. 

I don't know quite how to end this, because it can be taken two ways: both immortality and mortality are equally depressing. OR: maybe dying isn't so bad after all. Maybe the best thing we can do is make our lives the best they can be. 
</reply>
<reply id="cng4vlr" author="mybromarcusaurelius">
Was one of the most interesting points made! 
</reply>
</thread>
