<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rgs7o">
<title>CMV: Assuming there is no afterlife, then life is ultimately meaningless and pointless because we die.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rgs7o/cmv_assuming_there_is_no_afterlife_then_life_is/</source>
<OP author="mybromarcusaurelius">
*Note: Please assume that there is no afterlife when responding to my post. I am not religious. Thank you. ALSO: By "meaningless," I mean "meaningless" to the person who is doing the dying. To the person who is alive and who will then die, life is meaningless. 

CMV. Assuming there is no afterlife, life is ultimately meaningless and pointless because we die. Death is the great eraser. Living life is as irrational as reading a book that, after finished, is immediately erased from your memory. It is comparable to that, too. 

It makes no difference if I, a 23 year old, die now or live until I am 100 and die. Either way, after my brief spark of existence I become nothingness. Not only do I remember nothing; I AM nothing. To me, it is as if my life had never happened. 

I'll put it another way. Imagine the time before you were born. Have you remembered it yet? Of course not. You didn't exist. This is the state that we return to after death--a state of nothingness similar to the state we were in before birth. When I die, I return to this state after a brief period of consciousness, and I return to it permanently. I might as well have never lived. 

To anticipate a few responses:

(1) Helping others doesn't matter. They will die too. And then their descendants will die, on and on and on, until eventually the universe is destroyed or our galaxy collapses in an inevitable heat-death. Even if 1,000,000 people were helped by me, assuming they all die, then my life is still pointless and meaningless. For I will be dead and won't know what I did, and once they die, they won't know either. 

(2) Attaining fame doesn't matter and doesn't truly make me "immortal." I'll be dead, and again, death is nothingness. Thus, I won't be around to enjoy my fame. 

(3) Enjoying the moment is possible, but doesn't make life have a point. For once I die, all memories and all point is gone. 

Please change my view from this depressing sentiment. 
</OP>
<reply id="cnfr5mi" author="ThimSlick">
'Meaningless' is such a subjective term. Your stance seems to stand on the idea that anything that cannot outlast time is ultimately pointless. Is that correct? Well, I agree with you. But, I disagree that this lack of **eternal** meaningfulness is "irrational" or "depressing."

I'll give you an example. A lot of people enjoy spending a large amount of time and energy into their fitness. I'd say the vast majority of these people do not create any real economic benefit to their livelihood (in terms of making money, paying for food, rent) and, should they stop for a year or a month, much of the progress they make will be lost. Most of them will never fully utilize their fitness in a meaningful way. In the long run, their progress will definitely be lost because their bodies will eventually fail, and they will die. Yet, knowing they can't keep their fitness in a single lifetime (let alone eternity), they strive to work out and build themselves. Why is that? 

&gt;Every day is a journey, and the journey itself is home

~Matsuo Basho

As mortal beings, we are relatively short-sighted. But, maybe that isn't a depressing idea. Maybe it's a great thing. Maybe it's beautiful that we can find so much meaning, so many experiences and so much emotion in such a short time frame, even if none of it lasts. Individually, we'll live and die and the universe won't even have had a chance to blink. And yet, maybe we'll get to have lived pretty well here. 
</reply>
<reply id="cnfrgjw" author="mybromarcusaurelius">
Beautiful answer, thanks bro
</reply>
</thread>
