<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rexe3">
<title>CMV: EMTs, SAR, firefighters, police, etc. should receive “military discounts”.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rexe3/cmv_emts_sar_firefighters_police_etc_should/</source>
<OP author="ke7ofi">
For those of you who don’t know, it’s common (at least in the US) for businesses, transit agencies, etc. to give small discounts to military veterans to thank them for their service.

It seems that medical responders (even hospital staff, actually) and other emergency services do more good for society than soldiers and that such discounts should be given to them.

As for the “They’re not risking their lives for our country.” argument, police officers do that too, and for citizens rather than the country and its interests. Some might argue that soldiers do the US a disservice rather than help, but that’s [usually] the fault of their leaders and therefore not relevant to the debate.

I’m really hoping there’s a good reason behind the status quo, but we’ll see. [It looks like there’s even less reason behind it than I initially thought, actually.]

[edits in brackets]

[[My view’s been changed.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rexe3/cmv_emts_sar_firefighters_police_etc_should/cnfj9cu?context=10000) In summary, I think that EMS people are just as deserving of these discounts (and that many more people contribute enough to be placed in the same category), but I now believe - for the same reason - that these discounts shouldn’t be offered at all.]
_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnf93jv" author="[deleted]">
[deleted]
</reply>
<reply id="cnfbg9s" author="ke7ofi">
&gt; Sure firefighters, EMT's, and nurses do great things for people. . . for those who have money and great insurance.

It’s not like the dispatcher chooses which calls to answer based on insurance policies.

&gt;What a douchebag line.

You’ll have fun [here](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rexe3/cmv_emts_sar_firefighters_police_etc_should/cnf9wqo?context=3), then.
</reply>
</thread>
