<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rekjo">
<title>CMV: I believe you have three choices once you discover the suffering animals endure in the meat industry...</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rekjo/cmv_i_believe_you_have_three_choices_once_you/</source>
<OP author="Anticarnist">
The options are as follows:

1. You don't agree with what is going on and stop supporting it.

2. You don't care about animals, so you're content with paying for them to be abused for your pleasure. 

3. You don't agree with what is going on, but try to put it to the back of your mind and continue to support it.


Reasoning: I used to follow 'option number 3', but recently started 'option number 1' in an attempt to line my actions up with my values. I suspect this way of looking at it is still somewhat simplistic however, so feel free to prove me wrong.
_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnf8twx" author="MizzKittay">
&gt;1. You don't agree with what is going on and stop supporting it.

Stop supporting it how? As in never buying meat again, even as you know that doing so will not have any impact on the meat industry whatsoever, and won't make even an ounce of difference in the lives of animals? What's the point? If I stop eating meat today, it won't make any difference whatsoever and won't save even a single animal's life. 

The only way to make real change in industries like this is to organize and participate in a boycott on a wide-scale level, and/or to petition the government to make regulation changes. 
</reply>
<reply id="cnfb4jg" author="Anticarnist">
I wouldn't buy ivory, dog leather or fur for the same reasons - I find meat disgusting based on what I've seen and want no part of endorsing it whether it makes any difference overall or not.
</reply>
</thread>
