<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rcrkd">
<title>CMV: Veganism and vegetarianism are not the best way to improve farm animal welfare</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rcrkd/cmv_veganism_and_vegetarianism_are_not_the_best/</source>
<OP author="Helicase21">
Title is mostly to get attention, and I'm working from a specific set of assumptions. My argument is as follows:

1) The chances of the entire world adopting a vegan/vegetarian diet are slim to none

1a) Therefore, there will always be a market for meat and other animal products

2) The food market, like all other markets, operates on general principles of supply and demand

3) Meat farmers can use techniques exhibiting a range of costs or benefits, both in terms of environmental impact and animal welfare.

4) A vegan or vegetarian diet denies demand, and thus potential revenue, to all meat-producing farms, regardless of how humane or environmentally sound their practice are.

4a) Since the majority of farms are large factory farms, I concede that this is probably good for animal welfare. **However**:

5) Purchasing meat from farms known to produce their meat in an ethical way not only denies demand to large factory farms but helps improve the market share of ethical meat-growing, which seems as though it would be even better for animal welfare.

My general view is that people should probably as a rule eat less meat from better growers, and that will make for a bigger shift in growing practices than simply people dropping out of eating meat altogether. Moreover, this practice would be much easier to "evangelize" than a vegetarian or vegan diet. Face it, meat is tasty (and non-factory meat is often tastier than factory-farmed meat, at least in my own anecdotal experience)





_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnet6x7" author="t_hab">
Remember, the higher up you eat on the food chain the less efficient it is to produce that food. 

For example, the Brazilian Amazon is being burned down to grow soya to feed to cows to feed to humans. If we ate the soya directly we would need one tenth the land and there would be no reason to burn down the Amazon. 

Under this logic, you don't need *every single person* to stop eating meat. In fact, every time you don't eat meat, even just one meal a day, you reduce your environmental footprint. If you help to preserve some jungle, even a tiny bit, you significantly improve the welfare of some wild animals. 

I know that your post specified *farm animals,* but vegans don't want there to be farm animals so it's a bit of a circular argument unless we include wild animals. 
</reply>
<reply id="cnetai7" author="Helicase21">
&gt;the higher up you eat on the food chain the less efficient it is to produce that food.

Not always the case (but a good rule of thumb)! Fish tend to be at trophic level 3 or higher, while cows and other herbivorous farm animals are trophic level 2. However, due to their being ectothermic, fish devote a greater percentage of their energy intake to growth versus maintaining homeostasis, and are thus more efficient. 

Not trying to argue your point, really, just think that's an interesting fact that I wanted to share.
</reply>
<reply id="cnetsp9" author="t_hab">
And thank you for sharing! 

I am not an ecologist or biologist, I just got lucky enough to work with some really good ones on a handful of projects. That means I have a decent knowledge but oh so many gaps. I really appreciate you helping to fill them. 

Cheers!
</reply>
</thread>
