<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rc3p3">
<title>CMV:Patriotism is the belief that being born on one side of a line makes you better.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rc3p3/cmvpatriotism_is_the_belief_that_being_born_on/</source>
<OP author="sniperman357">
American patriots have a general mentality against immigration. Saying these people shouldn’t be allowed to become part of the country, is the same as saying they are worse, because they were born on a different side of a line, and americans are better because of the side of the line they are born on. This is prominent in many ads and political champagnes, namely the slogan “Creating jobs for americans”. I understand why politics use this slogan, because they are trying to get americans to vote for them, but this slogan is also prominent in ads made by private corporations. As if creating jobs for americans is morally superior to creating jobs for people of other countries. The companies launching these ads may be trying to win in the american market, so they can sell more of their product, but the fact that this can increase sales shows that many americans hold the being born on one side of a line belief. I am not blaming the politicians or corporations running ads running these slogans, they are merely trying to win votes or make money from this mentality, but really it is the citizens that have the belief that they are better, because of the side of a line they are born on, that are at fault. Patriotism is really just this belief.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnejagk" author="looklistencreate">
I'm sure you can find many people who self-identify as patriots while also favoring policies that would allow more immigration. I'm one of these people.

Even if you don't, you don't have to necessarily think you're better than other people because you're against immigration. Many of these people believe that it's not our responsibility as Americans to provide for people from other countries, but rather the responsibility of those countries. That's not the same as thinking you're better than other people. I don't want absolutely no immigration control for people coming into the US, but I don't think I'm better than the people I'd be denying citizenship.
</reply>
<reply id="cneqn7o" author="sniperman357">
I confused patriotism, which is the love of one's country, with nationalism, which is the idea that one's country is better than other countries. What you said is definitely true about patriots, but I misused patriots to mean nationalist.
</reply>
<reply id="cneqpz7" author="looklistencreate">
Believing your country is better than all others is not the same as believing your country's people are better than all others.
</reply>
</thread>
