<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rppq9">
<title>CMV: Religion is not violent or not violent, its followers are.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rppq9/cmv_religion_is_not_violent_or_not_violent_its/</source>
<OP author="DurianMD">

So recently I've seen a lot of posts condemning Islam as a violent religion or a sexist religion.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">I point out that many Christians follow the bible which has numerous examples of sexism, but in application, there are numerous branches of Christianity that are no more sexist than secular groups.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">For example, Congregationalists and Universaliists.</premise>

So, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="2">my belief is that while religion can inform the views of people, it is far more likely that religion will be used to justify actions that would have been executed any way.</claim> <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3">I think that most Jewish people don't want to stone adulterers and most Muslims don't want to stone non believers.</claim>

</OP>
<reply id="cni44vr" author="recycled_kevlar">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3a"> Your stance relies on the assumption that religion has no influence on the actions of its followers beyond the superficial. </claim> 
<premise type="logos" id="3b"> Yet something must exist that allows this pattern to occur. </premise> 
Ill narrow it down to religion or culture. 
So, <premise type="logos" id="3c"> you are correct if you assume the culture dominates the religion, and you are incorrect if the reverse is true. </premise> 
<claim type="interpretation" id="3d"> With this in mind, I think its safe to assume the truth is somewhere in between, with both the religion and the culture somehow influencing the unrest we see. </claim>
 
</reply>
<reply id="cni4gv3" author="DurianMD">

<premise type="pathos" id="3e"> I suppose I was taking a harsh stance when I assumed that religion had no effect on behavior </premise>, when <claim type="agreement" id="3f"> it obviously does </claim>. 

<claim type="interpretation" id="3g"> I still think the culture dominates religion to a great extent </claim>, however I cannot ignore that religion does have an effect on culture to some extent.

&#8710;

I do however, look forward to seeing if someone can convince me that culture is dominated by religion more than vise versa.

</reply>
</thread>
