<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rppq9">
<title>CMV: Religion is not violent or not violent, its followers are.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rppq9/cmv_religion_is_not_violent_or_not_violent_its/</source>
<OP author="DurianMD">

So recently I've seen a lot of posts condemning Islam as a violent religion or a sexist religion.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">I point out that many Christians follow the bible which has numerous examples of sexism, but in application, there are numerous branches of Christianity that are no more sexist than secular groups.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">For example, Congregationalists and Universaliists.</premise>

So, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="2">my belief is that while religion can inform the views of people, it is far more likely that religion will be used to justify actions that would have been executed any way.</claim> <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3">I think that most Jewish people don't want to stone adulterers and most Muslims don't want to stone non believers.</claim>

</OP>
<reply id="cnjrf90" author="AdmiralCrunch9">

<claim type="interpretation" id="3a"> Most branches of modern religions aren't inherently violent </claim>, and <claim type="interpretation" id="3b"> there are complex socio-political issues involving the ones that are </claim> (<premise type="logos" id="3c"> e.g. how much of the violence perpetrated by Wahabist Islamists is based off of true religious fanaticism </premise>, and <premise type="logos" id="3d"> how much is caused by angry, politically disenfranchised young men who seek out an ideology that justifies their anger with America/the West </premise>), but <claim type="interpretation" id="3e"> that does not mean that a religion cannot have violence as an integral part of it </claim>, and there are historical examples of this. <premise type="logos" id="3f"> Vikings believed that the highest achievement and best place in the afterlife were gained by dying bravely in battle. </premise> 
<premise type="logos" id="3g"> The Thuggee cult believed that the murder of innocents was necessary to appease Kali and prevent the destruction of the world. </premise> 
<premise type="logos" id="3h"> Aztecs required human sacrifice in their religious rituals. </premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="3i"> Perhaps some facets of these historical religions were based off of a desire to justify actions that the original practitioners would have done anyway </premise>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id = "3j"> the belief eventually becomes the driving force and incentive for the action in later generations. </premise> 
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3k"> You are probably right that cultural norms are extremely influential in the creation of a religion </claim>, but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3l"> once that religion is established as the capital-T Truth, the tail begins wagging the dog and culture shifts to accomodate and protect that Truth. </claim> 
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="3m"> Many religions have historically encouraged, or even required violence, and once that religion and it's expectation of violence is established, it makes it much more difficult to enact societal change on the group. </premise> 
<premise type="pathos" id="3n"> It's hard enough to change a social norm of violence when it's simply cultural, it's even harder if people have been conditioned to believe that the norm is all that stands in the way of preventing the end of the world or is a persons only way into Valhalla. </premise> 
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="3o"> I think in those cases we can both say that the religion is inherently violent </claim>, and <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="3p"> that even if culture helped start that norm it eventually becomes the religion that causes the actions. </claim>
  
<reply id="cnjua2g" author="DurianMD">
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3q"> This is exactly the kind of explanation I was looking for. </claim> 
I'm on mobile, but I'll award you a delta when I get home. 
<premise type="pathos" id="3r"> You've appealed to all my sensibilities around this kind of issue </premise> while only making statements I agree with to change my view. 
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3s">That was terrific.</claim>

&#8710;
 
</reply>
</thread>
