<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rmwcd">
<title>CMV: Freedom of speech is being taken too far</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rmwcd/cmv_freedom_of_speech_is_being_taken_too_far/</source>
<OP author="5skandas">

In the last few weeks we've had two huge events happen in the world, both of which were caused by matters relating to "freedom of speech." The first being the hacking of Sony over The Interview, and today the shooting at the offices of a satirical magazine in Paris.
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="0">I certainly value our free speech</claim> but to me <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="1">there is a clear line between exercising your first amendment right (<premise type="logos" id="1z">"President Obama sucks!" etc</premise>) and doing things that are known to be offensive to other cultures</claim> (<premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">Satirical cartoons of prophets, assassinating leaders, etc</premise>).

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3">Perhaps this is a bad analogy</claim> - but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">if you say something antagonizing to a bully and you get your ass kicked, you should have anticipated that outcome.</premise>

</OP>
<reply id="cnhc295" author="Grunt08">
&gt; Perhaps this is a bad analogy - but if you say something antagonizing to a bully and you get your ass kicked, you should have anticipated that outcome.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="5">Think of something you do every day that you consider perfectly reasonable; something that harms nobody in any direct sense.</premise>
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="6">Let's imagine this thing is to defined as "walking down the street wearing headphones".</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="7">Now imagine that I tell you that you doing this offends me deeply for reasons of personal belief that you don't share.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="8">I warn you that continuing to do this will mean that I will shoot you on sight.</premise>

In a society that can't protect you from me, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="9">it might be *wise* for you to take off your headphones to preserve your life</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="10">That does not make my demand legitimate, does not make my shooting you an acceptable act</premise> and <premise type="logos" id="11">does not make my actions your fault</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="12">What you ought to hope is that society will protect you from someone like me and make it clear to me that my preferences will not be especially entertained because I threaten violence.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="13">I think people who satirize Muhammad in ways that Muslims consider blasphemous should stop doing that.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="14">I think it's counterproductive, antagonizing and in poor taste.</premise>
But <premise type="logos_pathos" id="15">if someone disagrees with me on that point, *they don't deserve to be shot.*</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnhclhu" author="5skandas">

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="16">I definitely do condone any sort of reactionary violence</claim> and <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="17">hope I didn't imply that through my post</claim>.
<premise type="pathos" id="18">What would the reaction from Americans be if someone walked through the streets of a predominantly black neighborhood saying "I hate black people" and was murdered?</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="19">I guarantee no one would care.</premise>
But <premise type="pathos" id="20">suddenly everyone was up in arms when they thought they were never going to see the movie The Interview because for a few moments Sony reevaluated the situation and decided not to release it.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="21">Nobody seemed to be saying "Jeez guys, maybe this is a really bad idea and we shouldn't do it."</premise> Most people seemed to be saying "Fuck North Korea!!
<premise type="logos" id="22">We'll watch our fucking movie cause we'ere FREE in America!!"</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnhdajd" author="Grunt08">

&gt; What would the reaction from Americans be if someone walked through the streets of a predominantly black neighborhood saying "I hate black people" and was murdered?

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="23">"What would the likely reaction be?" is not the right question to ask.</claim> <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="24">You should ask "what is the proper reaction?"</claim> <premise type="" id="25">A person doing that is probably an asshole,</premise> but <premise type="" id="26">that does not mean that silencing him is a proper reaction.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="27">And I think many people would care, because nothing you say should be enough to justify my shooting you.</premise>

<claim type="interpretation" id="28">The two examples you've mentioned are both examples of satire that have been forcibly silenced.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="29">Satire is the portion of speech that always stretches the boundaries of what we condone because its purpose is often to be offensive as a means of highlighting truths about people or society that are difficult to address seriously.</premise>

In any case, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="30">I think you may have missed the point</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="31">None of the examples you given actually hurt anybody.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="32">They have only provoked reactions.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="33">North Korea hacked Sony because they are so paranoid and insecure that they can't stand their leader being mocked.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="34">Some Muslims are so irrationally offended and self-important that they believe they have both the imperative and the right to kill people for drawing pictures.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="35">Neither of these examples illustrate problems with the speakers, they show the unhinged reactions of listeners.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnhm4xd" author="5skandas">

&gt; North Korea hacked Sony because they are so paranoid and insecure that they can't stand their leader being mocked. Some Muslims are so irrationally offended and self-important that they believe they have both the imperative and the right to kill people for drawing pictures. Neither of these examples illustrate problems with the speakers, they show the unhinged reactions of listeners.

Damn.
I think you just changed my view.
That's what I needed, thank you.
&#8710;

</reply>
</thread>
