<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rkzen">
<title>CMV: Eugenics isn't all that bad... And we don't even have to kill anyone for it</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rkzen/cmv_eugenics_isnt_all_that_bad_and_we_dont_even/</source>
<OP author="Seventh_______">

Okay, I'm talking about making the human race smarter, forever.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">Intelligence is at least partially genetic</claim> and <premise type="logos" id="1">therefore passed down by parents</premise>, yes? [Yes.](http://www.the-scientist.com/?articles.view/articleNo/40459/title/Inherited-Intelligence/)

So, what if, instead of killing off the less-intelligent people (<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="2">I'm against killing.</claim>
Of most things.)
we just limit offspring?

<premise type="logos" id="3">For example, we could use the IQ scale (for want of a better intelligence measure) to determine the number of offspring a person should be able to genetically contribute to.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="4">Like, round the IQ to the nearest multiple of 50, then divide by 50, and that's the number of offspring you're allowed to create.</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="5">So someone with near average intelligence (near 100 IQ, 75-124) would have their IQ rounded to 100 and then divided by 50 to make 2 offspring.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="6">The total offspring is presumably equal to the number of people who contributed to it.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="7">A man and a woman with average IQ can have two children (not each.) and sustain their population.</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="8">Conversely, really above average IQs of 125-174 can contribute genetically towards 3 children... and so on.</premise>

<claim type="interpretation" id="9">This would eventually make the human race smarter</claim>, and <premise type="logos" id="10">therefore more likely to survive and advance the human race.</premise>

<premise type="logos" id="11">I know this would be a bitch to implement and it's near impossible to actually do</premise>, but I'm just looking at the concept.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="12">I know the IQ test has its faults and every policy can be abused</premise>... I know all that.

<claim type="interpretation" id="13">Exceptions would be made when you accidentally have twins which causes you to go over your limit</claim>, or etc.
(<premise type="logos_pathos" id="14">If a mother can make 2, and has twins, she can't make more, but if she already has one and has twins after one which makes 3, we're not gonna kill one</premise>)

<premise type="logos" id="15">Perhaps if you have a major, heritable health issue your IQ has 25 subtracted from it before being rounded?</premise>
Or <premise type="logos" id="16">maybe weighted differently, like extremely high chance of cancer (almost 100 percent or something) takes off more... Something like that.</premise>

<premise type="ethos_logos" id="17">Much better than "Kill off those with IQ less than 80"</premise>

<premise type="logos" id="18">I wouldn't mind a smarter human race...</premise>

EDIT: **I am trying to argue that this process, if not abused, if followed by the people, and if we found an increasingly accurate measure of intelligence, would be ultimately a good thing to advance the human race.**

EDIT 2: "**It looks to me like you've made so many exceptions to your main view that you aren't looking to have your view changed. I'd like to talk about the title of your post, but if you have to make so many exceptions to your view, then it seems you already know it's incorrect.**" -nikeson
I suppose that's true, now....

</OP>
<reply id="cngw4hp" author="nikeson">

<premise type="logos" id="19">It looks to me like you've made so many exceptions to your main view</premise> that <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="20">you aren't looking to have your view changed</claim>.
I'd like to talk about the title of your post, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="21">if you have to make so many exceptions to your view, then it seems you already know it's incorrect</premise>.

</reply>
<reply id="cngwmww" author="Seventh_______">

*applies aloe to burn*
&#8710;
Edit: Delta because <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="22">nikeson proved that my argument has changed so much from my main point that it really just proves my argument wrong</claim>.
Sorry for not explaining

</reply>
</thread>
