<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rkzen">
<title>CMV: Eugenics isn't all that bad... And we don't even have to kill anyone for it</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rkzen/cmv_eugenics_isnt_all_that_bad_and_we_dont_even/</source>
<OP author="Seventh_______">

Okay, I'm talking about making the human race smarter, forever.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">Intelligence is at least partially genetic</claim> and <premise type="logos" id="1">therefore passed down by parents</premise>, yes? [Yes.](http://www.the-scientist.com/?articles.view/articleNo/40459/title/Inherited-Intelligence/)

So, what if, instead of killing off the less-intelligent people (<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="2">I'm against killing.</claim>
Of most things.)
we just limit offspring?

<premise type="logos" id="3">For example, we could use the IQ scale (for want of a better intelligence measure) to determine the number of offspring a person should be able to genetically contribute to.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="4">Like, round the IQ to the nearest multiple of 50, then divide by 50, and that's the number of offspring you're allowed to create.</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="5">So someone with near average intelligence (near 100 IQ, 75-124) would have their IQ rounded to 100 and then divided by 50 to make 2 offspring.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="6">The total offspring is presumably equal to the number of people who contributed to it.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="7">A man and a woman with average IQ can have two children (not each.) and sustain their population.</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="8">Conversely, really above average IQs of 125-174 can contribute genetically towards 3 children... and so on.</premise>

<claim type="interpretation" id="9">This would eventually make the human race smarter</claim>, and <premise type="logos" id="10">therefore more likely to survive and advance the human race.</premise>

<premise type="logos" id="11">I know this would be a bitch to implement and it's near impossible to actually do</premise>, but I'm just looking at the concept.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="12">I know the IQ test has its faults and every policy can be abused</premise>... I know all that.

<claim type="interpretation" id="13">Exceptions would be made when you accidentally have twins which causes you to go over your limit</claim>, or etc.
(<premise type="logos_pathos" id="14">If a mother can make 2, and has twins, she can't make more, but if she already has one and has twins after one which makes 3, we're not gonna kill one</premise>)

<premise type="logos" id="15">Perhaps if you have a major, heritable health issue your IQ has 25 subtracted from it before being rounded?</premise>
Or <premise type="logos" id="16">maybe weighted differently, like extremely high chance of cancer (almost 100 percent or something) takes off more... Something like that.</premise>

<premise type="ethos_logos" id="17">Much better than "Kill off those with IQ less than 80"</premise>

<premise type="logos" id="18">I wouldn't mind a smarter human race...</premise>

EDIT: **I am trying to argue that this process, if not abused, if followed by the people, and if we found an increasingly accurate measure of intelligence, would be ultimately a good thing to advance the human race.**

EDIT 2: "**It looks to me like you've made so many exceptions to your main view that you aren't looking to have your view changed. I'd like to talk about the title of your post, but if you have to make so many exceptions to your view, then it seems you already know it's incorrect.**" -nikeson
I suppose that's true, now....

</OP>
<reply id="cngucgz" author="Namemedickles">

Firstly, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="19">IQ is not considered to be a good or accurate measure of overall intellect</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="20">Intelligence is hard to define and describe even by neurologists</premise> and <premise type="logos" id="21">reducing that complexity down to one number is incredibly challenging if not impossible</premise>.

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="22">It may also be important to note that your system isn't only difficult to implement like you point out, it's also in direct conflict with how things actually work.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="23">More intelligent people tend to have less children than do the more uneducated.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="24">There are multiple reasons for this, more intelligent people tend to be more busy with careers, etc.</premise>

<claim type="disagreement" id="25">Lastly you must recognize that the IQ test is a standardized test.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="26">This means that even if we went really extreme and killed everyone with an IQ under 80.....that would change nothing.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="27">The average IQ will still be measured in the same way</premise>, <premise type="pathos" id="28">the lowest scores will be assigned the lower numbers and the average will be the same</premise>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnguvxh" author="Seventh_______">

Firstly, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="29">I mentioned that</claim>.
(<premise type="logos_pathos" id="30">"for want of better measure of intelligence"</premise>)
<premise type="logos" id="31">I would love a better measure of intelligence.</premise>
[<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="32">Some theorize that intelligence can be defined in categories, too...(http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theory_of_multiple_intelligences) </premise>
So, maybe a complex way to combine them.
<premise type="logos" id="34">Like a total of all of them.</premise>
Idc.

I know about number two...
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="35">I'm not proposing we implement it</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="36">In a perfect world, sure.</premise>
But at least <premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="37">my theory limits the offspring of less-intelligent people</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="38">Less intelligent- less babies than contributors- less "less intelligent people" (and that would always be the case...)</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="39">I completely understand your distaste with the IQ test.</claim>
Again, <premise type="pathos" id="40">I only used the IQ test in my example because so far it is (seemingly) the most available measure of intelligence</premise>.
(<premise type="logos_pathos" id="41">better than SAT scores, right?</premise>)

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="42">And when the IQ test is adjusted, we would adjust the cutoff rate for "da murder" if we were to take that route in the first place.</claim>
(<premise type="logos" id="43">instead of killing lower than 80, it would be killing lower than like 50 or whatever</premise>)
<premise type="logos" id="44">The "number of mental retardation" would be adjusted from lower than 70 to whatever it would be, too,</premise> so <claim type="interpretation" id="45">I don't see your point there</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="46">In total, everyone's IQ would be x points higher and so the human race would be x much smarter...</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="47">My route would be a slower, more ethical way to do it.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cngvajh" author="Namemedickles">

<claim type="interpretation" id="48">Separating intelligence into categories *is* a far better way to go about it</claim>, but <claim type="interpretation" id="49">by it's very nature implies you cannot sum them</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="50">A brilliant mathematician make suck in all other areas such as music ability, linguistic skills, etc. making them look like a retard compared to a guy who is okay at math but also descent in those other categories.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="51">The point is intelligence is too complicated for us to try to breed certain kinds of it.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="52">It is a complex ploygenic trait we still don't fully understand.</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="53">It is also downright silly to consider</claim> since, as we know <premise type="logos" id="54">it isn't really feasible to control the populations genitals in any ethical manner.</premise>

&gt; I only used the IQ test in my example because so far it is (seemingly) the most available measure of intelligence

<claim type="interpretation" id="55">This is not a good reason to use anything.</claim> <premise type="logos" id="56">I know it sucks but I have nothing better does not justify using a sucky measurement.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cngvlik" author="Seventh_______">

1.
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="57">Perhaps, but if we summed it, future generations would be on average smarter than past ones.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="58">If we valued and weighted the categorical intelligences... Perhaps a brilliant mathematician would end up being (weighted) almost equal to a well rounded guy.</premise>

I also would like to add, hopefully <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="59">if we learn more about genetics and genetic engineering we would be able to selectively breed intelligence</claim> (<premise type="logos" id="60">Pass down mathy skills of father and kinesthetic skills of mother or whatever</premise>)

&gt; (The point is intelligence is too complicated for us to try to breed certain kinds of it. It is a complex ploygenic trait we still don't fully understand.)

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="61">Eh, maybe we don't fully understand it, but we know that through breeding we can increase it, right?</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="62">Just because we don't understand every minute aspect of it doesn't mean we can't recognize what parts are positive and how to increase it.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="63">Well hopefully it wouldn't be implemented in a way that forces you to do anything except stop having children after you reached the point where any more and you'd be hurting future generation's intelligence.</premise>
Let me clarify! <claim type="disagreement" id="64">You misinterpreted</claim>, <claim type="agreement" id="65">I wouldn't advocate using the actual IQ scale as the starting measure of doing this at all</claim>, <premise type="logos" id="66">I used it as an example of an intelligence measure</premise>, and <premise type="logos" id="67">I meant most available as the "most available/recognizable example of intelligence"</premise>
<claim type="disagreement" id="68">I do not want our current IQ scale to be used in any way even close to this.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cngvxsd" author="Namemedickles">

<claim type="agreement" id="69">I think you are still oversimplifying it.</claim>
And <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="70">no you can't just increase intelligence through controlling the breeding rights of the population</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="71">Since we do not know the one to one correlations between a complex variety of genes and gene interactions and the vaguely defined intelligence that they produce you cannot feasibly do this.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="72">What if someone with a low intellect (however the hell you measure it) and high intellect want to breed?</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="73">Also, only one of my parents finished high school.</premise>
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="74">I am their 6th child.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="75">I have a Masters degree.</premise>
(<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="76">See my user history for reference</premise>).
<premise type="logos" id="77">We don't know all of the complex genetic and environmental elements that go into intellect to do anything remotely like what you are describing.</premise>

&gt; I also would like to add, hopefully if we learn more about genetics and genetic engineering we would be able to selectively breed intelligence

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="78">I, like some of the other commentators here, find the hypothetical game to be intellectually dishonest.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="79">The "Yeah but what if..." thing just isn't going to fly.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="80">It is not conducive to a productive conversation of this sort.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cngwb5u" author="Seventh_______">

<premise type="logos" id="81">Well if someone of low intellect wanted to breed with someone of high intellect, their children count would be limited by the lower children count.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="82">Later in life, if higher intellect person wants more children, they can, only if they don't have a genetic contributor from someone who already fulfilled their amount?</premise>

<claim type="disagreement" id="83">I think you could increase intelligence through controlling the breeding rights of a population.</claim>
<claim type="agreement" id="84">I don't think its feasible, though...</claim>

Congrats on your degree, but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="85">degrees are no more a measure of intelligence than IQ</claim> (<premise type="logos_pathos" id="86">which kind of is, meaning degrees kind of are</premise>)

<premise type="logos" id="87">We don't know all</premise>, true, but <premise type="logos" id="88">we know some</premise>, <claim type="disagreement" id="89">which should be enough to increase intelligence</claim>.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="90">Maybe the hypothetical game is annoying and not productive, but its not intellectually dishonest...</premise>
<premise type="ethos" id="91">I'm sorry, maybe I shouldn't have posted this topic.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="92">I posted with the actual intent of proving that a hypothetical situation could have eugenics be good.</claim>

*shrug* in the end, are we agreeing that
1. <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="93">Eugenics is not realistically feasible</claim>
2.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="94">But in a hypothetical world where it is feasible, it would be a good thing</claim>
?

</reply>
<reply id="cngwkaa" author="Namemedickles">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="95">Eugenics would work if eugenics worked.</claim>
That's basically all you've said.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="96">Which is basically like saying if unicorns were real, they would be real.</premise>

&gt; Congrats on your degree, but degrees are no more a measure of intelligence than IQ (which kind of is, meaning degrees kind of are)

<claim type="disagreement" id="96a">No</claim>
. <claim type="disagreement" id="97">I think you'll find someone who has a degree in topic X is a much better indicator of their holistic intellectual ability with respect to category X than a simple reductive IQ test.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cngwt8g" author="Seventh_______">

<claim type="agreement" id="98">Yes and yes and sorry :/</claim>
&#8710;

Edit: My view was changed when Namemedickles pointed out how basically my argument depended on changing everything about how something could be implemented to the point of where it is impossible
&gt;Eugenics would work if eugenics worked. That's basically all you've said.

</reply>
</thread>
