<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qtklt">
<title>CMV - Mobile websites are a relic of the early mobile internet era and are inferior to actual websites when using your smartphone.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qtklt/cmv_mobile_websites_are_a_relic_of_the_early/</source>
<OP author="dubalubdub">

Full disclosure I use an iPhone but any smart phone can handle this.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">There isn't a single instance where a mobile website is preferable to a full site</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="1">The information is gutted and moved around</premise> <premise type="logos" id="2">making the site difficult to browse if it's something you are familiar with</premise> and <premise type="logos" id="3">less useful because the information is presented in a mobile-friendly way</premise>.
I believe <premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">smart phones are prevalent enough among phone users who want to use the Internet</premise> that <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="5">it outweighs the "some people don't have smartphones" argument</claim>.
Change my view.

Edit 1: I would like to change my position a little to be <claim type="interpretation" id="6">"Websites should not default force mobile and have the option to go default and instead start default and allow mobile."</claim>

Edit 2: Is it typical of change my view to downvote the ops responses across the thread because you disagree with their view?
<claim type="interpretation" id="7">It's very off putting and doesn't encourage me, as op, to continue discussing my view</claim>.

</OP>
<reply id="cnb1zvj" author="_Ravan_">

As someone from a developing country, I would like to point out that <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="8">mobile sites require less amount of data transfer to view than a desktop site</claim> <premise type="" id="9">which is a big thing for us due to slower Internet connections</premise>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnbkumq" author="dubalubdub">

&#8710; I hadn't considered the obvious fact that <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="10">web sites can be accessed globally and not everyone has the type of network the US enjoys</claim>.

</reply>
</thread>
