<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qslmz">
<title>CMV: There is only one "right" way to play the Mass Effect series (spoilers)</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qslmz/cmv_there_is_only_one_right_way_to_play_the_mass/</source>
<OP author="Magnus64">

*for title clarification, I am NOT referring to either of the paragon or renegade affiliations as the main topic for this post*

The Mass Effect games, however flawed though they may be, are some of my favorite games of all time.
Now that my bias is clear, I want to say that the completely irrational anger that you may see in the post below IS the reason I'd like my view changed.
I apologize for offending anyone and for sounding like an ass.
Needless to say, this post is really only meant for those who've played the series, but if you're not afraid of spoilers then feel free to chime in.

<claim type="agreement" id="0">So here's the brunt of my CMV: If you let any one of your squadmates die, (unless their d</claim>eaths are unavoidable) you are:

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="1">a.) incompetent</claim>

Talk to squadmates semi-regularly, do the loyalty missions, buy the ship upgrades, and -for Gaben's sake- put some points into persuade (you Neanderthal!), and don't make stupid (YES STUPID) choices during the final ME2 mission.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">It's really not that difficult with a little common sense!</premise>
RNG killed Mordin during the suicide mission?
RELOAD A DAMN SAVE.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="3">It's worth it dammit!</premise>

b.) <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="4">rushing/missing the damn point of the game</claim>

Don't give me that "I don't have time" crap; <premise type="logos" id="5">you bought an RPG!</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="6">You're already taking a good bit time to play the game</premise>, so why not take a little more and immerse yourself in the sexy sci-fi universe you paid good money for?
<premise type="logos" id="7">You get so much more out of the experience if you just take the time to explore.</premise>

c.) <claim type="agreement" id="8">unfit to fairly criticize the series</claim>

Firstly, I want to say that <premise type="logos_pathos" id="9">I do agree with most of the criticisms of the plot and that it could have been much better than what it was</premise> (see the original Kapysharn plot outline for details).
However despite its shortcomings, I believe that <claim type="interpretation" id="10">the real heart of the Mass Effect franchise lies not with the story or the narrative, but with its characters</claim>.
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="11">With only a couple exceptions, the vast majority of Shepard's crew are interesting, fleshed-out characters, each with their own flaws and redeeming qualities.</premise>

For example, (SPOILERS ME3) <premise type="logos_pathos" id="12">seeing Wrex grow from a mere gun-for-hire in ME1 to the responsible, yet still badass leader of the Genophage-free Krogan in ME3 was one of the most gratifying experiences of my gaming career.</premise>
Similarly, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="13">the leap of faith Shepard takes when trusting Legion on Rannoch, thus ending hundreds of years of conflict and bringing the Quarians and Geth together was immensely satisfying and could easily qualify for /r/frission material.</premise>

<premise type="pathos" id="14">Without these experiences, yeah, Mass Effect 3 didn't live up to the hype</premise>.
How could it?
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="15">It's such a hollow victory watching Wreav royally screw things up, or watching Tali commit suicide.</premise>
In my opinion, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="16">it's a complete waste of the player's time going about it that way.</claim>
Regardless of paragon or renegade alignment, I believe <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="17">there is one right way to play Mass Effect: a completionist run where NO ONE dies.</claim>

I need help guys.
It's getting to the point where I can't even discuss Mass Effect with others without judging someone for letting my favorite characters bite the bullet.
Hell, I've put one of my friends off playing the games because I was backseat-gaming during his playthrough.
I WANT to believe that games should be played however the player wants to play them, but for whatever reason it's different for me when it comes to Mass Effect in particular.
Please, CMV!

EDIT: Just wanted to say that I don't take issue with making an intentionally flawed Shepard to see what it looks like. It's just I feel that some who were more critical of the game could've missed out on an important and fulfilling character later on because I a mistake, and that could have potentially negatively color their views and the public perception of the game as a whole. 

Bah, apologies! I'm rambling, it's late, but I look forward to catching up with your comments tomorrow first thing! Thanks guys!

</OP>
<reply id="cn96gyu" author="gyrfalcons">

Or maybe you just like plots and characters and different stories.
I'd say my approach was different - <premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="18">if the material is in the game, it's there for a purpose.</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="19">It was there to be seen by players and to be experienced by them.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="20">And sometimes, tragedies are more fun than victories.</claim>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="21">I did do the completionist run!</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="22">I had a closeted gay paragon Shepard because I thought it was hilarious and he eventually shacked up with Kaidan, saved the world, let no one die, then picked destroy ending because why not.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="23">It went - well, okay, I guess.</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="24">However, after that, I wanted some real emotional punches.</premise>
I was *pissed as hell* at the [ME3 ending](http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/17ik93m5xahnwpng/original.png) (and I don't think, as another fan, you'll need me to elaborate on why - I loved those characters and I hated how little involvement they had in how things went, and the ending was a total slap in the face to the player and all their work until that point) so <premise type="logos" id="25">I thought you know what, I want a Shepard where this kind of ending makes sense.</premise>
Where an ending that's a fuck you to everything Shepard's been trying comes as the topping of a fuck you in the chain of everything that Shepard's done.
Where it isn't a betrayal of all the themes that have been brought up so far but the logical extension of them instead.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="26">And so I made the world's giantest asshole most self-justifying Shepard</premise>.
And if you ask me?
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="27">It's about as far as you can get from *your* completionist Shepard</premise>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="28">taken with ME3's ending, I think it makes for a far better story</premise>.
<premise type="pathos" id="29">A renegade lady who wasn't *xenophobic* as much as *very* pro-human, straight but distrusted Jacob and uninterested in any of the alien male love interests (and who killed Kaidan in ME1, woops).</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="30">Who was alone from start to end in a quest that only she seemed to really believe in.</premise>

Trust me, <claim type="disagreement" id="31">when you play a character who's a lot more of an asshole but who's a really *determined* asshole, who keeps losing stuff and who has people die but who convinces herself that it's *worth* something, that her mission has to be worth all that, who is willing to make sacrifices that she believes are necessary (when you, the player, know that they aren't) - the 'bad ends' in ME3 make for a fantastic experience.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="32">It's basically the game going 'well Shepard, you fucked up, and this is what you get for it'.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="33">They're not hollow at all, they're fantastic.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="34">The entire game and story turns into Shepard realizing too late that things could've been different and that the state of the universe going to shit is on *them*.</premise> They lose everyone who trusted them in some way or another, and *hurt* through it all.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="35">The finale of ME3 goes from a completely unsatisfying throughly annoying ending that ignored the themes of choice and self-determination that had been going on through the game into one final, desperate chance to make it right, instead.</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="36">Whatever Shepard picks, I felt a lot more satisfied with *that* story as a whole instead of the 'no one dies' run where it didn't really matter that no one died and that they worked so fucking hard for that - just pick choice A, B or C and that's your ending for you.</premise>

<premise type="logos" id="37">Shitty failure Shepard's ending was also a dialogue choice, but that just underscored that she'd burned and destroyed anything else around her</premise> - that no one else would stand by her side, that everyone was dead and this was all she had left.
<claim type="interpretation" id="38">To me, that kind of ending fit much better with the way I'd played her, and I felt far more vicious satisfaction putting that sort of character through it.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="39">Every other *possible* ending that could've been, she'd gone and wrecked through her own shitty actions.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="40">Losing all the choices at the end made *sense*, this time, in the context of her experiences.</premise>

Anyway, I still enjoyed the everyone-lives playthrough, but I'd say that <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="41">the 'everyone dies' route, seeing as it *is* there, also was meant to be played and in fact works pretty well as an overall story where Shepard is the one that's screwed up the whole way</claim>.
<premise type="ethos_pathos" id="42">I don't think of it as *me* killing of those characters off, it's whatever Shepard I'm playing in that particular runthrough that's doing it - a vicious, angry, bitter and ultimately futile Shepard.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="43">The emotional payoff on finishing the series went from 'are you serious is that actually the ending, the fuck' to 'HAHA YES, Shepard fucking deserved that, that was *great*'.</premise>

TL;DR: <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="44">The right way to play it is to experience everything that is there, and then figure out what makes you the most satisfied.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="45">For me, that wasn't a completionist run.</premise>
I can play as 'saves everyone' Shepard and also as 'total stupid asshole' Shepard - neither of them are me-the-player, they're just the main characters in their own stories.
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="46">The one I find the most hilarious and interesting is the one whose story makes the most sense as a whole, and that's the one where Shepard totally fails save anyone, including herself.</claim>

**Edit:** Also, OP, if you're complaining that people who let companions die miss out on content later in the game, you should consider that as a person who played through ME several times (these weren't actually my only Shepards, I have also tried every romance because I wanted to see what all the fuss was about), I've actually experienced far more of it than you have.
The 'but you see less of it if you do this other route' ignores that you can just *play the game again*.

</reply>
<reply id="cn978q6" author="Magnus64">

&#8710;

Thanks for your post! I suppose I hadn't really though to consider the complexities of a "shitty-Shep" in relation to the flaws of the game itself.
The absence of certain characters is valid too, even though losing squadmembers would be more somber than I'd personally prefer.
Almost poetic in a way, but I think I'll stick to going the long way around if I'm going to invest any time in another (one of at least five runs since it came out, btw) full Mass Effect runthrough. ;)

I suppose I should have mentioned that this would be in the case of a person doing a "final" canon run for THEIR Shep, and making those decisions on who to save and what to do.

</reply>
</thread>
