<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qrlmm">
<title>CMV: Any given aspect of the legal system should be short and simple enough that an average high school graduate could fully memorize it</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qrlmm/cmv_any_given_aspect_of_the_legal_system_should/</source>
<OP author="txwatson">

CLARIFICATIONS BASED ON ANTICIPATED CONFUSION:

(1.) I'm **not** saying simple enough that **all** high school students **should** memorize them; I'm saying <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="0">simple enough that almost anyone could, if they were struck by the impulse to make that unusually large commitment, do so</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">Like, most people don't memorize all of Romeo and Juliet.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">But most people, I think, if they really wanted to, **could.</premise>

(2.)
I'm not interested in hearing any arguments that are based in any way on what the laws are, right now, except by way of comparison.
This includes the constitution.
Seriously -- this isn't what I want to argue here, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">I'm 100% on board with trashing the US constitution and starting from scratch with new documents, so appealing to the constitution is not on topic.</premise>

I'm not a fan of extreme simplification, but <premise type="logos" id="5">I think the American legal system has gotten out of hand in complexity.</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="6">I think the law should be simple enough that close to anybody could reasonably know the mechanics of all the laws likely to apply to them.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="7">Ideally, it should be a relatively simple feat of memorization to learn the names of all the categories of law; the number of laws in each category; and the basic mechanics of the enforcement of that category's laws.</claim>

<premise type="logos" id="8">By categories, I mean things like: criminal law; the tax code; any given category of regulation by profession (medical, construction, IT, and so on).</premise>

I'd be fine with memorizing all the laws being a feat on par with memorizing the Bible; but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="9">it should be well within the average citizen's capacity to know all the laws likely to apply to them, word-for-word or close to it.</claim>

Edit 9:55: CLARIFICATIONS BASED ON CONFUSION THAT HAS OCCURRED:

(1.)
I am not arguing that a shorter legal code is by definition easy to understand.
I am not arguing that the average High School student should be able to achieve a lawyer's level of expertise in any given aspect.
I'm defending the memorization criterion as a way to limit the total length and vagueness of a set of laws.

EDIT 8:35 the following morning: Nobody last night since I went to bed made any points that I haven't already addressed more than once, so I'm done individually responding unless somebody comes up with something new. For the answers to all the posts since I went to bed: see anticipated clarifications 1 and 2, clarification based on actual confusion 1, [this comment,](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qrlmm/cmv_any_given_aspect_of_the_legal_system_should/cn91esr) and literally the name of the subreddit.

</OP>
<reply id="cn8uzj9" author="ghostmcspiritwolf">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="10">many laws regulate things that are simply far too complex to simplify to that level</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="11">It generally takes an undergraduate college level education at minimum to understand something like international financial markets and to then effectively regulate them</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="12">Laws have to be made with a working knowledge of the system and their language will reflect that.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cn8vcxw" author="txwatson">

2nd reply: I will grant that <claim type="agreement" id="13">changing the US laws would not change international laws</claim>, and <claim type="agreement" id="14">the systems of treaties necessary to interface with other countries' economies would be complex in proportion to the complexities of those countries' economic law</claim>.
So, you get a delta for that point.
&#8710; I do think that <premise type="logos" id="15">the actual practice of economics would become drastically simpler if the law were simpler internationally</premise> (in ways that I respect would still be complicated) but I agree with the point you didn't necessarily actually make that <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="16">reforming all the countries' economic legal systems to be simpler in compatible ways at the same time is a way bigger implausibility than reforming just one country's economic law in a way that is self-consistent.</claim>

</reply>
</thread>
