<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qrbaf">
<title>CMV: The theatrical cuts of Lord of the Rings are superior to the extended cuts and should be considered the definitive versions.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qrbaf/cmv_the_theatrical_cuts_of_lord_of_the_rings_are/</source>
<OP author="RYouNotEntertained">

I'll preface this by saying I'm a fan of both the books and movies.
<claim type="interpretation" id="1">I like them both for different reasons</claim>, but <claim type="interpretation" id="2">gun to my head I probably slightly prefer the films.</claim>

(The hobbit movies can S my D though.)

<claim type="agreement" id="3">IMO, the extended cuts seriously throw off the pacing of the films.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">When watching the theatrical cuts, I get swept into the story.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="5">When watching the extended cuts, I get distracted, and reminded that I'm watching a movie.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="6">They break the fourth wall, if you will.</premise>

<premise type="logos" id="7">Peter Jackson agrees with me:</premise>

&gt; The theatrical versions are the definitive versions. I regard the extended cuts as being a novelty for the fans that really want to see the extra material.

&gt; I felt that I was sacrificing pacing and momentum in order for these scenes to go in. 

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="8">The main objection to this, of course, will be that the extended cuts are able to include more scenes from the books, and are therefore better.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="9">Personally, I think it's a huge mistake to judge the quality of an adaptation by how closely it mirrors the source material, rather than by the strength of it's story telling.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="10">The LOTR movies are some of the best adaptations of all time *precisely because* they left a whole lot of the books un-filmed, and a whole lot more on the cutting room floor.</claim>
<premise type="ethos_pathos" id="11">They stretched some scenes from brief chapters into center pieces (Helms's Deep) and cut out some of the more... esoteric portions completely (Tom Bombadil).</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="12">Basically, I'm glad Jackson opted to make excellent **movies,** instead of attempting a shot for shot visualization of a **book,**</claim> and <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="13">I think the extended cuts subvert his success in that regard.</claim>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="14">Books and movies are not the same</premise>, and in general, **the more an adaptation respects the inherent differences between the various media it's adapting to and from, the better the final product will be.*
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="15">*</claim> <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="16">This is much more important than it's faithfulness to the source material.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="17">I believe this is true for all adaptations, not just LOTR.</claim>
Feel free to C my V on this larger point as well.

</OP>
<reply id="cn9b6ar" author="Mavericgamer">

<claim type="interpretation" id="18">I want to point out that I absolutely **could not** stand to read the LotR trilogy.</claim>
<premise type="ethos" id="19">And I tried.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="20">I loved The Hobbit, even though it got slow</premise>, but <premise type="logos" id="21">I found Tolkien's prose to be far too slow-paced and filled with inane babbling about things too far removed from the plot.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="22">I loved the extended edition</claim> because <premise type="logos_pathos" id="23">I get more engaged in an audio-visual medium than I do into books, as a general rule</premise> (this gets suspended for pretty much anything that starts with "Harry Potter and the..." but that's an exception), and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="24">the extended trilogy let me really grasp the world of Middle Earth for the first time.</premise>

And <premise type="logos" id="25">I'm the sort of person who, despite not really liking to read, will read summaries about the world surrounding my favorite movies or video games</premise>, because <premise type="logos" id="26">these are things I *want to know* but typically aren't in the film/game, so I endure the chore.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="27">I *love* that the extended edition helped with this, especially in this situation,</claim> because <premise type="logos_pathos" id="28">most of the answers to that on the internet before were "If you want to know more you should just read the damn books, scrub!" because nerds are like that sometimes.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cn9lo8f" author="RYouNotEntertained">

&#8710;
Thank God you make an exception for HP ;)

Best comment on the thread and you get a delta for pointing out that the extended editions give non-book readers an experience that is closer to the immersion of reading the books.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="29">As a book reader, I'll still be sticking to theatrical cuts though.</claim>

</reply>
</thread>
