<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qr8gn">
<title>CMV: People who cheat on their spouses can and should, in some cases, be forgiven</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qr8gn/cmv_people_who_cheat_on_their_spouses_can_and/</source>
<OP author="Li54">

<premise type="" id="0">There seems to be a commonly held belief that people who cheat on their SO/partner should be dropped immediately with no further contact.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="1">I understand that physical/sexual conduct with another person can seem like a betrayal</claim>, but <premise type="logos" id="2">in some cases, there are many worse things that can happen in a relationship, which couples seem to be able to work through.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="3">There are a few assumptions underlying the belief that "sex with another person = relationship over" that I don't think hold up.</claim>

* <premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">**Sex is the most important part of a relationship,** and therefore, betraying it and that agreement mean the relationship should end.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="5">My belief: sex is a very important part of a relationship, but not *the* most important part.</claim>
Immediately breaking up with someone because of something like this seems excessive.

* <premise type="logos_pathos" id="6">**Nobody makes mistakes ever,** so when they do, the relationship should end.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="7">My belief: obviously this isn't true, and a cornerstone of strong relationships is the ability to work through mistakes/issues together.</claim>

* <premise type="logos_pathos" id="8">**Cheaters will always cheat again,** so better to end it now.</premise> <claim type="interpretation" id="9">my view: That may be true in some cases</claim>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="10">other than anecdotal evidence, I haven't seen anything to support this claim.</premise> [
But would be really interested in reading anything scientific about this, actually!]

* <premise type="logos_pathos" id="11">**Cheaters cheat because of underlying issues with the relationship.**</premise> <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="12">My belief: if that's true, there are a lot of possibilities - not just breaking up - that could fix the problem</claim>, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="13">such as ... talking about the problem.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="14">Maybe fixing that issue will resolve the motivation to cheat.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="15">Caveat: sometimes, cheating happens because there are parts of the relationship that are fundamentally broken and/or the relationship is too far gone/unsalvageable and/or this is the straw the broke the camel's back etc.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="16">Cheating shouldn't always signify an immediate end to a relationship.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="17">In some cases, couples can and should choose to work through it</claim>
CMV!

</OP>
<reply id="cn8tm9p" author="looklistencreate">

<claim type="interpretation" id="19">I don't think this depends as much on the cheater as the person he/she cheated on.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="20">Some people are unable to stay with an unfaithful partner and should not be pressured into continuing a relationship after that point.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="21">Forgiveness depends on the forgiver, not the perpetrator.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="22">Nobody "should" be forgiven for cheating</claim>, and <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="23">I'm comfortable saying that anyone who knowingly betrays the trust of a relationship would deserve losing that relationship.</claim>
<claim type="disagreement" id="24">I wouldn't go so far as to say that it's expected to break up with the cheater</claim>, because <premise type="logos" id="25">some people are willing to be forgiving.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="26">But I can't envision a situation where cheating "should" be forgiven.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="27">Forgiveness is a gift, not an expectation.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cn8tuyn" author="Li54">

&#8710;
This makes the most sense to me - very coherent argument.
Thanks!

</reply>
</thread>
