<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qqxoy">
<title>CMV: Otherkin are delusional and should be treated as such</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qqxoy/cmv_otherkin_are_delusional_and_should_be_treated/</source>
<OP author="EwokHugz">

<premise type="logos" id="0">The DSM-IV defines delusion as:</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">A false belief based on incorrect inference about external reality that is firmly sustained despite what almost everyone else believes and despite what constitutes incontrovertible and obvious proof or evidence to the contrary.</premise>

<claim type="disagreement" id="2">Otherkin, or animalkin, the belief that their soul is an animal or something nonhuman, fit this definition</claim> and <claim type="disagreement" id="3">should be urged to seek psychiatric evaluation rather than joining communities of similar "kin."</claim>

<premise type="logos" id="4">If someone walks around genuinely convinced they are Jesus, the person is delusional</premise> and <premise type="logos" id="5">others would want to see that person medicated or receiving some form of psychiatric treatment for that persons own benefit.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="6">But out of fear of offending and looking like an insensitive bigot, no one would respond to an otherkin in the same way they would someone claiming ultimate divinity.</premise>

<claim type="interpretation" id="7">We should not encourage and accept otherkin behavior, but rather encourage seeking treatment for a delusional disorder.</claim> CMV.

</OP>
<reply id="cn8oez8" author="Holypoopsticks">

<premise type="logos" id="8">Since you mentioned the DSM IV, it is worth pointing out that all of the disorders listed in the DSM IV have one central piece of criteria that is at the heart of the diagnostic process</premise> (which I believe you've missed), and <premise type="logos" id="9">that has to do with the degree to which the disorder is disruptive not only to the person who has the disorder, but to the general public as well</premise> (if you doubt this, read through the criteria for any disorder listed in the DSM).

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="10">Generally speaking, delusions themselves are arguably less relevant to whether or not a behavior is indicative of a disorder than are the social repercussions of that behavior.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="11">Take for instance being "taken by the holy spirit".</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="12">From an outside perspective, this certainly appears to me to be a delusional behavior, but of course this alone is not enough for it to meet the criteria of a particular disorder.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="13">As people can engage in all kinds of delusional behavior and often still function in the world quite well, this is not sufficient evidence for whether or not something should or should not be constituted as evidence of a disorder.</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="14">The belief that one has an animal spirit is not new and has been a component of many primitive animistic cultures throughout history</premise>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="15">certain Native American practices still have vestiges of this</premise>, though <premise type="logos_pathos" id="16">most of us wouldn't describe them as "delusional" simply because they follow the traditions of their ancestors as they've been practiced for centuries.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="17">While you may find the practice disingenuous or disgusting, this is not reason enough to hold the behavior as evidence of a specific disorder in and of itself</claim>, and <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="18">in cases where there may be genuine mental illness involved, I believe that there's enough criteria already set forth in the DSM to diagnose these conditions accurately without directly addressing this particular cultural phenomenon as some kind of mental health outlier.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cn8os38" author="EwokHugz">

&#8710;

<claim type="agreement" id="19">You're right.</claim> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="20">I forgot that one of the main diagnostic criteria for almost any mental disorder is the impact it has on the persons well-being</premise>, and
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="21">if someone is generally in a better state identifying as an otherkin, then there would be no real need to treat them, unless they started disrupting the lives of others.</claim>

</reply>
</thread>
