<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qnu4z">
<title>CMV: The highest form of relationship between men and women doomed to be romance</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qnu4z/cmv_the_highest_form_of_relationship_between_men/</source>
<OP author="Skinners_Pidgeon">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">Maybe it has to do with being an adolescent and being new to dealing with the opposite sex</claim>, but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="1">I'm beginning to fall under the assumption that the only purpose for guys to get to know girls is to eventually engage in romance.</claim>

<premise type="pathos" id="2">"Why else do men engage women in conversation in public?"</premise> I wonder (<claim type="interpretation" id="3">my perception might just be distorted after reading Neil Strauss's *The Game*</claim>).
"<premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">Why do I feel like chasing after girls and getting to know them when I have so many great guy friends already who I know care about me so much more?</premise> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="5">Why can't I be friends with girls (even pretty ones) and not feel insecure when I don't try to advance some romantic agenda?</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="6">Why do I find myself inevitably becoming attracted to them?</premise>"

<claim type="agreement" id="7">I have so many more questions regarding the non-romantic side of male-female relationships</claim>, but <claim type="agreement" id="8">instead of writing an abhorrent block of text nobody could possibly be expected to read, I ask just the one title question</claim> (thinking that <claim type="agreement" id="9">the above questions are more like fragments of a bigger picture of misunderstanding</claim>) <premise type="logos" id="10">because I want to know what older, more mature people think</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="11">It also must distort my view to have gone to an all-boy's school for the majority of my life.</claim>

At times, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="12">I feel like the interplay between men and women is always (at least always initially) a bs game</claim> where <premise type="logos_pathos" id="13">the man tries to show the woman how non-threatening and valuable he is from a non-romantic standpoint before she is comfortable with allowing herself to think of him as a safe partner</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="14">Something about that seems so sinister, cynical, and hollow to me</premise> that <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="15">I can't stand it</claim>.
Please change this view.

</OP>
<reply id="cn7wrhe" author="inconspicuous_bear">

Id just like to point out that <claim type="disagreement" id="16">this has never remotely seemed the case from my perspective as a lesbian</claim>.
Beyond that, <claim type="disagreement" id="17">there are many people who want close relationships without romance</claim>, <premise type="logos" id="18">an obvious example would be asexual people</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="19">They can have close relationships that rival that of marriage</premise>, but <premise type="logos" id="20">how would you even quantify that</premise>?
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="21">How can you even compare them?</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="22">What about the relationship of a brother and sister?</premise>

If you <premise type="pathos" id="23">limit it to just heterosexual non-related men and women</premise>, then <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="24">maybe you're right</claim>, but then again <premise type="pathos" id="25">who is to say what form of relationship is the highest, two very close lifetime friends who are platonic or a married couple?</premise>

The bottom line is that <claim type="interpretation" id="26">people are different from you</claim> can <claim type="interpretation" id="27">relationships are hard to compare</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="28">Maybe for you, every relationship with a woman is motivated by romance.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="29">For someone other hetero guy it might not be.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="30">Sexual attraction is not something that just shuts off</claim> so even if <premise type="logos_pathos" id="31">you're in a lifelong comitted closed relationship</premise> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="32">you'll still probably feel attraction for other people</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="33">Thats just reality for most people</claim>, and <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="34">its not necesarily harmful and its not really shallow.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="35">There are very few absolutes when it comes to interpersonal relationships.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cn7yycg" author="Skinners_Pidgeon">

&#8710;

In short, <premise type="ethos_logos" id="36">I don't need to feel guilty when I'm attracted to people I know I can't have?</premise>
Maybe <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="37">I'm too black-and-white to think that the murmurs of my id are natural and not evil</claim>.

As for which relationship is *higher* from a quantifiable standpoint, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="38">I see what you mean</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="39">When I said highest, I meant it not from a perspective of quantity of some sort</premise>, but of <premise type="logos" id="40">a level of worth</premise>.
Looking at that statement, however, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="41">I think you're right</claim> again--<premise type="logos_pathos" id="42">who is to put a romantic relationship above a friendship?</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="43">It's a bit extreme and morbid</premise>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="44">if I were to put someone's spouse and someone's absolute best friend in front of a train and gave that person one to save, whom would they save?</premise>
Maybe I just find that <premise type="logos_pathos" id="45">once I reach a certain threshold with a guy-friend, I find that we become best friends</premise>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="46">when I reach that threshold with a girl-friend, I find that I want more</premise>.
Maybe <premise type="logos_pathos" id="47">I haven't been around the block enough or had enough female friends to feel this way</premise>.
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="48">I don't have any lesbian friends (as far as I know at least)</premise>, so <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="49">I don't know how I would react to being great friends with one.</claim>

</reply>
</thread>
