<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qncj3">
<title>CMV Me joining the army is not a waste of time nor does it conflict with my personality</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qncj3/cmv_me_joining_the_army_is_not_a_waste_of_time/</source>
<OP author="Hamza78ch11">

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="0">I've always had a respect for the men in uniform and I've always wanted to join.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="1">Recently I've disagreed with the practices of the U.S. military</claim> but that doesn't mean that I hate the Warriors, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">just the people that force them into it</premise>.
<premise type="ethos" id="1a">I'm an immigrant and a Muslim neither of which is or should be a deterrent from joining</premise>.
<premise type="ethos" id="1b">I want to be a doctor, not because of familial pressure but of a genuine need to help</premise>.
So here's where I am now: currently in first year of college studying biology, enough AP credits to be a tiny bit ahead of my classmates, an itching to explore this giant world God gave me, I'm also poor and medical school in the military (from what I understand) pays for smart kids.
Also, please forgive me if this is wrong or arrogant or whatever, I want the respect that people give men and women in the military.

My plan was to graduate College and join the USHS (the military medical school) and become and Army doctor.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3">The only reservation that I had was that it would be a waste of my time</claim> <premise type="pathos" id="4">because I want to be a neurosurgeon and that's a looooooooong and rigorous path</premise> and that <premise type="pathos" id="5">I might be losing precious time by joining the military</premise>.
My mom doesn't want me to join for that reason.
Other things that I've considered: <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="6">I love the idea of a brotherhood but I don't agree with the ideology,</claim> <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="7">the military putting me through Med school will help me jump start life,</claim> <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="8">I'm very inexperienced and haven't seen much of the world and this I think will help me</claim>.

I look forward to having my views challenged!
Thanks!

</OP>
<reply id="cn7tqy5" author="AgnosticKierkegaard">
&gt;My plan was to graduate College and join the USHS (the military medical school) and become and Army doctor.

<premise type="logos" id="9">FYI, you don't have to go to USHS to be a military doctor.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="10">You can go to civilian medical school, and get HPSP which is slightly different but accomplishes roughly the same thing.</premise>

&gt;The only reservation that I had was that it would be a waste of my time because I want to be a neurosurgeon and that's a looooooooong and rigorous path and that I might be losing precious time by joining the military. 

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="11">Well, it's not worth it for the money</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="12">. You'll lose money by taking HPSP and especially with USHS (a longer commitment than HPSP).</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="13">You'll owe the military tons of time for the training, so you won't be able to enter civilian practice for years.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="14">Civilian neurosurgeons will easily catch up to their debtless peers in the military due to the huge difference in salaries.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="15">A civilian neurosurgeon can make over 400k easily.</premise>
A military surgeon will never see that much.
<claim type="interpretation" id="16">So, with NSRGY you will have a net loss in the military compared to a civilian path with loans</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="17">This is assuming you get a neurosurgery residency in the military, which is suspect.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="18">Neurosurgery is already competitive, and the military's neurosurgery residencies are extremely limited.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="19">You may end up as a general surgeon, or doing several GMO tours before starting your 7 year neurosurgery residency.</premise>

&gt;Other things that I've considered: I love the idea of a brotherhood but I don't agree with the ideology

<premise type="logos" id="20">If you're not all in with the military you'll hate being a military doctor.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="21">The only reason to do HPSP or USHS is because you want to be a doctor in the military, not because you want the money.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="22">If you're ambivalent the risk is too great.</premise>

&gt;I'm also poor and medical school in the military (from what I understand) pays for smart kids. 

<premise type="logos" id="23">Banks have zero problem giving out loans to medical students.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="24">You'll easily cover your tuition, and while debt sucks you'll easily pay it off after residency.</premise>

In short, don't do it unless you are 100% committed to spending about a decade and a half in the military in a speciality that might not even necessarily be NSRGY

</reply>
<reply id="cn7ug34" author="Hamza78ch11">

&#916; That whipped me around real fast.
I guess it's more about being a military doctor rather than a doctor in the military.
Thanks!

</reply>
</thread>
