<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qmstv">
<title>CMV: The Call of Duty franchise is extremely overrated and overhyped.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qmstv/cmv_the_call_of_duty_franchise_is_extremely/</source>
<OP author="Inita_Life">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">I'd like to start off by saying that the CoD games are good games in their own right,</claim> though <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="1">they are extremely overhyped</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">One reason I take this stance is because the newly released games are ectremely similar to their predecessors.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="3">There are few if any changes in gameplay, and the basic level design for the most part, remains the same.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">Even Advanced Warfare, which seemed to promise the most novel changes, was criticized for changing too little from its preceding games.</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="5">Another reason for my opinion is that CoD doesn't really have anything astoundingly different from other games of the same genre.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="6">There are a few unique features here and there, but overall, it's just another FPS with nothing spectacular that sets it above the other games in its genre.</premise>

</OP>
<reply id="cn7jcik" author="_OccamsChainsaw">

Let me address this by pointing one thing out: <claim type="interpretation" id="7">numbers don't lie.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="8">With absolutely anything, there will always be things that people that aren't a fan of.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="9">Make major changes and instead of Person A hating the series and Person B loving it, now Person A loves it and Person B hates it.</premise>
You're entirely in your right to feel that CoD is overrated, and personally it seems futile to change this view.
You like what you like
. I can only provide objective points to maybe calibrate your perspective.

So back to numbers don't lie.
<premise type="logos" id="10">Consider the goal the creators of CoD have.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="11">To make money.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="12">And they consistently perform this goal well year after year.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="13">Now, you're an executive of Activision-Blizzard.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="14">Why would you tell the developers to do a complete 180 on the series, "for change's sake."?</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="15">You only run risk and very little reward.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="16">If you stick to the tried and true model they've had, you're very nearly guaranteed to make a certain amount of sales. I'm sure they can graph the sales of each subsequent game and make predictions to the gradual decline with each passing year as more and more individuals grow bored of the CoD formula.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="17">Really, your view of "overrated and overhyped" is nothing more than an idiosyncratic reflection of your own *personal* threshold for formulaic video games.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="18">But this view is separate from the objective success of the series.</claim>
<premise type="pathos" id="19">If they keep selling games, it means people still enjoy the series for what it is.</premise>
The idiom, "Don't fix what isn't broken" comes to mind.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="20">There are more people who still like the series and will buy new iterations without much change compared to the minority who do find it cliche, hackneyed, etc.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="21">I mean, be realistic here, if they promised the most radically new CoD next year, would you buy it?</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="22">Probably not.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="23">You have a bias against the series.</premise>
<premise type="" id="24">Why would their target audience be the people who *don't* like CoD?</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="25">It makes no sense.</premise>

<claim type="interpretation" id="26">The other major point is that video game development is extremely expensive.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="27">Making an entirely new engine is costly, takes years to develop, and you never have a guarantee of financial success upon release.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="28">It makes more sense to stick with the old engine and old code, which drastically reduces the time (and therefore cost) it takes to make a new game.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="29">Brand new engine CoDs likely wouldn't make sufficiently more money to offset their cost to make it.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="30">They aren't a charity, so gamers aren't entitled to it.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cn7l0zz" author="Inita_Life">

Hmm... I understand your point.
<claim type="interpretation" id="31">And your explanation on why the series' games are extremely similar to each other is superb.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="32">However, this in itself isn't why I think the games are overrated.</claim>
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="33">Many other game serie use a formulaic system for their games that renders them very similar to each other, such as Assassin's Creed, or Pokemon.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="34">The thing about CoD that really makes it an overrated series is that it is very similar to other FPS games, such as Battlefield.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="35">It really doesn't have any revolutionary groundbreaking features of its own,</claim> and <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="36">each game feeds off the success of its predecessor.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cn7le2a" author="_OccamsChainsaw">

Then to that, the only thing I can offer is the historical context of CoD. <premise type="logos" id="37">It was the first FPS to really popularize the RPG elements of progression and grow multiplayer FPS to the size that it is.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="38">Halo may have been the first of its kind at the time, but CoD created a very effective system where you leveled up, unlocked new guns, and gave you customization in your load out.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="39">When considering the first few CoDs, this was massive and largely is attributed to its success.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="40">It turned multiplayer FPS from a niche genre to if not the largest genre.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="41">One can argue some earlier games like Counterstrike did something similar much sooner, for some reason CoD popularized it.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="42">Brought it to the mainstream.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="43">It's not so much that CoD is similar to other FPS as other FPSs largely copied their model.</claim>
<premise type="pathos" id="44">Hell, consider Halo 4 that changed their fundamental mechanics to match more of a CoD pace and include load outs and level progression.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="45">It's a large statement that such a dedicated fanbase Halo had moved toward the direction of CoD. Given CoD's immense popularity, everyone wanted to jump on the bandwagon of its success.</premise>

<premise type="logos" id="46">To view CoD as overrated for being the series that really grew the genre to what it is today would be to say WoW is overrated given how many MMOs are similar.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="47">When you consider there were a select few MMOs before WoW that failed to mainstream and popularize the genre, and the immense number of WoW clones after its success, it's not fair to say WoW is overrated.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="48">It's iconic in its genre.</premise>
<claim type="agreement" id="49">It's the copies and general state of the genre today that is overrated and hackneyed.</claim>

Same with CoD. <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="50">I feel that your view isn't so much feeling that CoD is overrated as it is that you feel multiplayer FPS is overrated.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cn859xf" author="Inita_Life">

&#8710; Okay, this is good.
I definitely see your point.
CoD was the progenitor for what we now know as the FPS genre, rather than a copycat with better graphics.

</reply>
</thread>
