<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qmhw7">
<title>CMV: Posting nude pictures online is caused by a need for attention and not empowering</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qmhw7/cmv_posting_nude_pictures_online_is_caused_by_a/</source>
<OP author="partyp00per69">

Let me make this clear before I continue, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">I am not saying that people are not allowed to do what they like.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="1">I don't care if people post nudes, I'm just saying that this is how I feel when I see people posting nudes.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="2">Also, I don't mean to suggest that there is anything wrong with posting nudes.</claim>
<claim type="disagreement" id="3">Lastly, I have nothing wrong with nudity and am in fact a fan of nudity, I just don't understand exposing yourself to the entirety of the internet on a whim.</claim>

<claim type="interpretation" id="4">Whenever I see anyone, male or female, posting nude pictures on the internet, I immediately assume that they are somehow seeking attention.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="5">Of course, that's the point, but I think that it must stem from some underlying need to get attention that they must either be lacking in some other part of their life</claim>, or <premise type="logos_pathos" id="6">simply need because that's their personality and that they feed off of attention.</premise>

Specifically in the case with women, many of my female friends, including my girlfriend (hence the throwaway) , have posted nudes and any time I ask them why, they somehow defend it with "it makes me feel good."
Of course, I ask them why it makes them feel good and most either don't have an answer or somehow deay it makes them feel empowered as a woman who is proud of her body.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="7">I don't understand how posting images of yourself naked, often with the understanding that others will masturbate to you (/r/gonewild for example) is not empowering but instead a form of whoring yourself out in a sense.</premise>

So reddit, why do people post nudes? I seriously can't grasp the concept in a way that justifies this action, and have come into conflict with female friends and my gf and would like to be able to see this from another angle.

Thanks in advance.

EDIT:  Thank you for all of the replies!  You guys pointed out some clearly fallacious opinions I had and also showed me a multitude of other views on the issue.  This is a very personal issue that only pertains to my own beliefs and not something I go around spouting to others.  This was a good learning experience for myself, so again thank you all.  I have deltas to those I felt really stuck with the discussion, but I'd like to thank you all for commenting.

</OP>
<reply id="cn7gkjs" author="ExploreMeDora">

<premise type="logos" id="8">It depends on the person.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="9">One person can be incredibly confident with his/her private parts.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="10">Therefore, the person is eager to show off and get some attention.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="11">However, most people are not quite as endowed or gifted as these attention-seekers.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="12">It's an empowering feeling to be so comfortable with yourself (endowed or not) that you are proud to post nude photos.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="13">The compliments feel great as well!</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="14">In this sense, it is not done for attention.</claim>
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="15">After all, most people choose to remain anonymous -so what attention are they really getting?</premise>

<premise type="logos" id="16">You're also forgetting the tremendous amount of sexual energy that factors into posting nude photos.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="17">People enjoy browsing other's nude photos, so they decide to contribute some of their own.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="18">It gives them pleasure to know that other people get pleasure by seeing the posted photos.</premise>
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="19">Again, this is more empowering than attention-seeking.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cn7gx89" author="partyp00per69">

<claim type="agreement" id="20a">I agree that people enjoy showing off</claim>, in any context, but <premise type="logos" id="20">isn't that stool a form of attention seeking?</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="21">Being proud of something (which in the case of nudes, like breast size, is sometimes uncontrollable and not something that one has to work for to attain that pride) is different than showing it off.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="22">I'm proud of my own genitals but I have no need to show them to anyone other than my girlfriend who I want to enjoy them.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="23">The difference I see is between pride and attention seeking behavior caused by pride.</premise>

<claim type="agreement" id="23a">You so make a good point about the sexual energy.</claim>
I completely overlooked this part of the equation.
<premise type="logos" id="24">Of course, for those in relationships or some kind of monogamous partnership, I understand the sexual energy between sharing and receiving sexual images between each other.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="25">In the example of the monogamous partnership, I do not consider that type of behavior as being attention seeking or anything because it is meant to be between the two individuals for their own mutual sexual pleasure.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="26">The difference between that scenario (which I think most people can agree with) and posting nudes online is that often someone will post an image and an unknown amount of people may see it and get pleasure from it.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="27">Nudes end up all over the internet and going into that situation,</premise> a nudes-poster should anticipate this.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="28">In anticipating this inevitability, aren't they then giving away they're nudes essentially for anyone to recurve sexual pleasure from?</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="29">I see that behavior as attention seeking</claim> because <premise type="ethos_logos" id="30">what they get in return is the gratification of strangers admitting their nudity without the mutual respect in return.</premise>

In regard to your comment anonymity, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="31">I don't see it as one wanting to gain some type of status from it attached to themselves, but instead the gratification of having others pleasure themselves to their nudity.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="32">For example, internet trolls work on the basis of causing as much fuss and attention as possible while often remaining anonymous.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="33">They are not trying to get attention toward themselves superficially, but they're instead attention seeking to just get the attention of others.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cn7h4vg" author="ExploreMeDora">
&gt; I have no need to show them to anyone other than my girlfriend who I want to enjoy them.

So you want to show them off to your girlfriend so she will enjoy them.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="34">Do you do this to seek attention from her?</premise>
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="35">Or do you do it because it is empowering?</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="36">It makes you feel good when she tells you how impressed she is with your junk and when she gets pleasure from it.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="37">Other people don't have partners to do this with so they resort to the internet.</premise>
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="38">Some people even have partners and still do it.</premise>
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="39">It's a thrill and a risk that gives people immense pleasure.</premise>

&gt; In anticipating this inevitability, aren't they then giving away they're nudes essentially for anyone to recurve sexual pleasure from? 

<premise type="logos" id="40">They are not getting any attention though, since they usually remain anonymous.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="41">Also, when it is spread online you hardly ever find out who has seen it or what people think of it.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="42">Therefore, you may never be able to recognize the attention you get.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="43">Just the act of posting the photo is enough to drive some people wild, whether 1 person sees it or 1,000.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cn7hbl1" author="partyp00per69">

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="44">I want to show them to my girlfriend because I know that it makes her think of our sexual activities and I'm trying to make her think about that to remind her off how it feels good physically and to be close with her in a sexual way</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="46">I don't do it to bring attention to myself, but rather to our relationship.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="47">This is much different from posting a photo that a tension stranger will masturbate to.</claim>

<premise type="logos" id="48">Like I've said, isn't the garnering of any attention on the internet from your nudes photos still seeking the attention of others?</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="49">It doesn't matter how many strangers see it, just the fact that they are strangers.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="50">I think the anonymity of the internet allows people to freely get the attention without worrying about the recognition or views of friends and family, so they're purposely looking for attention they can't find within their immediate relationships.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cn7hhym" author="ExploreMeDora">

<claim type="agreement" id="51">You do it because you get pleasure from your girlfriend being into you and your sexual relationship.</claim>
<claim type="disagreement" id="52">This is empowering, not attention seeking.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="53">Other people do it because they get pleasure from strangers masturbating to it.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="54">This is empowering, not attention seeking.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="55">Just because you don't find it empowering to post nudes, doesn't mean other people won't.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="56">It's impossible to assert that everyone who has posted nudes does it strictly for attention.</premise>
Similarly, I have sent photos of this nature to various girls who I was not dating.
However, I have never posted nudes online.
I'm somewhere in between this spectrum.
<claim type="interpretation" id="57">I can guarantee you I was not trying to get attention from these girls, and nor was I trying to make them think of our sexual activities or remind them of sex (impossible since I didn't live near them).</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="58">I enjoyed their compliments, knowing that they received pleasure, and seeing their photos as well.</claim>
<claim type="disagreement" id="59">Sexting is an entirely separate entity that has it's own set of motivations.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cn7hqlv" author="partyp00per69">

I guess a big issue that others here have pointed out is my distinction between empowering and attention seeking.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="60">I just don't understand that you're of behavior and since I have never partaken in it I just can't grasp it.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="61">The trouble I have is that I don't get a good enough perspective from those that do post nudes online.</claim>
<claim type="agreement" id="62a">You're right about the sexting thing</claim>, and that's where, as I stated in another comment, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="62">the fine line ice drawn is hard to find and relatively ambiguous.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="63">Of course, I have no issue with sexting, considering I do it often,</premise> <claim type="interpretation" id="64">so I guess in that sense I can sort of understand the stance one would receive from posting nudes.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cn7hwsq" author="ExploreMeDora">

<premise type="ethos_pathos" id="65">Just as I don't necessarily understand the joy of exhibitionism, exhibitionists don't understand how I *don't* find joy from it.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="66">Since I am so unaccustomed to it and do not partake in it, I can't make an uninformed judgement about it.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="67">I am not going to tell that person that he/she is doing it for attention - because frankly - I have no clue why exactly the person does it (the person may not even know either)!</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cn7idtc" author="partyp00per69">

<claim type="agreement" id="68">Thats very true.</claim>
I guess I just doubt understand.
Of course, I don't share these opinions with others, I'm just saying that it's hard to get over these opinions I have.

You've definitely helped me see this from other angles.
<claim type="interpretation" id ="69">Applying it to my own life and what I personally do is a good way to assess not only this situation, but any situation in general.</claim>
Thank you.

I think this is how I award you a delta?
&#916;

</reply>
</thread>
