<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qmhw7">
<title>CMV: Posting nude pictures online is caused by a need for attention and not empowering</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qmhw7/cmv_posting_nude_pictures_online_is_caused_by_a/</source>
<OP author="partyp00per69">

Let me make this clear before I continue, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">I am not saying that people are not allowed to do what they like.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="1">I don't care if people post nudes, I'm just saying that this is how I feel when I see people posting nudes.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="2">Also, I don't mean to suggest that there is anything wrong with posting nudes.</claim>
<claim type="disagreement" id="3">Lastly, I have nothing wrong with nudity and am in fact a fan of nudity, I just don't understand exposing yourself to the entirety of the internet on a whim.</claim>

<claim type="interpretation" id="4">Whenever I see anyone, male or female, posting nude pictures on the internet, I immediately assume that they are somehow seeking attention.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="5">Of course, that's the point, but I think that it must stem from some underlying need to get attention that they must either be lacking in some other part of their life</claim>, or <premise type="logos_pathos" id="6">simply need because that's their personality and that they feed off of attention.</premise>

Specifically in the case with women, many of my female friends, including my girlfriend (hence the throwaway) , have posted nudes and any time I ask them why, they somehow defend it with "it makes me feel good."
Of course, I ask them why it makes them feel good and most either don't have an answer or somehow deay it makes them feel empowered as a woman who is proud of her body.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="7">I don't understand how posting images of yourself naked, often with the understanding that others will masturbate to you (/r/gonewild for example) is not empowering but instead a form of whoring yourself out in a sense.</premise>

So reddit, why do people post nudes? I seriously can't grasp the concept in a way that justifies this action, and have come into conflict with female friends and my gf and would like to be able to see this from another angle.

Thanks in advance.

EDIT:  Thank you for all of the replies!  You guys pointed out some clearly fallacious opinions I had and also showed me a multitude of other views on the issue.  This is a very personal issue that only pertains to my own beliefs and not something I go around spouting to others.  This was a good learning experience for myself, so again thank you all.  I have deltas to those I felt really stuck with the discussion, but I'd like to thank you all for commenting.

</OP>
<reply id="cn7h6kk" author="IIIBlackhartIII">

<claim type="interpretation" id="8">What you're really seeming to say is that any action which garners attention is morally corrupt.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="9">You've drawn this fine line where something that is done for attention cannot also be done for empowerment, which I find to be the crux of your dilemma.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="10">If someone is confident in their body, is it not empowering to have other people give you reassurance of that position?</premise>
<premise type="" id="11">The definition of empowering is to "make (someone) stronger and more confident".</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="12">If the feedback about their bodies does that, then so be it.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="13">People seem to get very morally judgmental about how the internet has made us all so much more open.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="14">We share so much and censor so much less... but why is this necessarily a bad thing?</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="15">If no harm is done, what problem is there in using the internet for such exchange?</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="16">Like it or not, the platforms websites have provided have made a level playing field for anyone to find some kind of minor 'celebrity', with a paparazzi of their anonymous peers.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="17">If the attrition of that kind of fan base is what empowers her, so be it.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="18">It may be complex for those in relationships who want more exclusivity, but that's more an interpersonal problem than a denial of empowerment.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cn7hjrk" author="partyp00per69">

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="19">I personally am against the openness that society has taken with the internet</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="20">.</claim> I do not participate in most social media besides reddit, and even then I mostly lurk.
Regardless, <claim type="interpretation" id="21">I think that this openness is not detrimental per se, but is just a display of someone's character.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="22">Like I said, I have no*problem* with anyone posting nudes,</claim> <claim type="interpretation" id="23">I just immediately view them differently as one seeking attention.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="24">There are plenty of other ways to garner positive attention that everyone can agree is positive, instead of morally questionable behavior.</premise>
Of course no harm is done, but often this type of behavior CAN come back to haunt the original poster in a number of ways.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="25">Also, why is gaining a celebrity status for something like posting nudes empowering?</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="26">What about that makes someone feel good?</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="27">When I see that type of situation I see someone who knowingly is attractive, considering they have a high status, and is willing to sexually pleasure their followers via this attractiveness that they already know they have.</claim>

I understand that a lot of the issues I raise are personal opinions not shared by others which is why I asked in the first place.
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="28">I as a person have a hard time seeing through other people's eyes if I can't justify a logical reason to do it.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="29">I just don't see any reason in this type of behavior.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="30">Also, I think that some of my problem is, like you said, the fine line I have drawn.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="31">The lines I tend to draw in life are ambiguous and hard to support which often results in a weak basis for my opinions.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="32">Hence, my seeking of others opinions.</premise>
Thanks for your reply.

</reply>
<reply id="cn7hxwe" author="IIIBlackhartIII">
&gt; There are plenty of other ways to garner positive attention that everyone can agree is positive, instead of morally questionable behavior.

<claim type="interpretation" id="33">And yet this is just the interplay of societal values.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="34">Let us not forget that during the Renaissance there was a huge movement for the exploration of the human form as a work of art.</premise>
<premise type="ethos" id="35">Much of the surviving ancient sculptures and paintings show the nakedness of the human form, and this art compares us to heroes and gods as did much of the writing and philosophy of the time as we tried to figure out our "meaning" in the universe.</premise>
<claim type="disagreement" id="36">Now of course, this is a romantic view of history which takes the surviving works of outstanding people, rather than looking towards the common man...</claim> but
<claim type="disagreement" id="37">certainly that is a point to be made about the modern time as well.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="38">What makes modern sexuality morally abhorrent?</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="39">What logical basis is there for the rejection of the human form and the demonizing those who are open about their sexual identity?</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="40">Slut shaming, or as you did, calling it as "whoring"?</premise>

<claim type="agreement" id="41">Certainly in America there is a huge bias against such things,</claim> but <premise type="ethos_logos" id="42">the basis of that has been our periodic pushes from the church, periods of "Great Awakening" where fundamentalists have tried to restore us to some kind of repressive god-fearing and internalized state of self loathing and cleansing for sin.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="43">Beyond some shell of spirituality, there is no real objective reasoning to be so opposed to sex.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="44">In fact if you look towards Europe, a lot of their media is much more lenient on sex than violence, whereas over here we're more lenient on violence than sex.</premise>

&gt; Of course no harm is done, but often this type of behavior CAN come back to haunt the original poster in a number of ways.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="45">The only ways I can think of are people trying to go back and find those pictures and use them against a person as some kind of ad-hominem attack in the public.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="46">This again, though, goes back to a culture which seems unreasonably biased towards sex.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="47">There's this mystique and taboos surrounding it's open discussion which involve shaming and peer pressure, bullying and non-sense.</claim>
Why?
<premise type="logos" id="48">Even you've admitted you can't really articulate it you just feel this way because you *just do*. Which is no basis for a logical or reasonable way to think about the world.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cn7invu" author="partyp00per69">

Thanks for your replies. I learned a lot from this thread, and specifically from your comments.

Thanks again &#916;

</reply>
</thread>
