<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qh719">
<title>CMV: If you're able, European and subscribe even loosely to European values, you should be on the Ukrainian border, driving back Russians</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qh719/cmv_if_youre_able_european_and_subscribe_even/</source>
<OP author="TheCyanKnight">

Obviously I'm not there right now, but I'm curious if anyone can put my mind at ease that I shouldn't be.

<claim type="interpretation" id="0">Feels to me as if Putin senses weakness in the Western world</claim>, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">with the US and Europe driven farther apart by issues like privacy and human rights,</premise> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">the US withdrawing as a dominant force in geopolitics,</premise> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="3">because people in and outside of the US are fed up with the US policing the world.</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="4">His territorial pissings seems to be meant to elbow some room for himself on the geopolitical stage, in other words gaining power.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="5">Putin is a totalitarian, oppressive, ruthless man, and allowing him to gain more power will affect all of us.</claim>

</OP>
<reply id="cn63zdl" author="HJD8d9d">

<claim type="disagreement" id="6">I doubt anyone on the Ukrainian front actually wants a bunch of untrained Europeans to show up and start attacking anything that looks vaguely Russian.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="7">This just won't help the situation in any way.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="8">If you really want to help, sending money you earn with something you're actually good at (your job) is far more helpful.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="9">Another thing you can do is to tell your government to send (military) aid.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="10">Neither things are as cool as fighting Russians out of a moral sense of duty, but they're far more effective.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="11">The above assumes that the Europeans should get more involved with the Ukrainian conflict.</claim>
<claim type="agreement" id="12">While I agree that that might be the moral thing to do,</claim> <claim type="disagreement" id="13">we should be very careful not to escalate the conflict.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="14">You should not underestimate how threatened Russia feels by the West's expansion into what used to be a buffer zone.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="15">Whether that feeling and their reaction are justified or not doesn't really matter; the fact is that a proxy war between Europe and Russia would be disastrous.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cn64ay7" author="TheCyanKnight">

Awarding a &#8710; for making me realize that intention to fight back Russians doesn't automatically mean you can do so effectively, and that it's the most effective thing to do.

My view has not utterly and definitely changed for the following reasons:

<premise type="logos" id="16">Telling my government to send help is easier said than done.</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="17">Not everybody will make enough that his financial support will outweigh the military support he can provide, this is a definite nuance to my general initial statement though.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="18">Supporting foreign militaries financially also has proven sketchy at best in the past, because it's hard to control where the weapons eventually end up.</premise>

I still needs convincing that supporting the currently ongoing fight is actually escalating the conflict.
<premise type="logos" id="19">Putin knows very well that he's transgressing.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="20">If that's quelled quickly and effectively, things will get back to normal, whereas if he gets away with it, he might push and push to see how far he can go.</premise>

</reply>
</thread>
