<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qgpie">
<title>CMV: Progress in automation will eventually lead to a full fledge genocide on the majority of the population.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qgpie/cmv_progress_in_automation_will_eventually_lead/</source>
<OP author="Prometheus_v2">

<premise type="logos" id="0">[47% of all jobs are at risk of being automated](http://motherboard.vice.com/blog/the-rich-and-their-robots-are-about-to-make-half-the-worlds-jobs-disappear).</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">This number will grow grow until the vast majority of people become obsolete for jobs.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">Since some of this automation will inevitably come to weapons, the wealthy will have the perfect opportunity to commit genocide on the 99%.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="3">By fortifying themselves in their gated communities with rows upon rows of automated defences, all unburdened by humans with consciences and families, they can simply wait for everyone to starve or get killed while they bask in their machine generated wealth.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">Once everyone is dead, they can simply be wiped from history.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="5">You, me, everyone will have never existed.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="6">A crime completely erased.</premise>

[I am not the only one to predict this outcome](https://www.jacobinmag.com/2011/12/four-futures/) (see the last section on "exterminism"). I don't think the other more optimistic futures expressed in that article will come to pass given current mentalities.
I think it's also too late to stop it.
Those who will fight it will lose.
Please CMV so I can have hope again.

</OP>
<reply id="cn620d0" author="isleepinahammock">

You remember that old phrase from Forest Gump, "a man only needs so much money, the rest is just for showing off."
Well that's actually quite true.

<premise type="pathos" id="7">Throughout history, people tend to use their wealth to show off how much wealth they have.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="8">The status symbols change over time, but the existence of status symbols doesn't.</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="9">There was a time, say in the 18th century, where the elite would wear quite elaborate clothing.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="10">Check out this picture of [Louis XIV](http://www.paradoxplace.com/Photo%20Pages/France/France_History/Images/Louis-XIV-BAR800.jpg).</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="11">He's dressing in elaborate, fantastical clothing to tell everyone, "look how rich and powerful I am.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="12">I can afford to waste resources on immense amounts of expensive fabric."</premise>

<premise type="pathos" id="13">Nowadays, you would never see a wealthy leader dressing like this.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="14">Clothes have become cheap, thus they are no longer useful as a status symbol.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="15">Certain elite brands are used to show off wealth, but the suit the president wears is little different in form than the suit you can buy down at Walmart.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="16">His suit is just higher quality and better fitted.</premise>

<premise type="pathos" id="17">Or consider beauty standards.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="18">Back during the Victorian Era, it was very fashionable for women of class to have extremely pale skin.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="19">When most of the populace lived on farms or walked to work in a factory, most people got tan quite easily.</premise>
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="20">Only the rich could afford to be pale.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="21">Nowadays, where most people work office jobs, retail jobs, food service, etc, tanning is a luxury good, a sign you have enough spare time to sit in the sun or money to go to a tanning salon.</premise>

<premise type="pathos" id="22">So, what would the luxury goods be for a post-scarcity society?</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="23">In such a society, the cost of most physical goods would approach zero.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="24">Raw materials would be extracted by robots.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="25">Energy would come from cheap robot-produced solar farms.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="26">Robots would assemble and repair other robots.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="27">The cost of most physical goods, in a true post-scarcity society, is near zero.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="28">Sure, a common laborer could buy a thousand copies of a 2015 Lexus, but what's the point?</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="29">Even someone working at Burger King could afford to put together a copy of Louis XIV's outfit, but no one ever does.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="30">It's just seen as silly and ridiculous, possibly even a sign of mental illness.</premise>

<premise type="logos" id="31">So, what would rich people spend their money on?</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="32">What are the status goods of post-scarcity society?</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="33">Well, real estate could certainly be one.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="34">The cost to build a house may be zero, but land certainly isn't.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="35">Still, this can be ameliorated by high-rises.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="36">Lots of people can afford to live in a ritzy downtown area if a high-quality high rise can be built to next for nothing.</premise>
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="37">Owning a single-family home in a high-quality area would be a status symbol, but just living their wouldn't.</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="38">So, without that, what do we have?</premise>
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="39">About the only thing you can buy with your money at that point is human-intensive services.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="40">Sure, you *could* use a robot to clean your house, but do you want people to think you are poor?</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="41">Show off your wealth by hiring a butler instead.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="42">You *could* put your kid through a MOOC to teach them algebra, but you're better than that.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="43">Hire an expensive private tutor instead.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="44">You *could* have a robot do your hair or nails, but really?</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="45">What are you, a common peasant?</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="46">Pay for the fancy salon instead and show off your fabulous wealth.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="47">You *could* use a driverless car, but having someone drive you around is just so much more classy.</premise>

<claim type="interpretation" id="48">In short, in a world where the cost of physical goods is near zero, the only way to show off your wealth is to hire a bunch of people as a status symbol.</claim>
So, what does retain

</reply>
<reply id="cn65fkv" author="Prometheus_v2">

&#8710;

<claim type="agreement" id="49">So instead of genocide we simply go back to feudalism.</claim>
I can't say this is a perfect outcome but I guess it's both better than death and it's something I can see happening.

</reply>
</thread>
