<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qd3li">
<title>CMV: Nativity scenes are antisemitic.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qd3li/cmv_nativity_scenes_are_antisemitic/</source>
<OP author="skunkardump">

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="0">This has nothing to do with the celebration of Christmas excluding religious minorities</claim>, it's because <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="1">traditional nativity scenes reinforce negative stereotypes about Jews</claim>.

<premise type="logos" id="2">As the story goes, when Jesus was about to be born his parents were travelling to Bethlehem, but when they got there the inn was full, so Mary had to give birth in the barn</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="3">The problem is, if nativity scenes are any indication, baby Jesus was still in the manger when the three wise men came to visit and give him Christmas presents</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="4">Most people know Jesus was born on Christmas, but less realize that the wise men didn't show up until the Epiphany twelve days later</premise>.

<claim type="interpretation" id="5">Are we honestly expected to believe that no vacancies opened up at the inn for almost two weeks?</claim> <premise type="logos" id="6">Because that would be the most unbelievable aspect of the entire story if you ask me</premise>, and <premise type="logos" id="7">it seriously strains credulity to begin with</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="8">Even miracles make more sense in the context of the birth of the Son of God</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="9">Maybe a virgin really could give birth to a deity, or a new star could magically appear over the birthplace</premise>, but <premise type="logos" id="10">there's no reason for the inn to miraculously have no rooms come open for nearly two weeks</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="11">Plus Mary and Joseph would be the first to know when something came available since they were basically squatting in the garage and would surely notice when patrons came to get their ox or camel or whatever before leaving</premise>.

<claim type="interpretation" id="12">The obvious implication is that Jesus' chintzy Jewish stepdad was such a tightwad that he was willing to let his pubescent wife and her newborn baby sleep in donkey slop if it would save him a few shekels</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="13">Joseph probably would have made that barn the family's permanent rent-free residence if the wise men hadn't showed up bearing enough cash and prizes to go live it up in Egypt</premise>.
After all, <premise type="logos" id="14">why did they stay so long anyway?</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="15">It's not like Mary needed the time to recuperate</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="16">Thanks to baby Jesus' healing powers even her hymen immediately regenerated, kind of like the redhead vampire from True Blood or the cheerleader from Heroes</premise>.
(<premise type="pathos" id="17">Not the real life Hayden Panettiere though, you know those gigantic Klitschkos split that wide open.</premise>)

MERRY CHRISTMAS!

</OP>
<reply id="cn504pa" author="GnosticGnome">

<premise type="ethos" id="18">Matthew 2:11</premise>

"And when they were come into the house, they saw the young child with Mary his mother, and fell down, and worshipped him and when they had opened their treasures, they presented unto him gifts; gold, and frankincense and myrrh."

<premise type="logos" id="19">When the wise men visited Jesus, it was in a house</premise>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="20">The Nativity scene is about the visit of the shepherds</claim>, but <claim type="interpretation" id="21">the wise men are drawn into the manger scene early</claim> because <premise type="logos" id="22">it looks cooler that way</premise>.

</reply>
<reply id="cn506v1" author="skunkardump">

<claim type="agreement" id="23">Right</claim>, but did <premise type="logos_pathos" id="24">the inventor of nativity scenes think it would "look cooler" because it portrays Joseph as a stereotypical Jewish cheapskate?</premise> <premise type="logos" id="25">Why change things from the biblical version of events?</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cn50azp" author="GnosticGnome">

<claim type="disagreement" id="26">If the various artists who contributed to the scene had intended to make Joseph stereotypically Jewish, they would have</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="27">They'd have given him a big hooked nose</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="28">They'd have given him opulent dress while giving Mary or Jesus poorer dress</premise>.
Something.

<claim type="interpretation" id="29">But no: they don't make Joseph look Jewish at all</claim>
. <premise type="logos" id="30">If there's anything anti-Semitic going on, it's the near-erasure of Jesus/Mary/Joseph's Jewishness</premise>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="31">The artists aren't focusing on Joseph as a Jew</claim>; <premise type="logos" id="32">he's an early Christian to them</premise>.

As to why this conflation of two similar events?
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="33">That's a pretty common artistic trope</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="34">You say "event X is like event Y, let's put them together"</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="35">The visit of the shepherds and the visit of the kings are narratively redundant</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="36">It's just cleaner storytelling to do the mashup</premise>.

</reply>
<reply id="cn50g0u" author="skunkardump">

&#8710; <claim type="agreement" id="37">Fair enough</claim>, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="38">I'm not totally convinced that the change wasn't motivated by the kind of antisemitism that was historically common in Christendom until quite recently</claim>, but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="39">I have to admit that artistic license does offer a somewhat plausible alternate justification</claim>.

</reply>
</thread>
