<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qc1rl">
<title>CMV: Most democracies are far too tolerant of extremism, especially the likes of neo-fascism, neo-nazism, radical Islamism and violent intolerance. The world has been to soft on these ideologies and they need to be eliminated whenever they appear.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qc1rl/cmv_most_democracies_are_far_too_tolerant_of/</source>
<OP author="amerifats_clap">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">I think some of the biggest threats to global stability comes from the political fringes.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="1">It's either the extreme left, or the extreme right.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="2">Radicalism almost always leads to violence, and is a plague on democratic society and governments.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="3">Since communism has been relegated to just a handful of countries</premise>, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="4">the far-left has for the most part been dealt with</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="5">However the far-right continues to be a menace.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="6">I believe fascist neo-nazi groups, the KKK, the golden dawn or any religious extremist group like radical Islamism all fall under the far-right.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="7">These groups are always extreme fringes</claim>, and <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="8">a handful of people make the world a much nastier place</claim>.

<premise type="pathos" id="9">Often it is the leaders of such movements that prey on the weak-willed, using them as pawns in their ambitions of power.</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="10">Unfortunately with the world's obsession with free speech and personal liberty</premise>, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="11">such leaders are given a free hand</claim>.
On websites like twitter and facebook we see ISIS recruit blind followers.
<premise type="logos" id="12">Wouldn't restricting "free speech" put brakes on this sort of recruitment ?</premise>

<premise type="logos" id="13">Political parties in democracies often try to keep these groups on a leash</premise>, but <premise type="logos" id="14">do not wish to eliminate them since they serve definite political goals like polarizing the electorate</premise>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="15">I see this as a major flaw in democracy.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="16">Fear of losing votes from radical sympathizers leads to political groups appeasing extremism.</premise>

Instead, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="17">I think governments should do much more and try to completely stamp out any signs of fascism</claim>.
<premise type="pathos" id="18">After the horrors of World War 2</premise> <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="19">I find it completely absurd that we still put up with their ideologies</claim>.

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="20">Bringing socio-economic growth to communities that feel disenfranchised just isn't enough</claim>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="21">their will always be a few bad apples</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="22">These bad apples need to be weeded out</claim>.
<premise type="pathos" id="23">Instead, we allow them to spread their rot, and infect society.</premise>

</OP>
<reply id="cn5sqpz" author="TBFProgrammer">
&gt; I think some of the biggest threats to global stability comes from the political fringes.

<claim type="disagreement" id="24">The only constant is change.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="25">Global stability is a myth grown out of a population that has gotten good at balancing acts.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="26">The supports necessary for real stability simply don't exist.</premise>

<claim type="interpretation" id="27">To carry out a balancing act, you have to avoid any extreme reactions, as they only make for larger oscillations.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="28">Censorship is an extreme reaction to an extreme force</premise>, and here are two very good arguments for why should be seen as an extreme option:

1) <premise type="logos_pathos" id="29">There are many things we used to consider extreme that are now fundamental principles of our society.</premise> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="30">We claim that our old positions were wrong, and have good evidence to back this up.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="31">With this in mind, we are forced to acknowledge that we are probably making errors in other places, and may even have been led astray in one of the areas we have already changed.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="32">Censorship halts this process and locks in whatever is current.</premise>

2) <premise type="logos" id="33">Censorship does not eliminate the censored individual.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="34">Indeed, they will work hard to evade the censor, carrying out their activities further from the public eye.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="35">This brings their arguments out of public discourse, where a solid counter-argument is more likely to be interjected.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="36">It also dooms any attempt to change their beliefs, as their opponents no longer understand those beliefs sufficiently to do this.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="37">Finally it gives them a true claim that they are being oppressed and targeted, which history suggests tends to strengthen a group.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cn5vfep" author="amerifats_clap">

<claim type="agreement" id="37a">Good arguments</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="38">Although I may disagree somewhat, I see why censorship can be dangerous.</claim>
One thing about censorship : <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="39">don't you think it's a problem that the likes of ISIS some neo-nazi groups actively recruit on twitter and facebook</claim> ? <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="40">Should't this sort of thing be stopped ?</claim>

&gt; There are many things we used to consider extreme that are now fundamental principles of our society

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="41">While this may be true, hasn't the killing of innocents (and murder or rape, or destruction of property) always been considered deeply immoral (outside of wars) ?</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="42">We already clamp down on extremism, and potential extremists are actively monitored using existing surveillance techniques.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="43">Is it really that bad to go after them just a little bit more ?</premise>

Anyhow, for a well thought out response:

&#8710;

</reply>
</thread>
