<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qbry8">
<title>CMV: America is not a democracy</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qbry8/cmv_america_is_not_a_democracy/</source>
<OP author="Smelly_Bob">

Really though.
<premise type="pathos" id="0">There is an unchecked organization that spies on them 24/7 without consent.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="1">The US has given itself license to detain and torture citizens with no trial.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="2">The energy laws in that country allow corporations to drill where they please and, as a result, poison who they please.</premise>
American citizens have clearly been lied to in many situations.
These lies have led to events like the second gulf war.
Not to mention the completely unregulated financial system.

Honestly, none of these things have been democratically voted for, so why are Americans so deluded about this?
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3">It's not a free, democratic society by any means.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="4">It's clearly an oligarchy</claim>

</OP>
<reply id="cn4pxm7" author="brutishbloodgod">

<claim type="interpretation" id="5">A democracy is not necessarily a functional, benevolent government, nor is a democracy necessarily free.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="6">The USA was intended to be a federal republic, a republic being a form of indirect democracy.</premise>
To see if it actually *is* one (at least the "republic" part), we just need to answer a few simple questions.

<claim type="interpretation" id="7">Is political power in the US held by elected officials?</claim>

<claim type="interpretation" id="8">Are those officials elected in free and fair democratic elections?</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="9">The answer to both of those questions is unambiguously "yes."</claim> <premise type="logos" id="10">The domestic spying, the secret courts, the torture, the corporate favoritism, the environmental destruction, the lies, the unjustified wars, the unregulated financial system... all of those are things instituted or approved by our democratically elected officials, fully within the scope of power ceded to them by the constitution.</premise>
And <premise type="pathos" id="11">we continue to vote those who do these things into office in free and fair elections, time and time again, without fail</premise>.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="12">You can argue, perhaps successfully, that the US is a fascist, un-free state</claim>, but <claim type="interpretation" id="13">it remains by definition a democratic one</claim>.

</reply>
<reply id="cn57z2h" author="Smelly_Bob">

<claim type="agreement" id="14">Fair enough haha.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="15">This is the best argument I've seen here</claim>
Edit: but how can you have truly fair elections if things like superpacs exist?

</reply>
<reply id="cn5l6es" author="brutishbloodgod">

What's your basis for believing that SuperPACs make elections un-free or un-fair?

</reply>
<reply id="cn5toxz" author="Smelly_Bob">

<claim type="interpretation" id="16">Well in my brain a fair election is when anyone can run for office.</claim>
<premise type="pathos" id="17">The fact that you need millions of dollars to do so seems unfair.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="18">It instantly results in a situation where only the rich can run for and hold offices.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="19">On the municipal level I don't think superpacs are a problem, but definitely on a federal level.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cn63czg" author="brutishbloodgod">

<claim type="interpretation" id="20">Anyone *can* run for office.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="21">You might not get very far</premise>, but you can run.
And <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="22">you don't need millions of dollars</claim>, <premise type="logos" id="23">you need to be *able to raise* millions of dollars</premise>.
In itself, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="24">I don't see a problem with that</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="25">Raising large amounts of money requires leadership, diplomacy, organization, charisma&#8230; all traits I like to see in my elected officials.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="26">The corruption and lack of transparency created by PACs and SuperPACs and Citizens United in general is definitely a major problem</premise>, but <premise type="logos" id="27">like some other things that have come up in this discussion</premise>, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="28">it's not an issue that makes the USA an un-democratic state</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="29">There's no rule saying that the person who raises the most money wins the election.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="30">The fact that most people vote for the most visible candidate on their side rather than the one that most closely represents their interests is a problem with the electorate and also a result of our winner-take-all voting system</premise>, but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="31">neither of those are in conflict with the USA being a democracy by definition</claim>.

</reply>
<reply id="cn64i37" author="Smelly_Bob">

<claim type="agreement" id="32">Okay, I think you have officially Changed My View haha...</claim> <claim type="agreement" id="33">it seems like the problem is more caused by the populace not being responsible voters</claim>, <claim type="agreement" id="34">I see that and agree with it</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="35">Ideally I would like it if no money was involved in the poltical process</claim>, but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="36">that is naive</claim>.

</reply>
<reply id="cn6a4ve" author="brutishbloodgod">

&gt; Okay, I think you have officially Changed My View haha

Glad this has been a productive discussion.
If your view has indeed been changed, please draw your attention to "The delta (&#8710;) system" in the sidebar and award me one delta.

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="37">The reason I think this is important is because I'm pissed off about the way things are in America</claim>, as I'm sure you are, and <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="38">I always think that the best way to address a problem is to see it for what it is</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="39">America's problem isn't that it isn't a democracy</claim>; rather, <claim type="interpretation" id="40">I think that America's problem is that it has fetishized democracy to the point where anything resulting from that system is accepted, even if it's corrupt and tyrannical</claim>, and <claim type="interpretation" id="41">that's exactly what it's turning into</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="42">No, we're probably never going to get money out of politics entirely</premise>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="43">corporations being able to anonymously fund entire campaigns is a major threat to healthy government, even if it isn't, strictly speaking, un-democratic</premise>.

</reply>
<reply id="cn6lwak" author="Smelly_Bob">

&#8710;

A delta for you then! (I'm new, so sorry in advance if I mess it up)

Maybe I put forward the wrong view, but <claim type="agreement" id="44">I think you and I more or less agree that their is something fetid in the system</claim>.
<premise type="pathos" id="45">I get tired of seeing people worship at the altar of the US flag</premise> - <premise type="pathos" id="46">they seem blind to what the US government is really about</premise>.
Cheers!

</reply>
</thread>
