<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qaf6l">
<title>CMV: If a child struggles to achieve in grade school it is virtually always the parents' fault.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qaf6l/cmv_if_a_child_struggles_to_achieve_in_grade/</source>
<OP author="unidangit">

<premise type="logos" id="0">For the sake of this thread, we'll exclude children with medically diagnosed learning disabilities</premise>; <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="1">IMO the knowledge and resource base for teaching said children is probably proportionate to the percentage they make up of the overall population</claim>.

<premise type="logos" id="2">With a healthy child, income, neighborhood, peers and teachers should be filtered through a responsible parent(s).</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="3">A child who struggles in earnest or intentionally slacks off is a direct reflection of parenting.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="4">I am curious regarding potential for more public accountability held to parents who fail to direct their child.</claim>(<premise type="logos_pathos" id="5">maybe a monetary incentive derived from public tax coffers paid to parents of children who maintain a passing grade, to be withheld if child dips below</premise>.)

<claim type="interpretation" id="6">I think parents are virtually 100% responsible for producing scholastically successful children</claim>.
CMV.

</OP>
<reply id="cn4h6d8" author="Snapop23">

<premise type="ethos" id="7">I had parents who were extremely persistent about making sure i stayed on track.</premise>
<premise type="ethos_pathos" id="8">I was only recently diagnosed with adhd a reading disability</premise> and <premise type="ethos" id="9">im 20 years old</premise>.
<premise type="pathos" id="10">I graduated on time but i struggled so much</premise>.
<premise type="pathos" id="11">I failed a bunch of stuff and was constantly embarrassed to show my grades to other people.</premise>
<premise type="ethos_pathos" id="12">I lost hope often because things felt hopeless</premise>, <premise type="ethos_pathos" id="13">which lead teachers, doctors, family and other students to think i just didnt care</premise>.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="14">An issue is there are a ton of people with "disabilities" more so than you'd think.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="15">Thats because we teach everyone to think the same way.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="16">Thats the issue.</claim>
<premise type="pathos" id="17">Im really good at doing certain things.</premise>
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="18">For example, i can read , write, and even speak backwards pretty well.</premise>
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="19">My brain is wired differently.</premise>

<premise type="ethos_pathos" id="20">I cant do the things the average person can</premise>, but <premise type="ethos_pathos" id="21">i can do a lot of things that they cant</premise>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="22">It doesnt make me stupid</claim>, because <premise type="ethos_pathos" id="23">im capable of the same things just in a different way</premise>, but <premise type="ethos_pathos" id="24">my experience at school did its best to convince me that i was stupid</premise>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="25">THAT is the issue</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="26">Everyone has a mind that works in its own way</claim>.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="27">The problem isnt always bad parenting, though that can play a role,</claim> <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="28">the problem is a black and white educational system</claim>.

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="29">Treating everyone the same way, other than special classes for "dumb" kids is the problem.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="30">Learning seems hard or dumb to some kids</claim> and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="31">thats because its not tapping into their mind right</premise>.

<claim type="interpretation" id="32">If a child can discuss something he or she cares about then the parents are just a plus.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cn4irnn" author="unidangit">

&#8710;

&gt; I cant do the things the average person can, but i can do a lot of things that they cant. It doesnt make me stupid, because im capable of the same things just in a different way, but my experience at school did its best to convince me that i was stupid. THAT is the issue. Everyone has a mind that works in its own way.


<claim type="agreement" id="33">Yes.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="34">I think that builds my initial point.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="35">Parents should be educated on how to identify *how* their child's mind works.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="36">This is what I meant when I said "100%" on the parents.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="37">You're parents would've known how to turn the way your mind worked into a successful academic career, in a perfect world.</premise>

</reply>
</thread>
