<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rppq9">
<title>CMV: Religion is not violent or not violent, its followers are.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rppq9/cmv_religion_is_not_violent_or_not_violent_its/</source>
<OP author="DurianMD">

So recently I've seen a lot of posts condemning Islam as a violent religion or a sexist religion.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">I point out that many Christians follow the bible which has numerous examples of sexism, but in application, there are numerous branches of Christianity that are no more sexist than secular groups.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">For example, Congregationalists and Universaliists.</premise>

So, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="2">my belief is that while religion can inform the views of people, it is far more likely that religion will be used to justify actions that would have been executed any way.</claim> <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3">I think that most Jewish people don't want to stone adulterers and most Muslims don't want to stone non believers.</claim>

</OP>
<reply id="cni4p0b" author="foobar5678">

<claim type="interpretation" id="3a"> This is like saying "Guns don't kill people, people kill people." </claim> 
<claim type="agreement" id="3b"> This might be true </claim>, but <premise type="logos" id="3c"> the gun certainty played a big part. </premise>
 
</reply>
<reply id="cni4u2i" author="DurianMD">

<claim type="interpretation" id="3d"> Okay, but even if religion did motivate people to kill, it doesn't provide the means to kill, only the motivation. </claim> 
<premise type ="logos" id="3e"> However, assuming that a gun provides the motivation, it also provides the tool to kill someone with. </premise>

That being said, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3f"> I'm not convinced that either motivates people to kill, and one gives the tools to kill with and the other doesn't </claim>. 
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3g"> This analogy falls short for me. </claim>
 
</reply>
<reply id="cni4y8t" author="foobar5678">

<claim type="interpretation" id="3h"> Religion gives them the psychological tools to justify to themselves that killing is ok. </claim> 
<premise type="logos" id="3i"> Without that, they wouldn't be able to kill. </premise> 
<premise type="logos" id="3j">So while the person is ultimately responsible, like the gun, religion played a part. </premise> 
 
</reply>
<reply id="cni5g16" author="DurianMD">

Hm, that sounds more like the motivation though.

</reply>
</thread>
