<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rnr30">
<title>CMV: I think the Paris shooting makes a good case for culture of responsible gun ownership any carrying.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnr30/cmv_i_think_the_paris_shooting_makes_a_good_case/</source>
<OP author="rrockethr">

Thinking about today's news: [BBC](http://www.bbc.com/news/live/world-europe-30710777), [Wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Hebdo_shooting)

<claim type="interpretation" id="0">I think France is in a tough spot in how to react to this.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">There would be even stronger calls for an anti-islam and anti-immigration policies.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">These event reminds people that they cannot depend on protection by government.</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="3">I think it would be a shame to allow the many, who are afraid more then anything, to be swayed by xenophobic nationalists (which might have been the goal of the attack anyway).</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="4">I think this, regardless of whether the weapons used by the attackers were owned legally, makes a good case for promoting a culture of a reasonable gun ownership and carrying.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="5">Say if 1 out of 5 people carried a gun with them, was well trained in its use and tested in his responsibility to prevent its misuse</premise>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="6">society upheld the value of these people as protectors, it would benefit the society more the the current state of legislature and culture of gun ownership in most of European countries</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="7">I also think this would be much better then increase in police numbers and rights</claim> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="8">as policemen are a very homogeneous group trained to stick together and the danger of even deepening the "not one of us" (pack) mentality and escalation of "police state"</premise>.
Change my view.

PS: I am not here to talk about USA and its gun problems.

EDIT: Awarded a delta to a comment which didn't refute this idea but led me to change my view that it would be best realized with paralyzing weapons rather then guns: http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnr30/cmv_i_think_the_paris_shooting_makes_a_good_case/cni3o83

</OP>
<reply id="cnhp8qw" author="cold08">

Scenario 1:

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="9">Let's say you're a drug addict and due to your addiction you can't hold down a job, are really strung out and resort to one of the stupidest ways to make $100 for your next fix which is mugging people on the street.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="10">Not getting the money is not an option</claim> <premise type="logos" id="11">because you're desperate</premise>.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="12">If one in 10,000 people are carrying firearms, do you take your chances and try to get someone to hand over their cash without shooting someone or do you kill them outright and steal their valuables off their corpse?</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="13">How does that decision change when the odds are 1 in 5?</premise>

<premise type="logos" id="14">Remember, you're an addict and not getting the money is not an option.</premise>

Scenario 2:

<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="15">You're carrying and you rear end a guy.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="16">You pull over and the guy is really mad and he gets out of his car yelling up a storm.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="17">You know there is a 1 in 5 chance that the guy is carrying as well.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="18">When do you reach for your holster to draw your weapon</premise> and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="19">when do you fire it?</premise>

1.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="20">When he's angry and yelling at you?</premise>

2. <premise type="pathos" id="21">When he reaches into his jacket where his holster might be?</premise>

3.
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="22">After you see the gun?</premise>

4.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="23">After he points it at you?</premise>

5.
<premise type="pathos" id="24">After he starts shooting?</premise>

Scenario 3:

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="25">You're carrying</premise> and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="26">you just picked your brand new car up from the dealer</premise> and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="27">while you were at the stoplight some asshole that was obviously texting while driving rear ends you in your brand new car</premise>.
<premise type="pathos" id="28">You lose your temper and get out of your brand new car yelling up a storm.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="29">You notice after a bit of yelling that the guy is carrying</premise> and <premise type="logos" id="30">he has observed that you are as well and is scared</premise>.

<premise type="logos" id="31">Do you wait until you're sure he has decided to use his firearm to act?</premise> or <premise type="logos" id="32">do you act first because by the time you're sure he is going to draw his firearm, you won't have time to act before he shoots you?</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="33">The only reason this stuff doesn't happen all the time is because we can make the reasonable assumption that a person we are having a conflict with is unarmed.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="34">As soon as it becomes a reasonable assumption, immediately escalating a conflict to deadly force starts being the best option.</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="35">I've worked in customer service and have been yelled at by strangers more often than anyone should have.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="36">If I lived in a society where most people were carrying firearms, I would have had to ask myself "Is this person angry enough to kill me? because if I wait to find out for sure I'll already be dead" way more often than I'd like.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnhpxs5" author="rrockethr">

Scenario 1: <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="37">I don't think this decision changes if you are comfortable killing for money</claim> <premise type="" id="38">you kill for money if you can get away with it</premise>.
Scenario 2: <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="39">When he starts to pulling out a gun you try to get cover</claim>, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="40">when he starts aiming at you you draw to fire</claim>.
Scenario 3: <premise type="logos" id="41">The known rule would be only to draw gun to shoot and who is aiming at you is aiming at you to shoot</premise> so <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="42">you are in right to defend yourself</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="43">If you are unsure of someone's intentions you should get cover</claim> and <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="44">as soon he notices that and doesn't intend to kill you he should make this well known to you</claim> as <premise type="logos" id="45">he doesn't you to shoot him either</premise>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnhqkes" author="cold08">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="46">You'd likely be dead in scenarios 2 and 3.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="47">This isn't the movies where you duck bullets and dive behind a table or something.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="48">By the time they have their hand on their gun you have maybe 2 seconds</premise>, and <premise type="logos" id="49">by the time they start aiming it at you, you have a fraction of one.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="50">There is a reason why police, when they have reason to believe that someone is armed have their guns already drawn.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="51">That shit happens fast, and reactive speed isn't fast enough.</premise>

As for scenario 1, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="52">once you remove the non-lethal option, the lethal one gets a lot more comfortable</claim>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnhr8ff" author="rrockethr">

<claim type="agreement" id="53">Yes</claim>, but <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="54">I don't see how you intend to CMV with the scenarios 2 and 3</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="55">I don't see them as very likely as nobody is going to draw a concealed gun when not intending to kill.</premise>

With scenario 1 <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="56">I would expect the effect would be that the still thinking criminals would change to some other safer crime</claim> as <premise type="logos_pathos" id="57">their chances of getting shot would also increase</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="58">It would still be illegal to kill a robber</premise> so <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="59">I don't think some of them would start killing</claim> (<premise type="logos" id="60">thus being legal to kill in defense</premise>).

</reply>
<reply id="cnhrsbb" author="cold08">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="61">Of course you intend to kill the person if you draw your weapon, if you can reasonably assume that they have a weapon,</claim> <premise type="logos" id="62">you can't wait for them to draw theirs before you decide to defend yourself if you want to leave alive</premise>.
<premise type="pathos" id="63">All you know in all three scenarios is that someone you are in conflict with probably has a gun and there is a significant chance they will use it.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="64">If you don't have reasonable cause to believe someone is armed because very few people have CCWs then things like letting the guy you just rear ended blow off steam becomes a reasonable option</claim> <premise type="logos" id="65">because he likely can't kill you within in a few seconds</premise>.

<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="66">If 1 in 5 people can kill you in seconds being impolite gets deadly very quickly.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnhscr2" author="rrockethr">

Well <claim type="disagreement" id="67">I don't think so</claim>, <premise type="logos" id="68">people with concealed guns don't shoot even if they see someone has a gun too</premise>.

</reply>
</thread>
