<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rnr30">
<title>CMV: I think the Paris shooting makes a good case for culture of responsible gun ownership any carrying.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnr30/cmv_i_think_the_paris_shooting_makes_a_good_case/</source>
<OP author="rrockethr">

Thinking about today's news: [BBC](http://www.bbc.com/news/live/world-europe-30710777), [Wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Hebdo_shooting)

<claim type="interpretation" id="0">I think France is in a tough spot in how to react to this.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">There would be even stronger calls for an anti-islam and anti-immigration policies.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">These event reminds people that they cannot depend on protection by government.</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="3">I think it would be a shame to allow the many, who are afraid more then anything, to be swayed by xenophobic nationalists (which might have been the goal of the attack anyway).</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="4">I think this, regardless of whether the weapons used by the attackers were owned legally, makes a good case for promoting a culture of a reasonable gun ownership and carrying.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="5">Say if 1 out of 5 people carried a gun with them, was well trained in its use and tested in his responsibility to prevent its misuse</premise>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="6">society upheld the value of these people as protectors, it would benefit the society more the the current state of legislature and culture of gun ownership in most of European countries</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="7">I also think this would be much better then increase in police numbers and rights</claim> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="8">as policemen are a very homogeneous group trained to stick together and the danger of even deepening the "not one of us" (pack) mentality and escalation of "police state"</premise>.
Change my view.

PS: I am not here to talk about USA and its gun problems.

EDIT: Awarded a delta to a comment which didn't refute this idea but led me to change my view that it would be best realized with paralyzing weapons rather then guns: http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnr30/cmv_i_think_the_paris_shooting_makes_a_good_case/cni3o83

</OP>
<reply id="cnhl37p" author="nenyim">

How so?

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="9">One of the person present was under the protection of something called "service de protection des hautes personalit&#233;s" (it has been renamed since but still same goal).</premise>
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="10">That mean that there was a policemen armed and trained specifically to protect someone in danger of being targeted.</premise>

<premise type="logos" id="11">It sadly didn't do them much good.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="12">Unless you bring the same kind of weapons and protections as them it's akin to bringing a knife to a gun fight.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="13">Charb, one of the victim, said concerning the threats he previously received "je pr&#233;f&#232;re mourir debout que vivre &#224; genoux" (I prefer to die rather than live on my knee)</premise> and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="14">I mostly rejoin it concerning the argument you are making, the cost of constantly living in fear and packing enough fire power to fight this kind of things (you would need to be incredibly level headed, trained and lucky to do it simply with a hand gun) simply isn't worth it.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnhlf5g" author="rrockethr">

<premise type="logos" id="15">Well we have many examples in history when it was common to walk around well armed, where those doing it were upheld as protectors.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="16">I think with such people among us the public would have less of a reason to be afraid then when the only people defending them is incompetent and untrustworthy police</claim> and <premise type="logos" id="17">in many countries you cannot choose to arm yourself appropriately to defend yourself and others.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnhn56e" author="nenyim">

&gt; Well we have many examples in history when it was common to walk around well armed, where those doing it were upheld as protectors.

As protectors unless they were the one people needed protection from.
<premise type="logos" id="18">Crimes rates, and especially violent crimes, were also much much higher than they are today in all of those examples.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="19">It's not like it was an utopia where zoro or lucky luck came to solve everything with their weapon before the bad guys had a chance to do something wrong.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="20">It's definitely not a time I want back</claim> and <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="21">our supposedly incompetent and untrustworthy police are definitely a better job of enforcing the law than those protectors could ever have</claim>.

&gt; <quote> I think with such people among us the public would have less of a reason to be afraid then </quote>

You mean if everyone around me has a gun I have less to worry about?
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="22">When I see how most people are driving I have absolutely no reason to believe people would be any more capable, responsible or safer with a gun</premise> so <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="23">I would have to worry about all those morons that can't be trusted with anything and about all the rest that maybe just had one of those days and simply forgot to do what they did 10 000 times before</claim>.

<premise type="pathos" id="24">At the same time rather than being afraid of getting mugged I will be afraid of getting mugged by someone pointing a gun right at my face, someone I have no reason to trust won't shot me by accident.</premise>

</reply>
</thread>
