<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rmwcd">
<title>CMV: Freedom of speech is being taken too far</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rmwcd/cmv_freedom_of_speech_is_being_taken_too_far/</source>
<OP author="5skandas">

In the last few weeks we've had two huge events happen in the world, both of which were caused by matters relating to "freedom of speech." The first being the hacking of Sony over The Interview, and today the shooting at the offices of a satirical magazine in Paris.
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="0">I certainly value our free speech</claim> but to me <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="1">there is a clear line between exercising your first amendment right (<premise type="logos" id="1z">"President Obama sucks!" etc</premise>) and doing things that are known to be offensive to other cultures</claim> (<premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">Satirical cartoons of prophets, assassinating leaders, etc</premise>).

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3">Perhaps this is a bad analogy</claim> - but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">if you say something antagonizing to a bully and you get your ass kicked, you should have anticipated that outcome.</premise>

</OP>
<reply id="cnhbcgj" author="ablarga">

&gt; Perhaps this is a bad analogy - but if you say something antagonizing to a bully and you get your ass kicked, you should have anticipated that outcome.

<claim type="agreement" id="5">Sure</claim>, but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="6">that doesn't mean we condone the bully's actions and don't punish the bullies for acting</claim>. 
<premise type="logos" id="7">We want to live in a world without bullies, whether those bullies act on behalf of beliefs, religions, countries, or even out own governments</premise>. 
<premise type="logos" id="8">Complete freedom in the expression of any idea, offensive or not, is a major element of that world</premise>. 

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="9">If you want to protect the freedom to speak for any of us, you have to protect the freedom to speak for all of us</claim>. 

</reply>
<reply id="cnhcexs" author="5skandas">

<claim type="agreement" id="10">I certainly agree with your points </claim>- <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="11">I didn't mean to imply that I was only for **some** freedom of speech</claim>. 
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="12">I just think lately there's been a lot of antagonistic material being published and everyone cries freedom of speech when certain groups get upset</claim>.

<premise type="pathos" id="13">Why can't America be the bigger person and say "Ok, we won't publish certain types of material, not because we're afraid of you but because we respect your views."</premise>
Is that so hard?

</reply>
</thread>
