<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rgs7o">
<title>CMV: Assuming there is no afterlife, then life is ultimately meaningless and pointless because we die.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rgs7o/cmv_assuming_there_is_no_afterlife_then_life_is/</source>
<OP author="mybromarcusaurelius">

*Note: Please assume that there is no afterlife when responding to my post.
I am not religious.
Thank you.
ALSO: By "meaningless," I mean "meaningless" to the person who is doing the dying.
To the person who is alive and who will then die, life is meaningless.

CMV.
Assuming <premise type="logos_pathos" id="0">there is no afterlife</premise>, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="1">life is ultimately meaningless and pointless</claim> because <premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">we die</premise>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="3">Death is the great eraser</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="4">Living life is as irrational as reading a book that, after finished, is immediately erased from your memory</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="5">It is comparable to that, too</premise>.

<claim type="interpretation" id="6">It makes no difference if I, a 23 year old, die now or live until I am 100 and die</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="7">Either way, after my brief spark of existence I become nothingness</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="8">Not only do I remember nothing; I AM nothing</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="9">To me, it is as if my life had never happened</premise>.

I'll put it another way.
<premise type="logos" id="10">Imagine the time before you were born</premise>.
Have you remembered it yet?
<premise type="logos" id="11">Of course not</premise>.
<premise type="pathos" id="12">You didn't exist</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="13">This is the state that we return to after death--a state of nothingness similar to the state we were in before birth</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="14">When I die, I return to this state after a brief period of consciousness</premise>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="15">I return to it permanently</premise>. <premise type="logos_pathos" id="16">I might as well have never lived</premise>.

To anticipate a few responses:

(1) <claim type="interpretation" id="17">Helping others doesn't matter</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="18">They will die too</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="19">And then their descendants will die, on and on and on</premise>, until <premise type="logos" id="20">eventually the universe is destroyed or our galaxy collapses in an inevitable heat-death</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="21">Even if 1,000,000 people were helped by me</premise>, <premise type="logos" id="22">assuming they all die</premise>, <claim type="disagreement" id="23">then my life is still pointless and meaningless</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="24">For I will be dead and won't know what I did</premise>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="25">once they die, they won't know either</premise>.

<claim type="interpretation" id="26">(2) Attaining fame doesn't matter and doesn't truly make me "immortal."
</claim> <premise type="pathos" id="28">I'll be dead, and again, death is nothingness</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="29">Thus, I won't be around to enjoy my fame</premise>.

(3) <premise type="logos_pathos" id="30">Enjoying the moment is possible</premise>, but <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="31">doesn't make life have a point</claim>.
For <premise type="logos_pathos" id="32">once I die, all memories and all point is gone</premise>.

Please change my view from this depressing sentiment.

</OP>
<reply id="cnfqhly" author="stratys3">

What if time itself is an illusion, and we really do live forever?

<premise type="pathos" id="33">Consider a novel</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="34">As you read through the novel, you go from page to page, eventually reaching the end</premise>.
But does the novel stop existing just because you finished the book?
Or does the book continue to exist, with it's words, chapters, stories, characters, and lives intact?

<premise type="logos" id="35">"Now" is *the page you are reading at this moment*</premise>.
But <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="36">just because there are pages you've already read, or pages you have yet to read, doesn't mean those pages don't exist</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="37">And all those pages will continue to exist, even after you've finished your book</premise>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnfr85u" author="mybromarcusaurelius">

Most interesting point so far.
Thank you!

</reply>
<reply id="cnfrp1a" author="stratys3">

And <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="38">this view is supported by physics and what we know of it</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="39">Time isn't "real" in the same sense that we experience it</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="40">We are simply at one point along a path, and that's the "now"</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="41">All the other points in time exist as much as the current point in time, however</premise>.

<premise type="logos" id="42">Let's say I travel from home to the grocery store</premise>: <premise type="logos" id="43">I leave my apartment, go down the elevator, out on the street, past the cigar shop, past the empty parking lot, and finally to the store</premise>. *
Now* I'm at the store, but did my apartment, my elevator, the street I walked on, the cigar shop, and the empty parking lot cease to exist simply because I'm not there *right now*?
<premise type="logos" id="44">Of course not</premise>.

</reply>
</thread>
