<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rgs7o">
<title>CMV: Assuming there is no afterlife, then life is ultimately meaningless and pointless because we die.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rgs7o/cmv_assuming_there_is_no_afterlife_then_life_is/</source>
<OP author="mybromarcusaurelius">

*Note: Please assume that there is no afterlife when responding to my post.
I am not religious.
Thank you.
ALSO: By "meaningless," I mean "meaningless" to the person who is doing the dying.
To the person who is alive and who will then die, life is meaningless.

CMV.
Assuming <premise type="logos_pathos" id="0">there is no afterlife</premise>, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="1">life is ultimately meaningless and pointless</claim> because <premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">we die</premise>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="3">Death is the great eraser</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="4">Living life is as irrational as reading a book that, after finished, is immediately erased from your memory</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="5">It is comparable to that, too</premise>.

<claim type="interpretation" id="6">It makes no difference if I, a 23 year old, die now or live until I am 100 and die</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="7">Either way, after my brief spark of existence I become nothingness</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="8">Not only do I remember nothing; I AM nothing</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="9">To me, it is as if my life had never happened</premise>.

I'll put it another way.
<premise type="logos" id="10">Imagine the time before you were born</premise>.
Have you remembered it yet?
<premise type="logos" id="11">Of course not</premise>.
<premise type="pathos" id="12">You didn't exist</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="13">This is the state that we return to after death--a state of nothingness similar to the state we were in before birth</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="14">When I die, I return to this state after a brief period of consciousness</premise>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="15">I return to it permanently</premise>. <premise type="logos_pathos" id="16">I might as well have never lived</premise>.

To anticipate a few responses:

(1) <claim type="interpretation" id="17">Helping others doesn't matter</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="18">They will die too</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="19">And then their descendants will die, on and on and on</premise>, until <premise type="logos" id="20">eventually the universe is destroyed or our galaxy collapses in an inevitable heat-death</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="21">Even if 1,000,000 people were helped by me</premise>, <premise type="logos" id="22">assuming they all die</premise>, <claim type="disagreement" id="23">then my life is still pointless and meaningless</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="24">For I will be dead and won't know what I did</premise>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="25">once they die, they won't know either</premise>.

<claim type="interpretation" id="26">(2) Attaining fame doesn't matter and doesn't truly make me "immortal."
</claim> <premise type="pathos" id="28">I'll be dead, and again, death is nothingness</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="29">Thus, I won't be around to enjoy my fame</premise>.

(3) <premise type="logos_pathos" id="30">Enjoying the moment is possible</premise>, but <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="31">doesn't make life have a point</claim>.
For <premise type="logos_pathos" id="32">once I die, all memories and all point is gone</premise>.

Please change my view from this depressing sentiment.

</OP>
<reply id="cnfptvg" author="limerick_santorum">

<claim type="interpretation" id="33">Your point is predicated on the assumption that something is pointless if it doesn't last forever</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="34">I'm having a hard time understanding how you came to this conclusion</claim>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnfpy27" author="mybromarcusaurelius">

Imagine reading a book that, once finished, is immediately erased from your memory.
<premise type="logos" id="36">That is what life is like</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="37">Reading the book is ULTIMATELY pointless</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="38">Because it is erased from your memory</premise>.

<claim type="interpretation" id="39">Life is pointless in a similar manner</claim>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnfq3y5" author="limerick_santorum">

<claim type="disagreement" id="40">I wouldn't consider it pointless if I derived pleasure from reading it at the time</claim>.

I mean if you really believe that everything that does not last forever is pointless, why do you do anything? Why not sit in a corner and stare at a wall until you die?
<premise type="pathos" id="41">I would guess that it's because you derive pleasure from certain things in life and that you pursue these things just like everyone else does</premise>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnfr492" author="mybromarcusaurelius">

My fear is that <premise type="ethos_pathos" id="42">pursuing those things is irrational</premise>, that since <premise type="pathos" id="43">death is coming and will erase all experience regardless</premise>, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="44">I might as well go ahead and die</claim>.

Especially if there is more pain or dull moments than pleasure in life, why not just die?

</reply>
<reply id="cnfrb3k" author="limerick_santorum">

Why is it irrational to pursue something pleasurable that will not provide pleasure of an infinite duration?
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="45">That seems like an arbitrary condition to apply to the value of pursuing pleasurable things.</claim>

</reply>
</thread>
