<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rexe3">
<title>CMV: EMTs, SAR, firefighters, police, etc. should receive &#8220;military discounts&#8221;.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rexe3/cmv_emts_sar_firefighters_police_etc_should/</source>
<OP author="ke7ofi">

<premise type="logos" id="0">For those of you who don&#8217;t know, it&#8217;s common (at least in the US) for businesses, transit agencies, etc. to give small discounts to military veterans to thank them for their service.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="1">It seems that medical responders (even hospital staff, actually) and other emergency services do more good for society than soldiers</claim> and that <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="2">such discounts should be given to them</claim>.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="3">As for the &#8220;They&#8217;re not risking their lives for our country.&#8221; argument, police officers do that too, and for citizens rather than the country and its interests</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">Some might argue that soldiers do the US a disservice rather than help</premise>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="5">that&#8217;s [usually] the fault of their leaders and therefore not relevant to the debate</premise>.

I&#8217;m really hoping there&#8217;s a good reason behind the status quo, but we&#8217;ll see.
<premise type="logos" id="6">[It looks like there&#8217;s even less reason behind it than I initially thought, actually.]</premise>

[edits in brackets]

[[My view&#8217;s been changed.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview
/comments/2rexe3/cmv_emts_sar_firefighters_police_etc_should/cnfj9cu?context=10000) In summary, I think that <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="7">EMS people are just as deserving of these discounts (and that many more people contribute enough to be placed in the same category)</claim>, but I now believe - for the same reason - that <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="8">these discounts shouldn&#8217;t be offered at all</claim>.]

</OP>
<reply id="cnf93jv" author="[deleted]">

<claim type="interpretation" id="8a">Sure firefighters, EMT's, and nurses do great things for people. . . for those who have money and great insurance.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="8b">What a douchebag line.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cnfbg9s" author="ke7ofi">

&gt; Sure firefighters, EMT's, and nurses do great things for people. . . for those who have money and great insurance.

<claim type="disagreement" id="9">It&#8217;s not like the dispatcher chooses which calls to answer based on insurance policies.</claim>

&gt;What a douchebag line.

You&#8217;ll have fun [here](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rexe3/cmv_emts_sar_firefighters_police_etc_should/cnf9wqo?context=3), then.

</reply>
</thread>
