<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rexe3">
<title>CMV: EMTs, SAR, firefighters, police, etc. should receive &#8220;military discounts&#8221;.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rexe3/cmv_emts_sar_firefighters_police_etc_should/</source>
<OP author="ke7ofi">

<premise type="logos" id="0">For those of you who don&#8217;t know, it&#8217;s common (at least in the US) for businesses, transit agencies, etc. to give small discounts to military veterans to thank them for their service.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="1">It seems that medical responders (even hospital staff, actually) and other emergency services do more good for society than soldiers</claim> and that <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="2">such discounts should be given to them</claim>.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="3">As for the &#8220;They&#8217;re not risking their lives for our country.&#8221; argument, police officers do that too, and for citizens rather than the country and its interests</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">Some might argue that soldiers do the US a disservice rather than help</premise>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="5">that&#8217;s [usually] the fault of their leaders and therefore not relevant to the debate</premise>.

I&#8217;m really hoping there&#8217;s a good reason behind the status quo, but we&#8217;ll see.
<premise type="logos" id="6">[It looks like there&#8217;s even less reason behind it than I initially thought, actually.]</premise>

[edits in brackets]

[[My view&#8217;s been changed.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview
/comments/2rexe3/cmv_emts_sar_firefighters_police_etc_should/cnfj9cu?context=10000) In summary, I think that <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="7">EMS people are just as deserving of these discounts (and that many more people contribute enough to be placed in the same category)</claim>, but I now believe - for the same reason - that <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="8">these discounts shouldn&#8217;t be offered at all</claim>.]

</OP>
<reply id="cnfkm3z" author="ReverendEarthwormJim">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="9">No they should not.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="10">Those people are civilians with full civil rights</premise> and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="11">in the case of police, are in a privileged position with regard to the law.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="12">Military personnel make substantial sacrifices and frequently live in poor conditions.</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="13">While I disagree with the hero fetish that is popular these days</claim>, <claim type="interpretation" id="14">I understand and support discounts for military personnel.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="15">Also, note that EMS personnel are frequently employes of private corporations.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnfmv09" author="ke7ofi">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="16">I&#8217;m not sure how sacrificing rights makes them more deserving of such discounts.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="17">After all, rewarding people for suffering rather than production is what the commies do[!]</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnfn0it" author="ReverendEarthwormJim">

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="18">War for oil sustains our economy.</premise>
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="19">Not sure where you got your idea of communism</premise>, but <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="20">ok</claim>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnfn5rx" author="ke7ofi">

Note the irony punctuation.
It was a joke based on Rand&#8217;s criticism of loving people for their flaws (I haven&#8217;t seen this happen outside of *Atlas Shrugged*.) and the stereotype of the militaristic, commie-hatin&#8217; &#8217;Murican.

</reply>
</thread>
