<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rekjo">
<title>CMV: I believe you have three choices once you discover the suffering animals endure in the meat industry...</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rekjo/cmv_i_believe_you_have_three_choices_once_you/</source>
<OP author="Anticarnist">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">The options are as follows</claim>:

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="1">1. You don't agree with what is going on and stop supporting it.</claim>

<claim type="disagreement" id="2">2. You don't care about animals, so you're content with paying for them to be abused for your pleasure.</claim>

<claim type="interpretation" id="3">3. You don't agree with what is going on, but try to put it to the back of your mind and continue to support it.</claim>

Reasoning: <premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">I used to follow 'option number 3', but recently started 'option number 1' in an attempt to line my actions up with my values.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="5">I suspect this way of looking at it is still somewhat simplistic however</claim>, so feel free to prove me wrong.

</OP>
<reply id="cnf49ho" author="Kirkaine">

(http://theconversation.com/ordering-the-vegetarian-meal-theres-more-animal-blood-on-your-hands-4659)
<premise type="logos" id="6">So what do you do when you discover [the suffering animals endure in the vegetarian food industry?]</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnf4ibc" author="Anticarnist">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="7">Ahh I've seen that article before and it's incredibly flawed.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="8">It boggles my mind it was even published in all honesty.</claim>

<premise type="pathos" id="9">Livestock animals eat a hell of a lot more crops humans do right?</premise>
So <premise type="logos" id="10">if you're really concerned with the damage done by the land use of growing food</premise>, then <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="11">not eating meat would be a great first step to reducing it</claim>.

<premise type="ethos_logos" id="12">The land required to feed one vegan for a single year is 1/6th of an acre and the land required to feed one meat eater for a year is 18 times more than that.</premise>

[Here's a cool infographic I found this morning](http://www.cowspiracy.com/infographic/)

</reply>
<reply id="cnf4ldj" author="Kirkaine">
&gt;Livestock animals eat a hell of a lot more crops humans do right?

<claim type="interpretation" id="13">Not all crops are created equal.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="14">How much grass do you eat on an average day?</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="15">No mice are slowly poisoned to death growing grass, they are for the crops that humans eat.</claim>
<claim type="disagreement" id="16">Why, it's almost like you only read the top two paragraphs.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cnf54op" author="Anticarnist">

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="17">I read it a month or so ago I'm actually referring to corn.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="18">More corn is produced for livestock than humans.</premise>

<premise type="logos" id="19">36% of all privately held acres in the US is used for growing corn just for livestock.</premise>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="20">That's without even getting into the massive amounts of land used for soy and hay production for livestock.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnf5l4o" author="Kirkaine">

Once again, read the article closely.
<premise type="logos" id="22">It's written by an Australian (where most livestock is grass-fed)</premise>, and <premise type="logos" id="23">explicitly notes that it only applies when livestock is fed on grass rather than grain</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="24">The fact that the US uses a poor method of production is not an indictment of the meat industry as a whole.</claim>

</reply>
</thread>
