<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rekjo">
<title>CMV: I believe you have three choices once you discover the suffering animals endure in the meat industry...</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rekjo/cmv_i_believe_you_have_three_choices_once_you/</source>
<OP author="Anticarnist">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">The options are as follows</claim>:

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="1">1. You don't agree with what is going on and stop supporting it.</claim>

<claim type="disagreement" id="2">2. You don't care about animals, so you're content with paying for them to be abused for your pleasure.</claim>

<claim type="interpretation" id="3">3. You don't agree with what is going on, but try to put it to the back of your mind and continue to support it.</claim>

Reasoning: <premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">I used to follow 'option number 3', but recently started 'option number 1' in an attempt to line my actions up with my values.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="5">I suspect this way of looking at it is still somewhat simplistic however</claim>, so feel free to prove me wrong.

</OP>
<reply id="cnf5658" author="garnteller">

<claim type="disagreement" id="6">There is a 4th choice.</claim>
You can choose to not anthropomorphize animals, and, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="7">despite how much you love your dog</claim>, realize that a chicken is just a chicken, and that <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="8">your farmed tilapia doesn't have the cognition to question whether it's life is worth living.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="9">I want the animals to be raised humanely</claim>, and, yes, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="10">I want them to be killed humanely</claim>.
But <premise type="logos_pathos" id="11">it's not like a wild turkey sits on it's deathbed and thinks fondly of those days gone by, when it roamed free and raised its baby turkeys.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="12">No, it thinks more "food? sex? food?".</claim>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="14">Yes, they feel pain, but so does an earthworm, if you mean "experience messages that say 'bad things are happening - endeavor to stop them'".</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="15">They don't look back and say, "Man, remember when I bumped into that electric fence?</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="16">That hurt like hell."</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="17">The best they can manage is "Fence. Bad."</claim>

<premise type="logos" id="19">There is no "meaningful" or "meaningless" life for an animal - they don't philosophize beyond needs.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="20">Most farm animals spend less time hungry, scratched by brambles, running from predators, etc than wild animals.</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="21">It doesn't make it a better of worse life - it's just existing.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="22">That's the other choice - accepting that animals are less than humans.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cnf5tce" author="Anticarnist">

&gt;a chicken is just a chicken

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="23">A chicken feels pain and suffering and does not want to feel those things as much as we do.</claim>

&gt;But it's not like a wild turkey sits on it's deathbed and thinks fondly of those days gone by, when it roamed free and raised its baby turkeys. No, it thinks more "food? sex? food?".

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="24">My sister is severely mentally disabled and most likely doesn't have the capacity to think fondly of days gone by on her death bed either.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="25">Does intelligence really make much of a difference when it comes to the ethics of whether we can kill them without moral concern?</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="26">I still don't see any good argument for how animals are 'less' than humans (beyond our own obvious bias).</claim>

EDIT: formatting

</reply>
<reply id="cnfaa3o" author="garnteller">

<premise type="" id="27">How does a chicken "want" anything?</premise>
<claim type="agreement" id="28">It is completely incapable of developing a though like, "Today would REALLY suck if that damn fox bites me again".</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="29">Yes, intelligence matters.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="30">If not, we wouldn't allow brain-dead people to be unplugged.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="31">Self-awareness puts one in a separate category than an animal.</claim>
But, regardless, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="32">I'm not trying to convince you not to care about animals</claim>, but that <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="33">a rational person could come to the decision that those without higher cognition or self-awareness aren't equal.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cnfazzs" author="Anticarnist">

<claim type="disagreement" id="34">Self awareness isn't a human-exclusive trait</claim> - <premise type="logos" id="35">dolphins, apes and elephants have been proven to possess it</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="36">Regardless of self-awareness</premise>, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="37">the ability to suffer is what I regard as being more important to an individual.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cnfculi" author="garnteller">

<claim type="interpretation" id="38">That may be what YOU consider, but that's not what others consider</claim>, which is why <claim type="interpretation" id="39">they can validly reach different conclusions.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="40">And "suffer" needs more definition to discuss whether it's something animals can do.</claim>

</reply>
</thread>
