<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rekjo">
<title>CMV: I believe you have three choices once you discover the suffering animals endure in the meat industry...</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rekjo/cmv_i_believe_you_have_three_choices_once_you/</source>
<OP author="Anticarnist">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">The options are as follows</claim>:

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="1">1. You don't agree with what is going on and stop supporting it.</claim>

<claim type="disagreement" id="2">2. You don't care about animals, so you're content with paying for them to be abused for your pleasure.</claim>

<claim type="interpretation" id="3">3. You don't agree with what is going on, but try to put it to the back of your mind and continue to support it.</claim>

Reasoning: <premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">I used to follow 'option number 3', but recently started 'option number 1' in an attempt to line my actions up with my values.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="5">I suspect this way of looking at it is still somewhat simplistic however</claim>, so feel free to prove me wrong.

</OP>
<reply id="cnf4upl" author="Mavericgamer">

Option 3.1415926: <claim type="interpretation" id="6">I buy all my meat from local farms that I know have free-range chickens and cows that are grass-fed and well-treated until they are humanely slaughtered</claim>, and <premise type="logos" id="7">once the technology exists to 3D-print a chicken breast that tastes about as good as the real thing at an affordable price with 0 animal death, I eat that instead.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnf5jn6" author="Anticarnist">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="9">I personally don't see any distinction between my pet dog and a chicken.</claim>
If <premise type="logos" id="10">I had to take my cat to be euthanised at the vet</premise>, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="11">I would never consider his throat being sliced by a machine as he hung upside down as humane treatment.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="12">Probably not even a bolt to the brain either.</claim>

<claim type="agreement" id="13">I agree that synthetic meat would be absolutely amazing though!</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cnf7p8l" author="Mavericgamer">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="14">I do see a distinction between a pet and livestock</claim>, namely that <premise type="logos_pathos" id="15">we domesticated those pet animals for the purpose of companionship</premise> (and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="16">in the case of the dog, a symbiotic relationship involving feeding them scraps for protection against predators that their scent can pick up easier than our sight, particularly at night</premise>), and have <premise type="logos_pathos" id="17">bonded with them specifically because their utility functions are greater as companions than as meat</premise>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="18">Chickens simply aren't.</claim>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="19">Also, again, local farms and humane slaughtering, not factory farming.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="20">As far as I'm aware, chickens at my local farm have their brains destroyed at the stem as quickly as possible while their head is chopped off.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="21">Gory, but painless, as the pain center is instantly destroyed.</premise>
And <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="22">I wouldn't want to witness it</claim>, but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="23">I would accept that as a humane death (as humane as we can make death, anyway)</claim>, as <premise type="logos" id="24">it has as little pain as we can deliver.</premise>
Admittedly, <claim type="interpretation" id="25">a better way would be a proper Brompton Cocktail</claim>, but <premise type="pathos" id="26">that would taint meat, and so is unfeasible</premise>.

Finally, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="27">here is the big problem I have</claim>: <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="28">It is literally impossible for me to live without other things dying.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="29">I wish it weren't so</claim>, but <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="30">it is</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="31">Carrots get eaten or boiled alive and we have no evidence that suggests, one way or another, if that is causing them suffering</premise>, as <premise type="logos_pathos" id="32">their nervous system is sufficiently different from us</premise> that I believe <claim type="interpretation" id="33">we wouldn't know what we were looking for</claim>.
However, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="34">there are plants that emit pheromones to alert other plants of an impending insect-predator's presence and causes other plants in the area of the same type to activate defenses</premise>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="35">other plants that will actively tense up in response to needle pricks</premise> (which, further, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="36">will stop responding when exposed to typical anasthetics</premise>), which tells me that <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="37">when plants behave in an animal-like manner, they can and do respond to some sort of pain stimuli.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="38">So, I don't consider plants to be necessarily more moral.</claim>

Further, <claim type="interpretation" id="39">I find death by human to be more humane than death by any other cause that most game or livestock animals could hope for</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="40">At the best</claim>, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="41">chickens, pigs, deer, and cows would have their throats ripped out by weasels or wolves or whatever other predator.</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="42">At best</claim> <premise type="logos" id="43">they'd die slowly and painfully of some disease that they have no hope of overcoming, or slowly and painfully of starvation after breaking a leg and falling behind their herd</premise>.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="44">Nature is not pretty</premise>, and <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="45">we should be working to improve it</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="46">I work best when I've had more to eat than a salad</premise>, so in the long run, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="47">future animals benefit more by my consumption of meat than they would if I was trying to go vegetarian/vegan</claim>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnfba54" author="Anticarnist">

<claim type="disagreement" id="48">I may have a different stance on seeing no difference between companion animals and farm animals</claim> because <premise type="logos_pathos" id="49">many of my pets are exotic and farm animals</premise>.
The fact <premise type="logos_pathos" id="50">we have domesticated some animals</premise> also <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="51">does not mean they suffer any differently to their wild cousins.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="52">Are you seriously saying you consider slaughtering an animal morally equal to harvesting a crop?</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnfc78y" author="Mavericgamer">

In a day, I eat maybe 1/3 of a cow or 1/2 of a chicken if I'm hungry
<premise type="logos" id="54">If I were eating veggies, I'd consume several plants</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="55">I consider my 1 chicken/2 days to be morally equivalent to the 8 heads of lettuce/day it would take me to get the same basic caloric intake (note: I don't have any real accuracy for the amount per day, just a rough guesstimation) to be about morally equal.</claim>

&gt;The fact we have domesticated some animals also does not mean they suffer any differently to their wild cousins.

On the contrary: <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="56">A sheep with a shepherd is many times less likely to have its throat ripped out by a wolf and having its last experience on earth be something as gruesome as the beginnings of being eaten.</claim>
<premise type="pathos" id="57">A bolt to the brain sounds bad</premise>, but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="58">there is nothing past that instant</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="59">No pain, no awareness, just cessation of life</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="60">Ditto that for every other domestic food animal, and even animals that we hunt for food</premise>: <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="61">at the very least we are less vicious than other predators in that we wait until the animal is definitely dead before we start eating it</claim>.

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="62">I'm not arguing that death at the hands of humans is better than living on</claim>; in the general sense, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="63">living on is better than just about any death</claim>; <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="64">I'm arguing that of the potential ways to die, being killed is the best an animal can realistically hope for</claim>.

</reply>
</thread>
