<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rekjo">
<title>CMV: I believe you have three choices once you discover the suffering animals endure in the meat industry...</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rekjo/cmv_i_believe_you_have_three_choices_once_you/</source>
<OP author="Anticarnist">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">The options are as follows</claim>:

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="1">1. You don't agree with what is going on and stop supporting it.</claim>

<claim type="disagreement" id="2">2. You don't care about animals, so you're content with paying for them to be abused for your pleasure.</claim>

<claim type="interpretation" id="3">3. You don't agree with what is going on, but try to put it to the back of your mind and continue to support it.</claim>

Reasoning: <premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">I used to follow 'option number 3', but recently started 'option number 1' in an attempt to line my actions up with my values.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="5">I suspect this way of looking at it is still somewhat simplistic however</claim>, so feel free to prove me wrong.

</OP>
<reply id="cnf4a02" author="ZippityZoppity">

What about Option 4: <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="6">You hate animals and you want to see them killed.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="7">View. Changed.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cnf4jhd" author="Anticarnist">

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="8">Shall we rule out sociopathy/psychopathy?</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnf4o6j" author="ZippityZoppity">

<claim type="agreement" id="9">Hmm maybe if it makes it easier for you</claim>.
Although <claim type="interpretation" id="10">I can imagine someone that has empathy for humans but none for other animals.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cnf5a2k" author="Anticarnist">

<claim type="agreement" id="11">Good point</claim>, although <claim type="interpretation" id="12">I regard that as speciesism.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="13">I do have a Christian friend who is extremely charitable</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="14">She's a carer, a foster mother and a complete romantic who writes novels about angels.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="15">She 's obviously an all-round good and kind person</premise>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="16">she eats meat</premise>.

<claim type="interpretation" id="17">I rationalise this by realising that helping people is her passion</claim>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="19">perhaps her religion justifies a moral distinction between humans and non-human animals</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="20">Doesn't the Bible claim something along the lines of that animals were created for the enjoyment of humans</premise> (I haven't read it myself)?

</reply>
<reply id="cnf5frm" author="ZippityZoppity">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="22">I think it's fairly normal to be a speciesist.</claim>
I want to make note that <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="23">I'm not trying to argue from a point of naturalism in regards to what ought to be done</claim>, but that <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="24">it shouldn't be that surprising when we encounter people that are that way</claim>.

I mean hell, <claim type="disagreement" id="25">it's hard enough for many people to empathize with *each other*</claim>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="26">you're asking them to try to put themselves in the hooves of a cow?</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="27">It's just beyond the scope for many people</claim> unless <premise type="logos_pathos" id="28">they seriously put the time in to think about it</premise>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="29">they've got their own lives to worry about</premise>.

To address your last question, yes, <claim type="disagreement" id="30">the bible states that all animals were put on earth by God to serve man</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="31">There were rules against eating certain kinds</claim>, but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="32">overall the idea was that humans have dominion over all</claim>.
In which case, <claim type="interpretation" id="33">there is no cognitive dissonance</claim>, but <claim type="interpretation" id="34">this would probably fall under your 2nd line of reasoning</claim>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnf5zo4" author="Anticarnist">

&gt;I think it's fairly normal to be a speciesist. I want to make note that I'm not trying to argue from a point of naturalism in regards to what ought to be done, but that it shouldn't be that surprising when we encounter people that are that way.

<claim type="agreement" id="35">Yes, speciesism is indeed the norm</claim> and <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="36">I appreciate you taking the time to comment</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="37">I asked this question so as to keep myself grounded in what other justifications my loved ones around me didn't have the same epiphany I did</claim> (<premise type="logos" id="38">as it may not necessary be the same reasons I had for not going vegan sooner</premise>).

&gt;I mean hell, it's hard enough for many people to empathize with each other, and you're asking them to try to put themselves in the hooves of a cow? It's just beyond the scope for many people unless they seriously put the time in to think about it, and they've got their own lives to worry about.

<claim type="agreement" id="39">A very good reminder, thank you</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="40">Not everyone is as obsessed with philosophy, psychology and nature as I am</claim>, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="41">just as I don't concern myself with keeping extremely up to date on world politics and Amnesty International petitions.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="42">I'd still class it as option 3 though</claim> :P

</reply>
</thread>
