<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rd7mg">
<title>CMV: America is a better place because of the 55 million abortions its had</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rd7mg/cmv_america_is_a_better_place_because_of_the_55/</source>
<OP author="runescapethug">

<premise type="logos" id="0">There have been 55 million abortions in the US since 1973</premise>.

<premise type="logos" id="1">Something in the ballpark of 45% of women who have abortions have more than one abortion</premise>.

<claim type="disagreement" id="2">These people would have been raised by their incompetent parents to drain down society, increase crime rates, suck up resources, and generally screw things up</claim>.

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="3">Various ways to lower a resource negative population would have to be explored, if not because of this 55 million, then because of the next 55 million</claim>.

<claim type="interpretation" id="4">One possibility is that there would be wars waged to try to kill them all, perhaps even with other countries with similar problems</claim>.
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="5">Waging war to purposefully lower population, even with a country facing similar issues, would cost not only resources, but it would also cause political, cultural, and global issues</premise>.

<premise type="logos" id="6">America's innovation and education rankings would be lower</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="7">Every middle-class child in the country would receive a lower quality education if there were 55 million more around</premise>.

(**Note:**I'm not trying to hear arguments on the ethics of abortion, its a banal argument that everyone and their mother has had at one point, what I am really fishing for is insight into what the country would look like with those 55 million around.
Would we adapt to the population and make good use of each of them?)

**Was view changed?**
<claim type="interpretation" id="8">Its a complicated issue</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="9">Without the extra population from abortions, has there been proportionately more immigration to fill labor needs, or are the millions of illegals from Mexico as likely to be so numerous even if there was a higher none-abortion population</premise>?
<premise type="logos" id="10">Doesn't immigration of a working class citizen on such a massive scale cause dissonance in a country more so than it does cultural exchange</premise>, meaning that <claim type="disagreement" id="11">it would have been preferable to have our abortions alive</claim>?
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="12">Or are we talking about a population so huge that race and national identity are insignificant, that there is always going to be a huge amount of hostility between different demographics</premise>?
-(choppy writing, but i'm on 3 hours of sleep and stretched for time, give me a break)-

(Side thought: <claim type="interpretation" id="13">Perhaps the immigration of illegals is lowering the value of blue collar work and makes it harder for the borderline impoverished citizens to provide for their children</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="14">Its debatable how many women are having abortions due to financial reasons</claim>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="15">surely its a significant number</premise>, so <premise type="logos_pathos" id="16">how many of these women wouldn't be having financial troubles if there wasn't competition from cheap illegal labor to keep wages lower</premise>?
<claim type="agreement" id="17">This holds true even if illegal immigration is an overall plus to the countries value</claim>.
Conclusion: <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="18">Mexicans are the supreme race, native Americans will go extinct through abortion and then out-breeding.</claim> *no that isn't a serious sentiment,
i'm just saying, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="19">this discussion is abstract enough to go into some weird places and that it is necessary to have a stopping point*</claim> )

Then there is the next question.
<claim type="interpretation" id="20">Is a more highly populated and economically productive America today going to result in an America tomorrow that can handle over population problems</claim>, or <claim type="interpretation" id="21">would having a higher population from none-abortion just add on to the problems of a world going to shit</claim>?
Similar: <premise type="logos_pathos" id="22">An aborted fetus is likely to have been a less productive person than a never-considered-for-abortion fetus</premise>, but <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="23">in an industrial society, its likely that these abortions would still be more productive than not</claim>.

<claim type="interpretation" id="24">Then there was the debate as to whether or not a larger population with less resources per person is more innovative than a smaller one</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="25">This is to be considered if one is convinced that having a higher population coming from none-abortions results in a strain for resources in the country</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="26">Modern technology like the internet must be considered</claim>.

Yes, my view was changed, but not into the polar opposite.
I am now confused and lost.

**EDIT:**

I'll be without internet for a few days.
I may end up returning and responding more but it won't be anytime soon.

This was my first post to CMV.
I apologize for a few things that I did that could be considered *rude* around here.
I also see a few times where I got redundant.

Thank you all for your arguments.
This is a very critical place, I hope to learn how to better use it and come here more often.
I feel I could learn a lot here.

</OP>
<reply id="cnfit4i" author="WhenSnowDies">

<claim type="interpretation" id="27">One thing not calculated in the slightly psychotic weighing of the value of human life as "useful" is the sociological effect of the 55 million just gone</claim>: <premise type="logos" id="28">A Zeitgeist wherein 55 million abortions is weighed as good for industry or not, the resulting thinking it good on account of efficiency, as certain citizens look on themselves and others as a figure or livestock</premise>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="29">The attitude of human value as "what they [potentially] contributed to me/Exxon Mobile" is the spirit of eugenics and genocide, subjects often glorified on reddit.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="30">It's the same problem with war</claim>: <premise type="logos" id="31">Once killing foreigners is an acceptable/inevitable means to profit and expand, you find that attitudes exposed to such behavior change with it</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="32">Other countries also build militaries to do so and to "defend" against each other</premise>, and <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="33">its no longer viewed as a hostile or paranoid thing to do</claim> because <premise type="logos" id="34">everybody's doing it and so must do it</premise>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="35">It becomes a recursive loop and generates a hostile attitude towards foreigners and other countries</claim>.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="36">This works on the inverse too</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="37">When we went to the moon, our horizons and view of mankind changed</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="38">Once we better understood such objects, nature worship definitely changed</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="39">You'll be hard-pressed to find moon worshipers today</premise>, and <premise type="logos" id="40">the "religions of the book" may be going out of style as highly literate people have access to more historical data and the time to translate The Bible, Torah, and Quran in context for themselves</premise>.
Also, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="41">it was once normal for religions to kill masses of unbelievers</claim>; <premise type="logos" id="42">now it's seen as wrong, even by the religions themselves</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="43">The Zeitgeist changes, as people's attitudes adjust to new information and ways of life and problem solving</claim>.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="44">This Zeitgeist concept is the same problem with the public school</claim>.
In it, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="45">intelligence is reduced to reciting what one is told to a high degree of accuracy and memorization</claim>, data treated as "fact" or "fiction" (<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="46">in reality, everything is true/untrue depending on it's level of resolution or accuracy</claim>), <premise type="logos" id="47">children are moved through by age, graded literally on the same scale as a meat product, and bells move them around</premise>.
On this, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="48">they're declared intelligent or not, and implicitly worthwhile or not</claim>.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="49">The many nuances of intelligence, higher forms of intelligence, varieties of people, and bigger issues like antisocial personality disorder and social skills, are virtually ignored during the developmental period for the "efficient" cattle model</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="50">Good meat or bad meat, instead of people with a variety of skill potential and problems</premise>.
<premise type="pathos" id="51">We end up with McEducation literally, with a lot of "product" to be "thrown away" and that seen as okay</premise>; but <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="52">the worst thing is not that</claim>, but <premise type="pathos" id="53">the Zeitgeist within society that people should be "grown", and graded, and that these categories are accurate</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="54">Consequential attitudes include the idea that information will be bestowed to us like our teachers did</premise>, that <premise type="logos" id="55">it's "true" or not and that "truth" is available to us in an absolute way</premise>, and <premise type="logos" id="56">that smart people are cooperative</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="57">Political parties appeal to these learned biases</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="58">The general attitude among the adult population is "don't think too much"</claim>, because <premise type="logos" id="59">it's seen as disruptive, problem-making, and culturally odious, and taking sides on trust is often seen as a good thing</premise>.

So with 55 million abortions, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="60">you're also treated to relaxed attitudes towards eugenics and genocide, and all the warped views of human value and what a "better place" is that come with it</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="61">Decisions are give-and-take and has benefits as well as problems</premise>.
You see, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="62">there would have certainly been benefits to a preemptive tactical nuclear strike against the USSR, and costs too</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="63">Anybody who denies either is blinded by zeal</premise>, and I'm not saying such a strike would have been worth it, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="64">only that benefits would exist and it's our job to weigh those against the costs always</claim>.
<premise type="pathos" id="65">If you cannot see the cost of the 55 million abortions, it means that you should immediately change your view so you can experience the other side of your thinking</premise>, <premise type="pathos" id="66">which has hijacked your perception and mistaken itself for truth recursively</premise>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnh1eex" author="runescapethug">

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="67">You're mistaking what I believe to be a good outcome as different from what you believe to be a good outcome</claim>.

Think America in 1000 years.
<premise type="logos" id="68">This America faced a sustainable growth rate</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="69">Imagine this country to be populated by billions of faces</premise>.
Pretend that technology has reached such a point that any human can pursue any passion they wish.
These Americans can go enjoy the wilderness of a terraformed planet (or use their immortality to wait until that is possible), enter a virtual reality program and experience any event by any person in history as if it was true, go see dinosaurs at the zoo, pursue as many doctorates as they'd like, increase or decrease their intelligence, and never have to work a day of their lives to earn such privileges.

Now imagine America in 200 years.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="70">Babies were created indiscriminately</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="71">The quality of education regressed and then stagnated to that of the year 1970</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="72">Even with new technology, having enough drinking water and arable land is becoming an issue</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="73">Everything is polluted to hell</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="74">The wealth gap is a factor of ten worse</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="75">The perception of the value of human life goes to zero</premise>.

(<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="76">I am in no way claiming that either one of those imaginary futures would result from having legal/illegal abortion</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="77">My point is that a responsible today allows for a better future</claim>.
My illustrations are ridiculous )

<claim type="agreement" id="78">Decisions like whether or not the non-existence of 55 million people provides to the greater good have to be faced, such as you said</claim>.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="79">Your claim is that the conscious acceptance of deaths providing logistical benefits is damaging to our perception of the value of human life</claim>.

<claim type="agreement" id="80">That is true</claim>, and <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="81">such sentiment should be properly weighed by someone attempting to assess whether or not these 55 million abortions have had a positive outcome</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="82">This should not overtake their thinking and drown out the other considerations</claim>.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="83">I believe you are in agreement with that</claim>.
However, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="84">you take the Zeitgeist as pretty much the highest consideration</claim>.
<claim type="disagreement" id="84a">This is where we disagree.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="85">I believe in a shittier today for a better tomorrow, such as how our ancestors had miserable and productive lives that ended up with us living to be 80 and fat</premise>.

<premise type="logos" id="86">I also don't think that the connection between poor education tactics and the "don't think too much" mentalities can be drawn between the zeitgeist claims you're making</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="87">If the quality of life is higher, you'll see higher quality education and the available resources for more to be able to think and live as as they'd like</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="88">If the quality of life is lower, you'll see people working miserable jobs just to be able to eat dinner</premise>, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="89">the only way to avoid depression would be to not think too much</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="90">Having a low quality of life results in a poor Zeitgeist</premise>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnhn714" author="WhenSnowDies">
&gt;I believe you are in agreement with that. However, you take the Zeitgeist as pretty much the highest consideration. This is where we disagree. I believe in a shittier today for a better tomorrow, such as how our ancestors had miserable and productive lives that ended up with us living to be 80 and fat.

No, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="91">I was only illustrating a hidden and relatable X-factor to get you to open up within your own assumptions and realize [how many other X-factors might exist,](https://www.reddit.com/r/dataisbeautiful/comments/2rj2bt/50_of_nigeriens_are_under_14_years_old_in/cngsdvf) and to encourage more caution towards unforeseen consequences and butterfly effects</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="92">I chose this approach because your view is highly cerebral and overconfident, seemingly unconcerned with potential consequence, and repackaging gross oversimplification and naive callous as bright utilitarianism (no offense)</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="93">I wanted to offer an example that had to do with people, instead of indulging your quasi-psychotic reasoning</premise>.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="94">See, psychotic behavior is retarded literally</claim>: <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="95">It comes from a lack of emotional sense and is a developmental disorder</claim>. <premise type="logos" id="96">I'm telling you this because you're probably a teen and will grow out of it by interacting with people like you are</premise>, and <premise type="logos" id="97">having them challenge you and show disgust</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="98">Psychotics are developmentally stunted because they're antisocial, even when they're around people</premise>, and so <premise type="logos_pathos" id="99">they never change their view and only develop a 7-year-old view from a little monster into a big monster</premise>.
That said, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="100">giving you the socio-political consequences of 55 million people missing might change your view</claim>, but <premise type="logos" id="101">the stupid and shallow premises would remain untouched</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="102">You might adjust your facts, but not expand your perspective</claim>.

See, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="103">the reason people are highly sensitive [emotionally] is the same reason you'd turn up the sensitivity dial of a camera, microphone, or any other sensor</claim>: Because <premise type="pathos" id="104">you're concerned you'll miss something, and are aware of the dangers of missing something</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="105">The mind and emotions operate like extremely complex equipment</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="106">This is why some people are very squeamish; myself not included</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="107">Contrarily, when a person is very confident, it's [almost never because they're on a higher tier of information or understanding</premise>](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunning%E2%80%93Kruger_effect), but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="108">because they don't even know that they don't know</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="109">In the case of cold utility, often peddled by teens as very novel because life and the self seems very simple to them, because they've such a low tier of contact with the world that it can look simple from a distance</premise>.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="110">It's why we recruit teens into the military</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="111">They're very easy to trick and convince to shoot a guy in a field for wearing different clothes without asking a lot of questions or thinking too hard about consequences</premise>.

Anyway, that's why I gave that explanation, and <claim type="disagreement" id="112">you didn't anticipate it, but thought you did, didn't you</claim>?
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="113">You said I gave the Zeitgeist explanation because it was my best</claim>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="114">it was really tailored to challenge your reasoning style</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="115">You probably don't see yourself as having a predictable reasoning style</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="116">This is the problem with X-factors and complexity</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="117">You don't know what you don't know, you didn't know you didn't know my motivation, and you don't know that the 55 million abortions were a good thing, or what interests were operating in the establishment of them, or the consequences</premise>.
So far, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="118">the consequences are extremely negative for your generation</claim>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnhq13m" author="runescapethug">

Essentially, <claim type="interpretation" id="119">i'm emotionally retarded, and instead of giving into my nature and letting my thought process be masturbated from a more standard answer, you're subjecting me to therapy by trying to illustrate that such views are had by inferior humans</claim>?
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="120">My inferior mind must be shown new views in order for me to see how wrong my initial view is</premise>? (teens tricked into joining the military, developmentally stunted, antisocial.
<claim type="interpretation" id="121">These illustrations very clearly show that you are attempting for me to change my view based on your argument that I am inferior</claim>. )

<claim type="interpretation" id="122">As for your concluding paragraph, it is complete nonsense</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="123">There is an assumption every other sentence with the remaining sentences being filled with assertions that you have not been backed with well-founded arguments</premise>.
<premise type="pathos" id="124">You completely circumvented every single debate being had in this thread and proceeded to ejaculate your rather arrogant assumptions all over the place</premise> .
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="125">It seems that you can barely fathom that you *may* be wrong, that you are too intelligent to have to provide any adequate reasoning for yourself</premise>.

Also, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="126">I don't know where in this thread that I was *very confident* in my views</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="127">On the contrary to the Dunning-Krueger effect you are implying that I face, I am very critical of myself and feel incompetent in areas where others rate me as competent</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="128">I have not said a single thing in this thread that i've been absolutely sure of</premise>.

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="129">Really, your argument is absolutely ludacris</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="130">It boils down to a well constructed shitpost</premise>.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="131">*those abortions may have been a good thing?</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="132">you can have that thought</premise>??
<premise type="logos" id="133">* **you are a retard!** *argue about whether or not these abortions have had a benefit to the country? </premise> 
<claim type="disagreement" id="135">I think not! you need to expand your perspective to not even consider such things!</claim>*

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="136">Its rather ironic that you are peddling how emotionally retarded I am</claim>, yet <premise type="logos_pathos" id="137">how you spent the past two comments trying to classify me, inform me of my inadequacies, *subtly be a superior human being*, and also fall under what seems to be the Dunning-Krueger effect yourself</premise>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnhubsd" author="WhenSnowDies">
&gt;Essentially, i'm emotionally retarded, and instead of giving into my nature and letting my thought process be masturbated from a more standard answer, you're subjecting me to therapy by trying to illustrate that such views are had by inferior humans?

Therapy. 
<claim type="agreement" id="138">I like that.</claim>
<claim type="disagreement" id="139">So personal; very theatrical</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="140">Can I comment on your inferior reasoning and why it's inferior without it being a big deal</premise>?
This is Change My View.
<premise type="logos" id="141">Did you expect people to *not* shoot holes in your reasoning</premise>?

&gt; My inferior mind must be shown new views in order for me to see how wrong my initial view is?

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="142">I'm pretty sure that's how everybody's mind works at all times</claim>, and <premise type="pathos" id="143">that I said that</premise>, and <premise type="pathos" id="144">you know that :)</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="145">I find your passive aggressiveness and focus on superiority and inferiority to be low</claim>.
I'd of liked this to have been mature, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="146">you probably should have anticipated people finding your worldview to be wrong on CMV</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="147">To change your view, they inevitably have to think you're wrong on some level of analysis</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="148">Didn't you anticipate your apparent reasoning to be challenged in the least</premise>?
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="149">Or did I do it too offensively well</premise>?

&gt; Teens tricked into joining the military, developmentally stunted, antisocial. These illustrations very clearly show that you are attempting for me to change my view based on your argument that I am inferior

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="150">Teens are still developing, you know</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="151">There's [plenty of research](http://www.health.harvard.edu/blog-extra/the-adolescent-brain-beyond-raging-hormones) supporting that their minds aren't fully developed</premise> and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="152">that they're incapable of certain higher processes regarding emotional awareness</premise>.
Also <premise type="logos" id="153">I was careful to say that psychosis was a developmental disorder</premise>, and <premise type="logos" id="154">that teenage reasoning only appears quasi-psychotic, but that it's not</premise>, in explaining how people think emotionally and why in a way you could understand.

<premise type="logos" id="155">And you can understand it, and do; which is why you're pissed</premise>.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="156">I didn't tell you to change your view because you're inferior</claim>, and <premise type="logos" id="157">I had the courtesy to explain what you missed and why</premise>, <premise type="logos" id="158">which did include a current inability to anticipate consequences (which is in the linked Harvard study) and how changing your view was a part of growing up and why</premise>.
Don't try and punish me for talking to you.

&gt; As for your concluding paragraph, it is complete nonsense. There is an assumption every other sentence with the remaining sentences being filled with assertions that you have not been backed with well-founded arguments.

Name one.

&gt; You completely circumvented every single debate being had in this thread and proceeded to ejaculate your rather arrogant assumptions all over the place

<premise type="logos" id="159">If by that you mean I posted my own impressions like everybody else,</premise><claim type="agreement" id="160">yeah</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="161">I think you're describing your feelings of how all the other posts were dwarfed in your opinion and are in my post's shadow, and how you hate it</claim>.
I like the implied sexual dominance part.
I'll take the ejaculating comment and agree on that.
I really did pound your thread pretty hard with thoughts, and I liked it.

&gt; It seems that you can barely fathom that you *may* be wrong, that you are too intelligent to have to provide any adequate reasoning for yourself.

<claim type="agreement" id="162">Well my post was about being wrong as an asset to learning things</claim>, but let's not spit hairs.
<premise type="logos" id="163">Yeah it's pretty important to not think what you think is wrong</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="164">There's not a lot of sense in thinking things you don't think are true</premise>.

&gt; Also, I don't know where in this thread that I was *very confident* in my views. On the contrary to the Dunning-Krueger effect you are implying that I face, I am very critical of myself and feel incompetent in areas where others rate me as competent. I have not said a single thing in this thread that i've been absolutely sure of

<claim type="interpretation" id="165">Most folks don't claim to have extreme views unless they have an unhealthy degree of misguided confidence in them</claim>.
At least enough confidence to have the gull to say it.
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="166">If you came up and said you hated black people I'd also assume you were relatively confident about it, too</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="167">Not exactly humble beliefs, are they</premise>.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="168">See, no emotional awareness</premise>. Harvard study.
<premise type="logos" id="169">My posts.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="170">Read them</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="171">You don't understand the signals you're sending, and get upset when folks read between the lines because you put the wrong information between them--likely true information</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="172">You probably really do believe America is a better place because of the 55 million abortions its had, and you probably see how shallow and dumb that is in retrospect</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="173">It's good that you've distanced yourself from your view in saying you're not that confident in it</claim>.
It's one step closer to abandoning it.

&gt; Really, your argument is absolutely ludacris. It boils down to a well constructed shitpost.

:D

&gt; *those abortions may have been a good thing? you can have that thought??* **you are a retard!** *argue about whether or not these abortions have had a benefit to the country? I think not! you need to expand your perspective to not even consider such things!*

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="174">Most people would have thought that, and would have been satisfied to ignore you for this very reason and not respond</claim>.
I did anticipate this, and I'm not doing it to troll, but I really do want to change your view--more specifically, that sort of thinking.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="175">It'll go well with you to be smarter than that</premise>.

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="176">I think it's working</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="177">I think your rage is death throes of a bad way of thinking</claim>.
Enjoy it.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="178">People smarter than you have a nasty habit of being a little proud and avoid conflict, and will just judge you when you tell them stuff like that, instead of taking the time to tell you why you're wrong</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="179">Few people are willing to correct even false facts these days, let alone patterns and assumptions</premise>.

&gt; Its rather ironic that you are peddling how emotionally retarded I am, yet how you spent the past two comments trying to classify me, inform me of my inadequacies, *subtly be a superior human being,* and also fall under what seems to be the Dunning-Krueger effect yourself

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="180">It's Dunning-Kruger</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="181">Also your view didn't anticipate the human element an iota</premise>, and <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="182">that was a lapse in emotion that revealed your age</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="183">Once you learn what you don't know, you will have made a dent in knowledge akin to the damage a dove would do to a mountain if it few by lightly brushing it with the tip of its wing</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="184">In other words, it wouldn't be a drop in the ocean, so if you're squeamish about being ignorant you shouldn't have been born, because everybody is ignorant of most things</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="185">Fixing your thought patterns means you can be like an explorer who can take weirdness as it comes and be ready to deal with it, instead of having a tiff when you get called dumb for calling 55 million abortions a good thing with c.15 whole years of experience</premise>.
As for you, fix those thought patterns and get used to it, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="186">because you're going to readjust a lot</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="187">Best to find out how to deal with information instead of trying to be "right"</claim>, because <premise type="logos_pathos" id="188">sides are made by and for clergy and politicians, it wont do you any good</premise>.

</reply>
<reply id="cnhx92z" author="runescapethug">

&gt; Therapy. I like that. So personal; very theatrical. Can I comment on your inferior reasoning and why it's inferior without it being a big deal? This is Change My View. Did you expect people to not shoot holes in your reasoning? If my reasoning is inferior, than prove the original view along with the logic behind it wrong. Its that simple .     

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="189">I wouldn't say you shot holes in my idea, more so that you used an unnecessary amount of time and effort to make a few simple points</claim>.

&gt; I'm pretty sure that's how everybody's mind works at all times, and that I said that, and you know that :)

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="190">Most minds don't work in such a way that they have to ignore information to function</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="191">The claim that one has to be emotionally retarded to have such a thought is ridiculous</claim>.

":)"
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="192">you seem to have been made mad by my comment and then put anger into the rest of your response</claim>.

&gt; I find your passive aggressiveness and focus on superiority and inferiority to be low.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="193">Perhaps it is shallow</claim>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="194">it is the topic you set, no</premise>?

&gt; I'd of liked this to have been mature, and you probably should have anticipated people finding your worldview to be wrong on CMV. To change your view, they inevitably have to think you're wrong on some level of analysis.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="195">Of course, but that doesn't mean that I have to agree with you when I see you as wrong</claim>.

&gt; Didn't you anticipate your apparent reasoning to be challenged in the least? Or did I do it too offensively well?

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="196">I absolutely expected to be chewed alive for every fallacy I had</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="197">What I was *annoyed* by were your unfounded and arrogant assumptions</claim>.

&gt; Teens are still developing, you know. There's plenty of research supporting that their minds aren't fully developed and that they're incapable of certain higher processes regarding emotional awareness. Also I was careful to say that psychosis was a developmental disorder, and that teenage reasoning only appears quasi-psychotic, but that it's not, in explaining how people think emotionally and why in a way you could understand.    

There you go again.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="198">You claim i'm too underdeveloped to argue with, I should just accept your view, flush my brain of such thoughts, and continue about my day</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="199">You truly are ridiculous</premise>.

&gt; And you can understand it, and do; which is why you're pissed
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="200">I didn't tell you to change your view because you're inferior</claim>, and <premise type="logos" id="201">I had the courtesy to explain what you missed and why, which did include a current inability to anticipate consequences (which is in the linked Harvard study) and how changing your view was a part of growing up and why</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="202">Don't try and punish me for talking to you</premise>.

I'm not anticipating consequences?
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="203">That was the entire point of my CMV</claim>.
<premise type="pathos" id="204">Did you not even read any of this?</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="205">Did you not see the note that said that I was fishing for insight into the impact of 55 million abortions</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="206">?</premise> <premise type="logos" id="207">You could have actually posed consequences to change my view</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="208">And Christ, you said you *had the courtesy to explain this to me*. Kid...</premise>

&gt;"As for your concluding paragraph, it is complete nonsense. There is an assumption every other sentence with the remaining sentences being filled with assertions that you have not been backed with well-founded arguments."
&gt;**Name one.**

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="209">Anyway, that's why I gave that explanation, and you didn't anticipate it, but thought you did, didn't you?</claim> (1) <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="210">You said I gave the Zeitgeist explanation because it was my best</claim>(2), but <premise type="logos" id="211">it was really tailored to challenge your reasoning style</premise>.
<premise type="pathos" id="212">You probably don't see yourself as having a predictable reasoning style(3)</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="213">This is the problem with X-factors and complexity(4)</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="214">You don't know what you don't know, you didn't know you didn't know my motivation, and you don't know that the 55 million abortions were a good thing(The point of the thread, no?), or what interests were operating in the establishment of them(The point of the thread, no?), or the consequences(The point of the thread, no?)</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="215">So far, the consequences are extremely negative for your generation(heck of a statement without an argument behind it)</premise>

&gt; If by that you mean I posted my own impressions like everybody else, yeah. I think you're describing your feelings of how all the other posts were dwarfed in your opinion and are in my post's shadow, and how you hate it.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="216">A little self important eh?</claim>

&gt; I like the implied sexual dominance part. I'll take the ejaculating comment and agree on that. I really did pound your thread pretty hard with thoughts, and I liked it.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="217">You seem to be quasi-psychotic</claim>

&gt; Well my post was about being wrong as an asset to learning things, but let's not spit hairs. Yeah it's pretty important to not think what you think is wrong. There's not a lot of sense in thinking things you don't think are true.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="218">Rambling on</claim>.

&gt; Most folks don't claim to have extreme views unless they have an unhealthy degree of misguided confidence in them. At least enough confidence to have the gull to say it. If you came up and said you hated black people I'd also assume you were relatively confident about it, too. Not exactly humble beliefs, are they.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="219">First of all, your comments, under your own description of the Dunning Krueger effect, have some serious ass Dunning Krueger</claim>.
Second of all, <premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="220">I had reasoning behind my views, and was confident about the reasoning</premise>, but <premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="221">came here in expectance that there was some reasoning that I had not yet considered which may change my opinion</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="222">I came here to learn</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="223">I came here expecting myself to be proven wrong</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="224">You certainly weren't close to proving anything</premise>.

&gt; See, no emotional awareness. Harvard study. My posts. Read them. You don't understand the signals you're sending, and get upset when folks read between the lines because you put the wrong information between them--likely true information.         

<claim type="interpretation" id="225">Having a thought, however morbid and efficient, is not enough to indicate a lack of emotional intelligence</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="226">People grow up learning different things, and get this, having different views</premise>.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="227">Then you go on to, instead of making an actual argument to prove me wrong, to say that I am not capable of holding these views without being inferior</premise>.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="228">Really, were you home-schooled</premise>?
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="229">Your views are indicative of an angsty 20 year old who has not had much world exposure, one that wasn't weened until the age of 15</premise>.

<premise type="logos" id="230">You also have special snowflake syndrome</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="231">All you do is sputter about whatever little information that you have while maintaining an illusion of superiority so that i'll trust how very *smart* you sound</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="232">I'm supposed to just accept your views without you proving them to be correct?</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="233">This explains how long-winded you are, its apart of the illusion</premise>.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="234">Also, your "Harvard studies, read them" was a pretty vain attempt of seeming more intelligent and of having more authority without adding anything new to the discussion</premise>.

&gt; You probably really do believe America is a better place because of the 55 million abortions its had

Read: post title.

&gt; and you probably see how shallow and dumb that is in retrospect.

<premise type="logos" id="236">600 people would at least agree that it was an interesting thought.</premise>

&gt; It's good that you've distanced yourself from your view in saying you're not that confident in it. It's one step closer to abandoning it.

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="237">I'm not going to *abandon* a view, i'm going to be presented with new information that changes my mind.</claim>

&gt; Most people would have thought that, and would have been satisfied to ignore you for this very reason and not respond.

Oh?
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="238">Then why is this post so popular?</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="239">Again, instead of making actual arguments, all you're doing is to attempt to devalue me and the idea</claim>.

&gt; I did anticipate this, and I'm not doing it to troll, but I really do want to change your view--more specifically, that sort of thinking. It'll go well with you to be smarter than that.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="240">Visit the subreddit /r/iamverysmart to see your error</premise>

&gt; I think it's working. I think your rage is death throes of a bad way of thinking. Enjoy it. People smarter than you have a nasty habit of being a little proud and avoid conflict, and will just judge you when you tell them stuff like that, instead of taking the time to tell you why you're wrong.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="241">You're one of those people you imply?</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="242">See: Dunning Krueger</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="243">Also, see the numerous other similar things you've said that don't actually contribute to the discussion, all you're doing is attempting to devalue the argument and myself.</premise>

&gt; Few people are willing to correct even false facts these days, let alone patterns and assumptions.

Praise jesus!
<claim type="agreement" id="245">this intellectual has blessed me with correcting my false facts! I should be thankful!</claim>

&gt; knowledge akin to the damage a dove would do to a mountain if it few by lightly brushing it with the tip of its wing.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="246">Its like you say the same thing over and over again and make it as convoluted as possible</claim>

&gt; Fixing your thought patterns means you can be like an explorer who can take weirdness as it comes and be ready to deal with it, instead of having a tiff when you get called dumb for calling 55 million abortions a good thing with c.15 whole years of experience.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="247">Isn't this another one of those places where you were supposed to contribute to the discussion rather than doing your *i'm an intellectual* masturbation?</claim>

&gt; As for you, fix those thought patterns and get used to it, because you're going to readjust a lot. Best to find out how to deal with information instead of trying to be "right", because sides are made by and for clergy and politicians, it wont do you any good

Ahh.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="249">I'm susceptible to politics and religion because I disagree with you.</claim>
Bonus fedora points!!

</reply>
</thread>
