<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rnr30">
<title>CMV: I think the Paris shooting makes a good case for culture of responsible gun ownership any carrying.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnr30/cmv_i_think_the_paris_shooting_makes_a_good_case/</source>
<OP author="rrockethr">

Thinking about today's news: [BBC](http://www.bbc.com/news/live/world-europe-30710777), [Wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Hebdo_shooting)

<claim type="interpretation" id="0">I think France is in a tough spot in how to react to this.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">There would be even stronger calls for an anti-islam and anti-immigration policies.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">These event reminds people that they cannot depend on protection by government.</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="3">I think it would be a shame to allow the many, who are afraid more then anything, to be swayed by xenophobic nationalists (which might have been the goal of the attack anyway).</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="4">I think this, regardless of whether the weapons used by the attackers were owned legally, makes a good case for promoting a culture of a reasonable gun ownership and carrying.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="5">Say if 1 out of 5 people carried a gun with them, was well trained in its use and tested in his responsibility to prevent its misuse</premise>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="6">society upheld the value of these people as protectors, it would benefit the society more the the current state of legislature and culture of gun ownership in most of European countries</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="7">I also think this would be much better then increase in police numbers and rights</claim> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="8">as policemen are a very homogeneous group trained to stick together and the danger of even deepening the "not one of us" (pack) mentality and escalation of "police state"</premise>.
Change my view.

PS: I am not here to talk about USA and its gun problems.

EDIT: Awarded a delta to a comment which didn't refute this idea but led me to change my view that it would be best realized with paralyzing weapons rather then guns: http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rnr30/cmv_i_think_the_paris_shooting_makes_a_good_case/cni3o83

</OP>
<reply id="cnhmb9v" author="imaginethehangover">

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="9"> Are you suggesting that INCREASING the number of weapons would decrease the lethal use of those weapons? </claim> 
<claim type="interpretation" id="10"> It MIGHT help mitigate one instance of shootings, like today's in Paris </claim>, but <premise  type="interpretation" id="11"> surely tempt or instigate more occurrences in its place as the weapons are that much easier to access and use? </premise> 
<premise type="logos" id="12"> If increasing gun ownership would benefit society, would there be a point where if X number of people owned and carried a gun, there would be no shootings at all? </premise> 
<premise type="logos" id="13"> How do the stats stack up in support of your view? </premise>

<claim type="interpretation" id="14"> This seems like a very difficult thing to prove or disprove either way because of the lack of research </claim>, but <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="15"> I'm loathed to suggest increasing gun ownership could be a possible solution </claim>, because...<premise type="logos_pathos" id="16"> I dunno,they have a reputation for misuse? </premise> 
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="17"> Surely, LESS would be better? </claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cnhmn66" author="rrockethr">

<claim type="disagreement" id="18"> No I'm not claiming this. </claim> 
Please read again my original post, this time trying to understand it.
<premise type="logos" id="20"> Distinguish between decreasing and stopping, owning and responsibly owning, laws and culture... </premise>
 
</reply>
</thread>
