<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rd7mg">
<title>CMV: America is a better place because of the 55 million abortions its had</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rd7mg/cmv_america_is_a_better_place_because_of_the_55/</source>
<OP author="runescapethug">

<premise type="" id="0">There have been 55 million abortions in the US since 1973</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="1">Something in the ballpark of 45% of women who have abortions have more than one abortion</premise>.
<claim type="disagreement" id="2">These people would have been raised by their incompetent parents to drain down society, increase crime rates, suck up resources, and generally screw things up</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="3">Various ways to lower a resource negative population would have to be explored, if not because of this 55 million, then because of the next 55 million</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="4">One possibility is that there would be wars waged to try to kill them all, perhaps even with other countries with similar problems</claim>.
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="5">Waging war to purposefully lower population, even with a country facing similar issues, would cost not only resources, but it would also cause political, cultural, and global issues</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="6">America's innovation and education rankings would be lower</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="7">Every middle-class child in the country would receive a lower quality education if there were 55 million more around</premise>.
(**Note:**I'm not trying to hear arguments on the ethics of abortion, its a banal argument that everyone and their mother has had at one point, what I am really fishing for is insight into what the country would look like with those 55 million around.
Would we adapt to the population and make good use of each of them?)
**Was view changed?**
<claim type="interpretation" id="8">Its a complicated issue</claim>.
<premise type="logos" id="9">Without the extra population from abortions, has there been proportionately more immigration to fill labor needs, or are the millions of illegals from Mexico as likely to be so numerous even if there was a higher none-abortion population</premise>?
<premise type="logos" id="10">Doesn't immigration of a working class citizen on such a massive scale cause dissonance in a country more so than it does cultural exchange</premise>, meaning that <claim type="disagreement" id="11">it would have been preferable to have our abortions alive</claim>?
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="12">Or are we talking about a population so huge that race and national identity are insignificant, that there is always going to be a huge amount of hostility between different demographics</premise>?
-(choppy writing, but i'm on 3 hours of sleep and stretched for time, give me a break)-
(Side thought: <claim type="interpretation" id="13">Perhaps the immigration of illegals is lowering the value of blue collar work and makes it harder for the borderline impoverished citizens to provide for their children</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="14">Its debatable how many women are having abortions due to financial reasons</claim>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="15">surely its a significant number</premise>, so <premise type="logos_pathos" id="16">how many of these women wouldn't be having financial troubles if there wasn't competition from cheap illegal labor to keep wages lower</premise>?
<claim type="agreement" id="17">This holds true even if illegal immigration is an overall plus to the countries value</claim>.
Conclusion: <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="18">Mexicans are the supreme race, native Americans will go extinct through abortion and then out-breeding.</claim> *no that isn't a serious sentiment,
i'm just saying, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="19">this discussion is abstract enough to go into some weird places and that it is necessary to have a stopping point*</claim> )
Then there is the next question.
<claim type="interpretation" id="20">Is a more highly populated and economically productive America today going to result in an America tomorrow that can handle over population problems</claim>, or <claim type="interpretation" id="21">would having a higher population from none-abortion just add on to the problems of a world going to shit</claim>?
Similar: <premise type="logos_pathos" id="22">An aborted fetus is likely to have been a less productive person than a never-considered-for-abortion fetus</premise>, but <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="23">in an industrial society, its likely that these abortions would still be more productive than not</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="24">Then there was the debate as to whether or not a larger population with less resources per person is more innovative than a smaller one</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="25">This is to be considered if one is convinced that having a higher population coming from none-abortions results in a strain for resources in the country</claim>.
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="26">Modern technology like the internet must be considered</claim>.
Yes, my view was changed, but not into the polar opposite.
I am now confused and lost.
**EDIT:**
I'll be without internet for a few days.
I may end up returning and responding more but it won't be anytime soon.
This was my first post to CMV.
I apologize for a few things that I did that could be considered *rude* around here.
I also see a few times where I got redundant.
Thank you all for your arguments.
This is a very critical place, I hope to learn how to better use it and come here more often.
I feel I could learn a lot here.
_____

</OP>
<reply id="cnevo8r" author="princessbynature">

<quote>"Something in the ballpark of 45% of women who have abortions have more than one abortion.</quote>"Something in the ballpark of 45% of women who have abortions have more than one abortion.
<quote>These people would have been raised by their incompetent parents to drain down society, increase crime rates, suck up resources, and generally screw things up."</quote>These people would have been raised by their incompetent parents to drain down society, increase crime rates, suck up resources, and generally screw things up."
What are you talking about?
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="27">Do you really think abortions are only had by incompetent people who couldn't be good parents?</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="28">This appears to be a belief that has led you to conclude that America must be better off</claim> but <claim type="interpretation" id="29">you are really misinformed about the type of women who obtain abortions.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cnew0yt" author="runescapethug">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="30">That may be true.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="31">My thinking was that abortions were mainly required by unfortunate people, who in turn from their difficult circumstances, would've raised the child to be the same.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="32">Can you counter that?</premise> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="33">I have a [source](http://www.guttmacher.org/media/nr/2010/05/04/index.html) that shows that abortions are typically (and in some years, mostly) had by people without enough wealth to care for there kids.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnf0msd" author="princessbynature">

Sure, hopefully I can find some sources to support this argument as well, otherwise I may have to change my mind!
[http://juneauchoice.com/whohasabortions.htm](Here is a well sourced link to some stats about women who have abortions)
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="34">Some stats for example include "31% of women obtaining abortions are in school; 68% of women who have abortions are employed."</premise>
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="35">"33% of women who obtain abortions have family incomes under $11,000 annually, 11% of abortions are obtained by women whose household incomes are $50,000 or more."</premise>
So <premise type="logos" id="36">that means the majority of those having abortions have income between $11,000 and $55,000, which is above the Federal Poverty line.</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="37">I can't confirm but I do recall reading once that a common reason for women to abort is becoming pregnant too soon after having a child</claim>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="38">It could be about finances but could just be too soon for a woman to go through again.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="39">Pregnancy is hard on the body and far riskier than an abortion performed within a few weeks.</premise>

</reply>
</thread>
