<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rcsdh">
<title>CMV: Humans are going to die out because of an economic collapse</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rcsdh/cmv_humans_are_going_to_die_out_because_of_an/</source>
<OP author="Oflameo">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">Bill Gade presents the argument better than I do so I will just quote him.</claim>

&gt; There have been 4 jobs or activities which Man has engaged in throughout the centuries: Hunter/Gathering, Agriculture, Manufacturing, and Services. What's next? What category can you imagine in which billions of people will be working in the future? 
&gt; It turns out that there is a final category. It is known as Unemployment. As Agriculture, Manufacturing, and Services become more efficient in the coming months, workers will have nowhere to go but to the unemployment line. At some point, Man's artificial economic system will necessarily collapse. When that happens, the corporations which produce and deliver food will no longer have an incentive to do so. The cities will suffer great hunger and it will be the end of Man. 
&gt; The current jobless situation you read about in the news is not an ordinary part of the business cycle. It is the final stretch of the linear trend that began with the birth of our species.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">There is also a Youtube video to go with this opinion.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rlQrYCacrKo</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="2a">I do realize that this is a very unhealthy idea to have whether or not that the idea is true or not, I just have not been able to beat it myself.</claim>

<claim type="disagreement" id="3a">I do disagree with Gade a little bit.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="3b">I don't think it would kill everybody, </claim> but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="3c">the some few people that still know how to hunt and gather would probably survive as well people who were rich enough to have access to a lot of resources to start out with before the economy crashes.</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="3">I probably believe this because I listen to Alex Jones too much.</claim>

</OP>
<reply id="cnffcvi" author="TEmpTom">

Praxagora: I want all to have a share of everything and all property to be in common; there will no longer be either rich or poor; I shall begin by making land, money, everything that is private property, common to all.
Blepyrus: But who will till the soil?
Praxagora: The <quote>~~slaves~~ robots</quote><claim type="evaluation_rational" id="4">~~slaves~~ robots</claim> of course.&#8221;
&#8213;Aristophanes
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="5">Automation is a slow process that will take decades, and end up revolutionizing our economic structure and way of life.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="6">Just like the Industrial revolution forced feudal and mercantile agriculturalist societies to become capitalist ones,</premise> <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="7">the Automation revolution will force capitalist economies to become socialist ones.</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cnfku13" author="Oflameo">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="8">On one hand the trend if confirmed would be consistent with Karl Marx's prediction.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="9">On the other hand I work with Free Software on a daily basis</premise> but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="10">it seems more capitalist than anything.</claim>

</reply>
</thread>
