<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rcsdh">
<title>CMV: Humans are going to die out because of an economic collapse</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rcsdh/cmv_humans_are_going_to_die_out_because_of_an/</source>
<OP author="Oflameo">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">Bill Gade presents the argument better than I do so I will just quote him.</claim>

&gt; There have been 4 jobs or activities which Man has engaged in throughout the centuries: Hunter/Gathering, Agriculture, Manufacturing, and Services. What's next? What category can you imagine in which billions of people will be working in the future? 
&gt; It turns out that there is a final category. It is known as Unemployment. As Agriculture, Manufacturing, and Services become more efficient in the coming months, workers will have nowhere to go but to the unemployment line. At some point, Man's artificial economic system will necessarily collapse. When that happens, the corporations which produce and deliver food will no longer have an incentive to do so. The cities will suffer great hunger and it will be the end of Man. 
&gt; The current jobless situation you read about in the news is not an ordinary part of the business cycle. It is the final stretch of the linear trend that began with the birth of our species.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">There is also a Youtube video to go with this opinion.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rlQrYCacrKo&spfreload=10</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="2a">I do realize that this is a very unhealthy idea to have whether or not that the idea is true or not, I just have not been able to beat it myself.</claim>

<claim type="disagreement" id="3a">I do disagree with Gade a little bit.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="3b">I don't think it would kill everybody, </claim> but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="3c">the some few people that still know how to hunt and gather would probably survive as well people who were rich enough to have access to a lot of resources to start out with before the economy crashes.</premise>
<claim type="interpretation" id="3">I probably believe this because I listen to Alex Jones too much.</claim>

</OP>
<reply id="cneps5p" author="jumpup">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="4">you are forgetting the need to make money also wains</claim>, <premise type="" id="5">as unemployment rises it simply converts half the population to communism while the working class keep capitalism</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cneyqa3" author="Oflameo">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="6">Isn't communism the reason why The USSR lost the cold war and North Korea a joke?</claim>

</reply>
<reply id="cnez9c1" author="jumpup">

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="7">partly,</claim> but <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="8">communism in combination with capitalism has a different approach then pure communism,</claim> <premise type="" id="9">one of the failures of communism was the lack of incentive, with a part capitalism those with drive can still succeed, but everyone else will still have basic living tools,</premise>
and <premise type="logos" id="10">i won't lie, people will see a reduction in what they are able to buy</premise>, but <claim type="interpretation" id="11">when you balance that out with perpetual unemployment its still better then the alternative.</claim>
ps
<claim type="interpretation" id="12">Communism has some flaws,</claim> but <claim type="interpretation" id="13">it has also had a long time for people to find solutions to those flaws,</claim>

</reply>
</thread>
