<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rcrkd">
<title>CMV: Veganism and vegetarianism are not the best way to improve farm animal welfare</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rcrkd/cmv_veganism_and_vegetarianism_are_not_the_best/</source>
<OP author="Helicase21">

Title is mostly to get attention, and I'm working from a specific set of assumptions.
My argument is as follows:

1) <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">The chances of the entire world adopting a vegan/vegetarian diet are slim to none</claim>

1a) <premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">Therefore, there will always be a market for meat and other animal products</premise>

2) <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="2">The food market, like all other markets, operates on general principles of supply and demand</claim>

3) <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3">Meat farmers can use techniques exhibiting a range of costs or benefits, both in terms of environmental impact and animal welfare.</claim>

4) <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="4">A vegan or vegetarian diet denies demand, and thus potential revenue, to all meat-producing farms, regardless of how humane or environmentally sound their practice are.</claim>

4a) <premise type="logos_pathos" id="5">Since the majority of farms are large factory farms</premise>, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="6">I concede that this is probably good for animal welfare.</claim> **
However**:

5) <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="7">Purchasing meat from farms known to produce their meat in an ethical way not only denies demand to large factory farms</claim> but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="8">helps improve the market share of ethical meat-growing</claim>, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="9">which seems as though it would be even better for animal welfare.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="10">My general view is that people should probably as a rule eat less meat from better growers</claim>, and <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="11">that will make for a bigger shift in growing practices than simply people dropping out of eating meat altogether.</claim>
Moreover, <premise type="pathos" id="12">this practice would be much easier to "evangelize" than a vegetarian or vegan diet.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="13">Face it, meat is tasty (and non-factory meat is often tastier than factory-farmed meat, at least in my own anecdotal experience)</premise>

</OP>
<reply id="cnet8f7" author="lnfinity">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="14">I take some issue with assumption #1.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="15">Dramatic societal changes have happened multiple times throughout history.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="16">They are gradual and at times may seem impossible to many</premise>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="17">they do happen</premise>.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="18">The larger issue is that you are somehow concluding that someone choosing to go vegan gives more demand to large factory farms.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="19">You are correct that it may reduce the demand for meat from *slightly* less cruel farms</premise>, but <premise type="logos" id="20">it also takes demand away from the larger farms</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="21">Going vegan means fewer animals suffer on small farms and fewer animals suffer on factory farms, not that fewer animals suffer on small farms and more animals suffer on factory farms.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnetcl9" author="Helicase21">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="22">Someone going vegan and someone becoming an ethical carnivore reduce demand for factory-farmed meat by exactly the same amount (1 person).</claim>
<premise type="pathos" id="23">The ethical carnivore just happens to *also* increase demand for responsibly-grown meat.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnetjmw" author="lnfinity">

&gt; Someone going vegan and someone becoming an ~~ethical~~ *slightly less unethical* carnivore reduce demand for factory-farmed meat by exactly the same amount (1 person). The ~~ethical~~ *slightly less unethical* carnivore just happens to also increase demand for responsibly-grown meat.

I fixed your statement.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="24">Someone who eats "happy" meat isn't helping animals.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="25">They are simply supporting farms that are somewhat less cruel.</premise>

</reply>
<reply id="cnetkwd" author="Helicase21">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="26">Since, as you stated in your first post of this discussion, you reject my first assertion, I think we're just going to have to agree to disagree on that one.</claim>

</reply>
</thread>
