<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rc3p3">
<title>CMV:Patriotism is the belief that being born on one side of a line makes you better.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rc3p3/cmvpatriotism_is_the_belief_that_being_born_on/</source>
<OP author="sniperman357">

<claim type="interpretation" id="0">American patriots have a general mentality against immigration.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">Saying these people shouldn&#8217;t be allowed to become part of the country, is the same as saying they are worse,</premise> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">because they were born on a different side of a line</premise>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="3">americans are better because of the side of the line they are born on</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="4">This is prominent in many ads and political champagnes, namely the slogan &#8220;Creating jobs for americans&#8221;.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="6">I understand why politics use this slogan</claim>, <premise type="logos" id="7">because they are trying to get americans to vote for them</premise>, but <premise type="logos" id="8">this slogan is also prominent in ads made by private corporations</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="9">As if creating jobs for americans is morally superior to creating jobs for people of other countries.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="10">The companies launching these ads may be trying to win in the american market, so they can sell more of their product,</premise> but <premise type="logos" id="11">the fact that this can increase sales shows that many americans hold the being born on one side of a line belief</premise>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="12">I am not blaming the politicians or corporations running ads running these slogans</claim>, <premise type="logos" id="13">they are merely trying to win votes or make money from this mentality</premise>, but <claim type="interpretation" id="14">really it is the citizens that have the belief that they are better, because of the side of a line they are born on, that are at fault</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="15">Patriotism is really just this belief.</claim>

</OP>
<reply id="cnemor5" author="debatingaccount">

<claim type="interpretation" id="16">I would define patriotism quite simply as supporting one's country, but not *necessarily* disparaging others.</claim>
<premise type="logos" id="17">Therefore I would say that the antithesis of patriotism is not having a global perspective</premise>, but <premise type="logos" id="18">is in fact selfishness</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="19">Someone who attempts to extract gain for themselves at harm to their overall country is acting unpatriotically</premise>, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="20">someone who assists another country that is in worse shape instead of assisting their own can still be a patriot, but also recognize significant need in other nations and decide to assist them as well</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="21">Whether you support immigration or not, so long as you are supporting what you believe is best for your nation, you are still acting patriotically</premise>, and <premise type="logos" id="22">even if you decide to support another nation you can still be acting patriotically as well so long as you support your nation too</premise>.

</reply>
<reply id="cneqxqg" author="sniperman357">

<claim type="agreement" id="23">This is true</claim>, but, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="24">I think, supporting the common good is also more important than supporting your country</claim>.

</reply>
<reply id="cney5lx" author="debatingaccount">

<claim type="agreement" id="25">Yes</claim>, but <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="26">the two are often one the same</claim>, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="27">especially when you live in a country as large as the U.S. most acts which serve the common good generally support your country</premise>.

</reply>
</thread>
