<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rc3p3">
<title>CMV:Patriotism is the belief that being born on one side of a line makes you better.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rc3p3/cmvpatriotism_is_the_belief_that_being_born_on/</source>
<OP author="sniperman357">

<claim type="interpretation" id="0">American patriots have a general mentality against immigration.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">Saying these people shouldn&#8217;t be allowed to become part of the country, is the same as saying they are worse,</premise> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">because they were born on a different side of a line</premise>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="3">americans are better because of the side of the line they are born on</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="4">This is prominent in many ads and political champagnes, namely the slogan &#8220Creating jobs for americans&#8221;.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="6">I understand why politics use this slogan</claim>, <premise type="logos" id="7">because they are trying to get americans to vote for them</premise>, but <premise type="logos" id="8">this slogan is also prominent in ads made by private corporations</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="9">As if creating jobs for americans is morally superior to creating jobs for people of other countries.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="10">The companies launching these ads may be trying to win in the american market, so they can sell more of their product,</premise> but <premise type="logos" id="11">the fact that this can increase sales shows that many americans hold the being born on one side of a line belief</premise>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="12">I am not blaming the politicians or corporations running ads running these slogans</claim>, <premise type="logos" id="13">they are merely trying to win votes or make money from this mentality</premise>, but <claim type="interpretation" id="14">really it is the citizens that have the belief that they are better, because of the side of a line they are born on, that are at fault</claim>.
<claim type="interpretation" id="15">Patriotism is really just this belief.</claim>

</OP>
<reply id="cnejagk" author="looklistencreate">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="16">I'm sure you can find many people who self-identify as patriots while also favoring policies that would allow more immigration.</claim>
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="17">I'm one of these people.</premise>

Even if you don't, <premise type="pathos" id="18">you don't have to necessarily think you're better than other people because you're against immigration</premise>.
<premise type="pathos" id="19">Many of these people believe that it's not our responsibility as Americans to provide for people from other countries, but rather the responsibility of those countries</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="20">That's not the same as thinking you're better than other people</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="21">I don't want absolutely no immigration control for people coming into the US</claim>, but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="22">I don't think I'm better than the people I'd be denying citizenship</claim>.

</reply>
<reply id="cneqn7o" author="sniperman357">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="23">I confused patriotism, which is the love of one's country, with nationalism, which is the idea that one's country is better than other countries.</claim>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="24">What you said is definitely true about patriots</premise>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="25">I misused patriots to mean nationalist</premise>.

</reply>
<reply id="cneqpz7" author="looklistencreate">

<claim type="interpretation" id="26">Believing your country is better than all others is not the same as believing your country's people are better than all others.</claim>

</reply>
</thread>
