<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rawgb">
<title>CMV: I believe that regularly browsing 4chan will make you into a worse person</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rawgb/cmv_i_believe_that_regularly_browsing_4chan_will/</source>
<OP author="InsaneTeaparty">

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="0">Because of the anonymity on 4chan people are more prone to not think through, care about what they post and are quicker to throw out insults.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1">They will care about how people respond to them</premise>, but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">since it's largely negative they will stoop down to the same level rather than go to any high ground since they are not linked to an identity</premise>.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="3">Surrounding the entire site there's a general pessimistic group mentality</premise>, and <premise type="logos_pathos" id="4">people are subconsciously encouraged to take part of it in order to feel like they are a part of the group</premise>.
<premise type="pathos" id="5">Some boards will have specific groups of people who they are encouraged to hate, women, SJWs, casual gamers, Jews</premise>, and <premise type="pathos" id="6">any reasonable argument against a poster can be made redundant by saying or thinking they are a part of these agendas or groups</premise>.

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="7">On boards you will find echo chambers where people are more prone to believe rumors than proof</premise>.
<premise type="pathos" id="8">Things about e-celebrities will start as rumors</premise>, <premise type="pathos" id="9">ideas about them or things will get taken out of context and it will be posted continually until it's taken as fact</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="10">It will reach conspiracy theory levels of "proof" where people will simply believe it because they feel as if they are a part of a group-effort that's uncovering something.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="11">Surrounding yourself with this will in general make you into a more pessimistic, negative and possibly depressive person.</claim>

<claim type="interpretation" id="12">I'm not saying that every person who browses 4chan is depressed or negative</claim>, but <claim type="interpretation" id="13">that the majority of them are affected negatively by browsing the site</claim>.

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="14">Thinking that you are unaffected by this doesn't necessarily mean you are, but instead means that you are unaware of how much it affects you.</claim>

EDIT: [Awarded Delta](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rawgb/cmv_i_believe_that_regularly_browsing_4chan_will/cneyhn7?context=3)

</OP>
<reply id="cne90oe" author="stanhhh">

<claim type="interpretation" id="15">It will certainly make you a colder person.</claim>
Or <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="16">let's say, a "less sensitive" person</claim>.
But <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="17">I'm not conviced that this is always a bad thing.</claim>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="18">After all the gore I witnessed on 4chan, I'm able to jump in an accident scene and actually keep my cool while most other people around are freaking out like crazed apes, yelling and really doing nothing to help at all.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="19">After all the freak sexualities i was exposed to in 4chan, I find it hard to judge anyone about anything they do with their bodies and partners.</premise>

And so on.

<claim type="interpretation" id="20">I'd say 4chan will open your eyes and show you Reality on many topics.</claim>

<premise type="logos_pathos" id="21">It can have a bad influence with all the racism etc tho</premise> but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="22">this, you have to keep in check yourself</premise>.

About "pessimism"..well yeah...<premise type="pathos" id="23">some people may answer to you that there is not much to be optimistic about in this world and that maybe you are delusional/uninformed to think otherwise</premise>.
Are they right?
Are they wrong?
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="24">Hard to tell</claim>.

</reply>
<reply id="cne92a0" author="InsaneTeaparty">

&gt; After all the gore I witnessed on 4chan, I'm able to jump in an accident scene and actually keep my cool 

Is this something that has actually happened?

</reply>
<reply id="cnea8vl" author="stanhhh">

<claim type="agreement" id="25">Yes</claim> and <claim type="disagreement" id="25a">no</claim>.

<premise type="pathos" id="26">a little girl was swept by a car in Paris</premise>, <premise type="pathos" id="27">she was lying unconscious with a bit of blood from her nose</premise>, <premise type="pathos" id="28">people were hysterical</premise>, <premise type="pathos" id="29">I kept the mother in check cause she was trying to move her</premise> , <premise type="pathos" id="30">then had to keep the people around in check cause they were physically trying to restrain her to prevent the mother to only touch her</premise> and <premise type="pathos" id="31">she was getting totally mad</premise>...
<premise type="ethos_pathos" id="32">All while calling the ER and taking a picture of the car's licence plate cause the driver kept near his open door all the time (while he was being harassed and yelled at by like 10 persons)</premise>. I've had no follow up on this incident.

<premise type="pathos" id="33">Just 2 weeks ago, heard and felt a crash very close to my house</premise>, <premise type="pathos" id="34">a drunken teen had just smashed his car full force into another's property wall after missing the turn</premise>, <premise type="pathos" id="35">neighbors went out but no one had the head to keep the guy in check, cause he was walking near his ruined car, not understanding what just happened told him to stay put and sit and just generally speak to him so he doesn't freak out</premise>.
<premise type="pathos" id="36">People were looking from a few meters, not doing anything</premise>.
<premise type="pathos" id="37">I called the ER</premise>, <premise type="pathos" id="38">the guy stood up and tried to restart his car</premise>, <premise type="pathos" id="39">had to take his keys from him, spent 20 minutes, making small talk, reassuring him and just generally checking if he wasn't internally hurt/losing consciousness/ had blood coming out from the mouth ears or nose</premise>.
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="40">He seemed ok appart from the shock and high level drunkenness.</premise>

Aaand... <premise type="pathos" id="41">I work in a surgery unit</premise> and <premise type="pathos" id="42">the kind of gore I witness there doesn't shock me at all</premise> .

So yeah. It wasn't a person cut in half or whatever gore you can see on 4chan but <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="43">I think a bit of desensitization can help keep a leveled head in stressful situations</claim>.

</reply>
</thread>
