<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qnu4z">
<title><claim type="interpretation">CMV: The highest form of relationship between men and women doomed to be romance</claim></title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qnu4z/cmv_the_highest_form_of_relationship_between_men/</source>
<OP author="Skinners_Pidgeon">

<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="0">Maybe it has to do with being an adolescent and being new to dealing with the opposite sex</claim>, but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="1">I'm beginning to fall under the assumption that the only purpose for guys to get to know girls is to eventually engage in romance.</claim>

<premise type="pathos" id="2" rel="support" ref="3">"Why else do men engage women in conversation in public?"</premise> I wonder (<claim type="interpretation" id="3">my perception might just be distorted after reading Neil Strauss's *The Game*</claim>).
"<premise type="logos_pathos" id="4" rel="support" ref="1">Why do I feel like chasing after girls and getting to know them when I have so many great guy friends already who I know care about me so much more?</premise> <premise type="logos_pathos" id="5" rel="support" ref="1">Why can't I be friends with girls (even pretty ones) and not feel insecure when I don't try to advance some romantic agenda?</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="6" rel="support" ref="1">Why do I find myself inevitably becoming attracted to them?</premise>"

I have so many more questions regarding the non-romantic side of male-female relationships, but instead of writing an abhorrent block of text nobody could possibly be expected to read, I ask just the one title question (thinking that <claim type="interpretation" id="9">the above questions are more like fragments of a bigger picture of misunderstanding</claim>) <premise type="logos" id="10" rel="support" ref="9">because I want to know what older, more mature people think</premise>.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="11">It also must distort my view to have gone to an all-boy's school for the majority of my life.</claim>

At times, <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="12">I feel like the interplay between men and women is always (at least always initially) a bs game</claim> where <premise type="logos_pathos" id="13" rel="support" ref="12">the man tries to show the woman how non-threatening and valuable he is from a non-romantic standpoint before she is comfortable with allowing herself to think of him as a safe partner</premise>.
<premise type="logos" id="14" rel="support" ref="15">Something about that seems so sinister, cynical, and hollow to me</premise> that <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="15">I can't stand it</claim>.
Please change this view.

</OP>

<reply id="cn8o3mn" author="littleln">

<premise type="ethos" id="16" rel="support" ref="17">I'm a middle aged female.</premise>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="17" rel="rebuttal_attack" ref="title">Quit putting the pussy on a pedestal.</claim> 
<premise type="pathos" id="18" rel="support" ref="19">If you think that the only reason to get to know a female is to bone her</premise> <claim type="interpretation" id="19" rel="rebuttal_attack" ref="1">you are doing 2 things </claim>1) <claim type="interpretation" id="20" rel="undercutter" ref="1">dehumanizing females a placing them in a category separate from yourself- almost like a separate class or subspecies...</claim> For an extreme example of this <premise type="logos_pathos" id="21" rel="support" ref="20">look at some Arab cultures where women have few rights and can't even show 1 square inch of forearm lest a man be tempted</premise>. 
2) <claim type="interpretation" id="22" rel="undercutter" ref="1">elevating a woman's  sexuality to a higher plane than where it deserves to be.</claim> 
You are. Really.
Knock that pedestal over. 
<premise type="pathos" id="23" rel="support" ref="24">Women aren't putting your dick up there</premise>, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="24" rel="rebuttal_attack" ref="1">don't put the pussy up there</claim>. 
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="25" rel="undercutter" ref="1">It just makes a guy look a little desperate when he treats a woman and her vagina like a magical unicorn.</claim> 
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="26" rel="support" ref="25">Nobody worth dating really wants that in my book.</premise> 
<claim type="interpretation" id="27" rel="undercutter" ref="1">You may think you aren't guilty of this</claim> but <premise type="logos_pathos" id="28" rel="support" ref="27">by virtue of the fact that you think the sole goal of befriending a female is to fuck her</premise>, you are.
<claim type="interpretation" id="29" rel="undercutter" ref="1">You are making the pussy very valuable.</claim> 
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="30" rel="rebuttal_attack" ref="1">Making friends with a lot of women actually devalues the shit out of it even if you aren't hitting it.</claim> 
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="31" rel="rebuttal_attack" ref="1">Which long term is a really great thing.</claim>

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="32" rel="undercutter" ref="1">Continuing to think of women as magical pussy creatures who aren't worth befriending or even talking to unless you can eventually stick your cock into them is not a good way to form a healthy relationship if you manage to form one at all with those beliefs. </claim>

<premise type="ethos_logos" id="33" rel="support" ref="36">I've always had lots of male friends.</premise> 
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="34" rel="support" ref="36">I just don't get along with women.</premise> 
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="35" rel="support" ref="36">I'm straight.</premise> 
<claim type="interpretation" id="36" rel="rebuttal_attack" ref="1">I don't want to have relations with any of my male friends and afaik they don't expect any sex from me.</claim> 
<premise type="pathos" id="37" rel="support" ref="36">They all know I've been married for 12 years and am loyal.</premise> 
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="38" rel="support" ref="36">All we do is hang out and play video games or board games and drink beer</premise> (admittedly its rare that I have the time with 2 kids to do this). 
<premise type="ethos_logos_pathos" id="39" rel="support" ref="36">My husband is 100% OK with this and trusts me completely. </premise>

</reply>

<reply id="cn8t1qp" author="Skinners_Pidgeon">

<claim type="agreement" id="40" rel="agreement" ref="17">That is a really good point.</claim> 
I guess <claim type="interpretation" id="41" rel="agreement" ref="17">I've been indoctrinated into thinking the way you described: that being friends with girls is something wholly separate from being friends with guys when it's not.</claim>

</reply>
</thread>
