<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<thread ID="2qncj3">
<title><claim type="evaluation_emotional">CMV Me joining the army is not a waste of time nor does it conflict with my personality</claim></title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qncj3/cmv_me_joining_the_army_is_not_a_waste_of_time/</source>
<OP author="Hamza78ch11">

<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="0">I've always had a respect for the men in uniform and I've always wanted to join.</claim>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="1">Recently I've disagreed with the practices of the U.S. military</claim> but that doesn't mean that I hate the Warriors, <premise type="logos_pathos" id="2">just the people that force them into it</premise>.
<premise type="ethos" id="1a" rel="support" ref="0">I'm an immigrant and a Muslim neither of which is or should be a deterrent from joining</premise>.
<premise type="ethos" id="1b" rel="support" ref="0">I want to be a doctor, not because of familial pressure but of a genuine need to help</premise>.
So here's where I am now: currently in first year of college studying biology, enough AP credits to be a tiny bit ahead of my classmates, an itching to explore this giant world God gave me, I'm also poor and medical school in the military (from what I understand) pays for smart kids.
Also, please forgive me if this is wrong or arrogant or whatever, I want the respect that people give men and women in the military.

My plan was to graduate College and join the USHS (the military medical school) and become and Army doctor.
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3">The only reservation that I had was that it would be a waste of my time</claim> <premise type="pathos" id="4" rel="support" ref="3">because I want to be a neurosurgeon and that's a looooooooong and rigorous path</premise> and that <premise type="pathos" id="5" rel="support" ref="3">I might be losing precious time by joining the military</premise>.
My mom doesn't want me to join for that reason.
Other things that I've considered: <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="6">I love the idea of a brotherhood but I don't agree with the ideology,</claim> <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="7">the military putting me through Med school will help me jump start life,</claim> <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="8">I'm very inexperienced and haven't seen much of the world and this I think will help me</claim>.

I look forward to having my views challenged!
Thanks!

</OP>

<reply id="cn913il" author="Hawkeye1226">
I want to go a slightly different route here and ask why you would join the Army specifically? 
<claim type="interpretation" id="9" rel="undercutter" ref="8">Different branches have different options and very different lifestyles and culture</claim>. 
<premise type="logos" id="10" rel="support" ref="9">For example, you mentioned that you wanted to see more of the world.</premise>
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="11" rel="partial_attack" ref="8">The best branch for that would be the Navy.</claim>
</reply>

<reply id="cn916m8" author="Hamza78ch11">
<premise type="ethos" id="12">I get seasick lol.</premise> 
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="13" rel="undercutter" ref="9">The Marines aren't knows for their... Genius...</claim> 
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="14" rel="undercutter" ref="9">The air force isn't right for me</claim> because <premise type="logos" id="15" rel="support" ref="14">I couldn't fly</premise> and <premise type="logos" id="16" rel="support" ref="14">don't want to be an engineer</premise>. 
Army it is then. 
</reply>

<reply id="cn91iiz" author="Hawkeye1226">
<claim type="disagreement" id="17" rel="undercutter" ref="13">I think you need to get a bit better informed if you're going with those particular stereotypes</claim>. 
<premise type="logos" id="18" rel="support" ref="17">Did you know the Army's minimum ASVAB score is lower than the Marines, for instance?</premise> 
<claim type="interpretation" id="19" rel="undercutter" ref="12">As for getting seasick, it's not as much of an issue on such large ships.</claim> 
Don't go for the Coast Guard though, that's for sure. 
And <claim type="interpretation" id="20" rel="undercutter" ref="12">there is actually a decent chance to never set foot on a ship.</claim> 
Especially since <premise type="logos" id="21" rel="support" ref="20">the Marines don't have their own medical services</premise>. 
The Navy provides them.

In the end, I'd probably recommend the Airforce for you. 
When you join the military, you sign a contract that gives you a specific(or not so specific if you join the Marines) job. 
If there is a slot open for a doctor in the Airforce, they'll put in in your contract. 
If there isn't, you can either wait or go to another branch.

Can I ask how much you actually know about actually *being in the military?* 
I don't want to offend you, but <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="22" rel="undercutter" ref="0">a lot of people looking to join tend to forget that bit</claim>, when <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="23" rel="undercutter" ref="0">it's really the most important part</claim>. 
<premise type="logos" id="24" rel="support" ref="22">All when the clostest they've been to military life are </premise><claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="25" rel="undercutter" ref="0">movies which are either terrible representations or great representations of *very specific parts* of the military</claim>.

You won't be a *doctor in the military*, you will be a *military doctor.* 
That's why I recommend the Air Force. 
<claim type="interpretation" id="26" rel="rebuttal_attack" ref="14">Out of all the branches, it has the most in common with the civilian world in regards to its culture.</claim> 
<premise type="logos" id="27">It's only 60 something years old</premise>, after all.
</reply>

<reply id="cn97omx" author="Hamza78ch11">
Okay, thanks so much for the info! 
<claim type="interpretation" id="28" rel="partial_agreement" ref="17">I think I still have a lot to research</claim> but <claim type="interpretation" id="29" rel="partial_attack" ref="17">my main reason against the marines was that they are very homogeneous.</claim> 
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="30" rel="support" ref="29">From all the marines that I've met they all think and act the same way to the point where it freaks me out a little.</premise> 
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="31" rel="support" ref="29">They subscribe to the same pages on facebook and whatnot</premise>, <claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="32" rel="partial_attack" ref="17">it's a little creep tbh</claim>. 
I'm definitely going to look at the airforce, thanks to what you've suggested!
 
</reply>

<reply id="cn99bzi" author="Hawkeye1226">
Look at it like this. 
<claim type="interpretation" id="33" rel="partial_agreement" ref="28">The Army is a military service</claim>, <claim type="interpretation" id="34" rel="partial_agreement" ref="28">the Air Force is a business</claim>, <claim type="interpretation" id="35" rel="partial_agreement" ref="28">the Navy is a "denim and leather" bar</claim>, and <claim type="interpretation" id="36" rel="partial_agreement" ref="28">the Marines are a cult</claim>.
</reply>
</thread>
