<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qgpie">
<title><claim type="interpretation">CMV: Progress in automation will eventually lead to a full fledge genocide on the majority of the population.</claim></title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qgpie/cmv_progress_in_automation_will_eventually_lead/</source>
<OP author="Prometheus_v2">

<premise type="logos" id="0" rel="support" ref="title">[47% of all jobs are at risk of being automated](http://motherboard.vice.com/blog/the-rich-and-their-robots-are-about-to-make-half-the-worlds-jobs-disappear).</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="1" rel="support" ref="title">This number will grow grow until the vast majority of people become obsolete for jobs.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="2" rel="support" ref="title">Since some of this automation will inevitably come to weapons, the wealthy will have the perfect opportunity to commit genocide on the 99%.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="3" rel="support" ref="title" >By fortifying themselves in their gated communities with rows upon rows of automated defences, all unburdened by humans with consciences and families, they can simply wait for everyone to starve or get killed while they bask in their machine generated wealth.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="4" rel="support" ref="title">Once everyone is dead, they can simply be wiped from history.</premise>
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="5" rel="support" ref="title" >You, me, everyone will have never existed.</premise>
<premise type="logos" id="6" rel="support" ref="title">A crime completely erased.</premise>

[I am not the only one to predict this outcome](https://www.jacobinmag.com/2011/12/four-futures/) (see the last section on "exterminism"). I don't think the other more optimistic futures expressed in that article will come to pass given current mentalities.
I think it's also too late to stop it.
Those who will fight it will lose.
Please CMV so I can have hope again.

</OP>

<reply id="cn5z7c0" author="TryUsingScience">
<premise type="ethos_logos" id="7" rel="support" ref="9">Bill Gates is one of the wealthiest people in the world and he devotes a substantial portion of his wealth to philanthropy.</premise> 
<premise type="logos" id="8" rel="support" ref="9">He is not alone in this.</premise> 
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="9" rel="undercutter" ref="title">While there are rich assholes, many wealthy people use their money to try to improve the world.</claim> 
What makes you think these same people will turn around and start slaughtering everyone as soon as automation improves?
</reply>

<reply id="cn5zlnq" author="Prometheus_v2">
<premise type="logos_pathos" id="10" rel="support" ref="11">If there are more non-asshole rich, why isn't there a global push for better worker protection, and investment, instead of the complete opposite?</premise> 
<claim type="evaluation_emotional" id="11" rel="rebuttal_attack" ref="9">The rich are all hoarding money on the Cayman Islands and don't care about anything that keeping it for themselves and their dynasties.</claim>
</reply>
</thread>
