<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qbry8">
<title><claim type="evaluation_rational">CMV: America is not a democracy</claim></title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qbry8/cmv_america_is_not_a_democracy/</source>
<OP author="Smelly_Bob">

Really though.
<premise type="pathos" id="0" rel="support" ref="title">There is an unchecked organization that spies on them 24/7 without consent.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="1" rel="support" ref="title">The US has given itself license to detain and torture citizens with no trial.</premise>
<premise type="pathos" id="2" rel="support" ref="title">The energy laws in that country allow corporations to drill where they please and, as a result, poison who they please.</premise>
American citizens have clearly been lied to in many situations.
These lies have led to events like the second gulf war.
Not to mention the completely unregulated financial system.

Honestly, none of these things have been democratically voted for, so why are Americans so deluded about this?
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="3" rel="agreement" ref="title">It's not a free, democratic society by any means.</claim>
<claim type="interpretation" id="4" rel="agreement" ref="3">It's clearly an oligarchy</claim>

</OP>
<reply id="cn4qcur" author="HilariousEconomist">
<claim type="evaluation_rational" id="5" rel="undercutter" ref="title"> Most of what you said is either patently false or simplification to the point of absurdity, </claim> but <claim type="evaluation_rational" id="6" rel="undercutter" ref="title"> more importantly has nothing to do with whether or not America is a democracy. </claim> 
<premise type="logos" id="7" rel="support" ref="6"> Democracies can be oppressive illiberal regimes, totalitarian systems, command-and-control socialist systems, social democracies, liberal capitalist states, oligarchies etc. </premise> 
<premise type="logos" id="8" rel="support" ref="6"> You have yet to give evidence that there is widespread tampering with free and fair elections which define the US as a democratic state. </premise>

<premise type="logos" id="9" rel="support" ref="6"> For example: according to you a democracy is defined as "a state which has strict financial regulations, outlaws fracking, </premise> and <premise type="logos" id="10" rel="support" ref="6"> doesn't have a spy network". </premise> 
You'd get an F in government class I suppose.

</reply>
<reply id="cn57xwp" author="Smelly_Bob">
<claim type="agreement" id="11" rel="agreement" ref="6">I probably would yeah.</claim>
</reply>
</thread>
